<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Custom Templates on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/custom-templates/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Custom Templates on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 10:12:19 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/custom-templates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>User Distributor Custom Tag Template For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/user-distributor-tag-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 10:12:19 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/user-distributor-tag-template/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed working with custom templates for Google Tag Manager. A lot. So much so that whenever the need to add some custom code to a container emerges, my first thought is how to turn that into a custom template.
Google has been forthcoming in introducing new APIs steadily, and I think the variety of things you can do with template is improving with every new API release.
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to use a simple tag template for distributing your users to groups, based on a random split.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Introducing The GTM Templates Library</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/introducing-gtm-templates-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:51:06 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/introducing-gtm-templates-library/</guid>
      <description>When Custom Templates were released in Google Tag Manager, many of us active in the GTM communities started doing two things: 1) creating our own custom templates, and 2) waiting patiently for Google to release a &amp;ldquo;gallery&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;library&amp;rdquo; for distributing these community contributions.
While I have full faith in the latter happening some time in the future, I thought it would be fun to create something similar to a library, and then open-sourcing it for the community to help out with or to download locally for their own purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Build A Google Tag Manager Monitor</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-tag-manager-monitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 11:49:15 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-tag-manager-monitor/</guid>
      <description>Google Tag Manager is strictly a tag delivery system, and it&amp;rsquo;s very careful not to collect any analytics data on its own. This is most likely a deliberate choice, because if GTM was to start collecting data, it would introduce additional barriers to adoption.
Nevertheless, being a tool that consolidates the design, development, deployment, and testing of all the marketing and analytics pixels, code snippets, and utilities running on a website or a mobile app, lacking the necessary features for auditing and monitoring has always seemed like an oversight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Ecommerce Object Builder Template For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-builder-custom-variable-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 11:48:29 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-builder-custom-variable-template/</guid>
      <description>One of the cool things about Enhanced Ecommerce deployments in Google Tag Manager is that you can use a Custom JavaScript variable to generate the necessary data.
There are many reasons to do so, with the biggest one being the flexibility it offers for manipulating the dataLayer object in case quick changes are required on the site, and it would take too long to wait for a new release of the site JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Create Facebook Pixel Custom Tag Template</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/create-facebook-pixel-custom-tag-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 18:05:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/create-facebook-pixel-custom-tag-template/</guid>
      <description>After the recent release of Custom Templates for Google Tag Manager, my mind has been occupied by very little else. However, I have a nagging feeling that due to how involved the feature set is, there&amp;rsquo;s still a lot of demystifying that needs to take place before templates are fully embraced by the GTM user base.
In this article, I want to show you a concrete example of template creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Templates Guide For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/custom-templates-guide-for-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 18:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/custom-templates-guide-for-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>As I have finally managed to pick up my jaw from the floor, it&amp;rsquo;s now time to tell you what&amp;rsquo;s got me so excited. Google Tag Manager recently released a new feature called Custom Templates. Actually, it&amp;rsquo;s not fair to call it a feature. It&amp;rsquo;s a full-blown paradigm shift in how we use Google Tag Manager. It&amp;rsquo;s a suite of features designed to help brands, companies, and users create and share their own custom JavaScript and HTML setups with ease, while taking care that the code is optimized for delivery in the web browser.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>