<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cookie on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/cookie/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cookie on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 10:12:19 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/cookie/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>User Distributor Custom Tag Template For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/user-distributor-tag-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 10:12:19 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/user-distributor-tag-template/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed working with custom templates for Google Tag Manager. A lot. So much so that whenever the need to add some custom code to a container emerges, my first thought is how to turn that into a custom template.
Google has been forthcoming in introducing new APIs steadily, and I think the variety of things you can do with template is improving with every new API release.
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to use a simple tag template for distributing your users to groups, based on a random split.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal Analytics: Fire Script Just Once Per Session</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/universal-analytics-fire-script-just-per-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 11:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/universal-analytics-fire-script-just-per-session/</guid>
      <description>There is a new version of this post for GTM V2 here.
While going over my previous post about using weather conditions to segment data in Google Analytics, I started thinking about performance issues. Since I&amp;rsquo;m using a visit-scope custom dimension, it seems futile to have it send the weather details with every single page load. The odds of the weather changing drastically during one visit are slim (unless you live in the UK), and I have yet to come up with a good reason to change my on-site behavior because the weather changed from a drizzle to a downpour.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>