<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Swift on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/swift/</link><description>Recent content in Swift on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 10:10:12 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/swift/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>iOS Quickstart With Google Analytics For Firebase And Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/ios-quickstart-google-analytics-firebase-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 10:10:12 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/ios-quickstart-google-analytics-firebase-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>A while ago, I &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/android-quickstart-google-analytics-firebase-google-tag-manager/">published&lt;/a> an article on how to build an Android application, and bundle it with &lt;a href="https://console.firebase.google.com/">Firebase&lt;/a>. The purpose of that article, and the one you are reading now, is to slowly introduce the world of mobile app development and Firebase, given the latter is getting more and more traction as Google&amp;rsquo;s go-to &lt;a href="https://www.blog.google/products/marketingplatform/analytics/new-way-unify-app-and-website-measurement-google-analytics/">analytics platform&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After finishing work on the Android guide, I immediately started working on its counterpart for iOS, and that&amp;rsquo;s the one you&amp;rsquo;re reading now.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Track Launch Campaigns In GTM For iOS</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/gtmtips-track-launch-campaigns-in-gtm-for-ios/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 08:10:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/gtmtips-track-launch-campaigns-in-gtm-for-ios/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com">Google Analytics&lt;/a> for iOS, there are two types of campaign measurement. There&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/ios/v3/campaigns#ios-install">install campaign measurement&lt;/a>, which lets you track the channels which brought your visitors to the App Store, where they proceeded to download your app. There&amp;rsquo;s also &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/ios/v3/campaigns#general-campaigns">launch campaign tracking&lt;/a>, which lets you attribute app launches to specific campaigns.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this tip post, we&amp;rsquo;ll tackle the latter. We&amp;rsquo;ll leverage a feature of the &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/ios/v3/">Google Analytics iOS SDK&lt;/a> to build the parameters, and then push them to &lt;code>dataLayer&lt;/code> so that they can be used in the Tag.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Useful GTM For iOS Tips</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/useful-gtm-for-ios-tips/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 07:49:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/useful-gtm-for-ios-tips/</guid><description>&lt;p>A while ago I wrote a blog post about how to install &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> for iOS using the Swift programming language (you can read the article &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/setup-google-tag-manager-ios-with-swift/">here&lt;/a>). I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a lot of work with Swift lately, and I&amp;rsquo;m more and more convinced that GTM is actually a very powerful utility for running in your iOS app instead of the &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/ios/v3/">Google Analytics SDK&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why? Because it abstracts a lot of the nitty-gritty you&amp;rsquo;d otherwise need to explicitly manage in your GA installation. Also, by using the &lt;code>TAGDataLayer&lt;/code> interface, you&amp;rsquo;re abstracting stuff &lt;em>yourself&lt;/em>, not forced to adopt any specific syntax or semantic structure in your tracking. Instead, you&amp;rsquo;ll be leveraging generic key-value pairs and an object structure, which you&amp;rsquo;re probably already familiar with if you&amp;rsquo;ve worked with GTM for the web.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Setup Google Tag Manager iOS With Swift</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/setup-google-tag-manager-ios-with-swift/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 12:16:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/setup-google-tag-manager-ios-with-swift/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to write about &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> for &lt;strong>mobile apps&lt;/strong> for such a long time. Finally, I have some great use cases to share, as well as some useful examples for implementing &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/tag-manager/ios/v3/">GTM for iOS&lt;/a>. That&amp;rsquo;s right, this is an &lt;strong>iOS&lt;/strong> guide, and, to be more specific, geared towards a successful &lt;strong>Swift&lt;/strong> implementation.&lt;/p>


 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/images/2015/10/swift-xcode.jpg" title="Google Tag Manager iOS with Swift">
 
 &lt;amp-img src="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/images/2015/10/swift-xcode.jpg" layout="responsive" alt="Google Tag Manager iOS with Swift" height="822" width="2878">&lt;/amp-img>
 
 &lt;/a>
 

&lt;p>If you didn&amp;rsquo;t know, &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/swift/">Swift&lt;/a> is a relatively new programming language, developed by Apple for iOS and OS X programming. It&amp;rsquo;s got some nice synergies with existing Objective-C implementations, which means you can either gradually migrate to Swift, or just start writing new apps with it instantly.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>