<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cross-Domain Tracking on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/cross-domain-tracking/</link><description>Recent content in Cross-Domain Tracking on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 07:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/cross-domain-tracking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#GTMTips: Cross-domain Tracking In Google Analytics 4</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/cross-domain-tracking-google-analytics-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/cross-domain-tracking-google-analytics-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>Setting up &lt;strong>cross-domain tracking&lt;/strong> in &lt;strong>Google Analytics 4&lt;/strong> has been &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/10071811?hl=en">well-documented&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main departure from &lt;strong>Universal Analytics&lt;/strong> is how cross-domain measurement is something you configure through the &lt;em>Google Analytics user interface&lt;/em> rather than through implementation and JavaScript.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While this approach is obviously beneficial especially for those who lack the know-how or the resources to configure the JavaScript trackers, it does lead to problems, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, I want to tackle these edge cases. They are:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cookieless Tracking For Cross-site Iframes</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/cookieless-tracking-cross-site-iframes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 09:00:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/cookieless-tracking-cross-site-iframes/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Updated 25 May 2021&lt;/strong>: Added information about using this with GA4. As Google Analytics 4 does not have a mechanism to disable cookie storage, only the second solution (send &lt;code>dataLayer&lt;/code> events from iframe to the parent) described in this article will work for GA4.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Here I am, back with &lt;code>&amp;lt;iframe&amp;gt;&lt;/code> and &lt;strong>cross-domain tracking&lt;/strong>. I&amp;rsquo;ve published a couple of articles before on the topic, with &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/tracking-cross-domain-iframes-upgraded-solution/">my upgraded solution&lt;/a> being the most recent one. These articles tackle the general problem of &lt;strong>passing the Client ID from the parent to the &lt;code>&amp;lt;iframe&amp;gt;&lt;/code>&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Decorate Links And Decorate Forms Tag Types</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/decorate-links-decorate-forms-tags/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 12:39:45 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/decorate-links-decorate-forms-tags/</guid><description>&lt;p>Getting &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/#cross-domain-tracking-list">cross-domain tracking&lt;/a> right in &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com/">Google Analytics&lt;/a> is difficult. Even if you use &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>. There are many known issues when cross-domain tracking &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/iframe-cross-domain-tracking-in-google-tag-manager/">iframes&lt;/a>, for example.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Google Tag Manager implements the cross-domain tracking plugin quite handily via the Universal Analytics tag template, and often the easiest way to track links and form submits is to use the &lt;strong>Auto-Link Domains&lt;/strong> option, as described in this great series of posts on &lt;a href="https://www.bounteous.com/insights/2015/06/16/cross-domain-tracking-with-google-tag-manager/">cross-domain tracking&lt;/a> by Bounteous.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, sometimes you want more precision in decorating the URLs. Perhaps you only want to decorate one specific link rather than all links that share the same hostname. Or perhaps you only want to decorate forms when they are submitted by your actual visitors rather than internal users.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Auto Link Domains With Regex</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/auto-link-domains-with-regex/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 10:06:19 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/auto-link-domains-with-regex/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Update &lt;strong>5 March 2019&lt;/strong> due to GTM not supporting negative lookbehinds any more.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> makes it fairly easy to do &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/1034342">cross-domain tracking&lt;/a>. Basically, you list the hostnames you want to automatically decorate with linker parameters in the &lt;strong>Auto-Link Domains&lt;/strong> field of your Page View tag, and that takes care of decorating the URLs with the necessary parameter. It&amp;rsquo;s dead easy, even if there are a bunch of traps you need to watch out for (see my post on &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/troubleshooting-cross-domain-tracking-in-google-analytics/">troubleshooting cross-domain tracking issues&lt;/a>).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Cross-domain Tracking With Multiple GA Trackers</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/cross-domain-tracking-with-multiple-ga-trackers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 15:15:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/cross-domain-tracking-with-multiple-ga-trackers/</guid><description>&lt;p>To be fair, this tip isn&amp;rsquo;t just for &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> but for regular old on-page &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com/">Google Analytics&lt;/a> as well. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those little things that&amp;rsquo;s corroding your data quality without you ever realizing it. Namely, this tip is about how to handle &lt;strong>cross-domain tracking&lt;/strong> in situations where you are sending data to multiple Google Analytics properties on the same page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a very typical scenario - you have a &amp;ldquo;local&amp;rdquo; property, which tracks only the traffic of the current site, and then a &amp;ldquo;rollup&amp;rdquo; property, where you send data from all your organization&amp;rsquo;s websites. The rollup property would need cross-domain tracking enabled, since you want to track users across your organization&amp;rsquo;s many website domains.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting Cross-Domain Tracking In Google Analytics</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/troubleshooting-cross-domain-tracking-in-google-analytics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 08:23:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/troubleshooting-cross-domain-tracking-in-google-analytics/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/1034342?hl=en">Cross-domain tracking&lt;/a>, in &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com/">Google Analytics&lt;/a>, is the process of passing information stored in browser cookies from one domain to another. Due to web browsers&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Same-origin_policy">same-origin policy&lt;/a>, a browser cookie is only available to the domain it is written on and all its subdomains (by default). Since Google Analytics uses cookies to persist the &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookies-user-id">Client ID&lt;/a>, once the user moves from domain to domain it&amp;rsquo;s important to somehow pass this Client ID, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cross-domain tracking isn&amp;rsquo;t the easiest thing to implement, though. At its easiest, especially if you use &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>, it&amp;rsquo;s a question of configuring a couple of fields in your Google Analytics trackers and snippets. However, issues typically arise when your website uses unconventional link redirects, or when you want to &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/iframe-cross-domain-tracking-in-google-tag-manager/">persist the Client ID in an iframe&lt;/a> loaded from another domain.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>