<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tasks on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/tasks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tasks on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 07:15:38 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/tasks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>customTask - The Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/customtask-the-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 07:15:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/customtask-the-guide/</guid>
      <description>Last updated 4 September 2018
If you have been reading my blog articles over the past year, you might have noticed a disturbing trend. I&amp;rsquo;ve published 9 articles on customTask since the API was released. It might not sound like much, but I can&amp;rsquo;t think of a single feature in Google Analytics or Google Tag Manager that has so completely convinced me of its usefulness in such a short time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Send Google Analytics Tag To Multiple Properties</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/send-google-analytics-tag-multiple-properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 07:54:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/send-google-analytics-tag-multiple-properties/</guid>
      <description>Here we are again, revisiting an old theme. When using Google Tag Manager, we often want to send the contents of the same tag to multiple Universal Analytics properties. With on-page GA, this used to be quite simple, as all you had to do was create a new tracker and then just remember to run the ga(&#39;trackerName.send&#39;...) commands to all the trackers (or you could use my duplicator plugin). With GTM, your options are more limited, since Google Tag Manager abstracts the tracker object, giving you far fewer tools to work with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Use customTask To Access Tracker Values In Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/use-customtask-access-tracker-values-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 08:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/use-customtask-access-tracker-values-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>One of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve recommended from the get-go is to always send the Client ID to Google Analytics with your users&amp;rsquo; hits. This is very useful for adding a level of granularity to your tracking. At first, I recommended using an Event tag to do this. Then I modified my approach a little so that you could send it with your initial Page View (thus not inflating your hit counts).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Tracker Duplication For Universal Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/simple-tracker-duplication-universal-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 10:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/simple-tracker-duplication-universal-analytics/</guid>
      <description>First of all, I&amp;rsquo;m sorry about the title. I should really stop throwing the word &amp;ldquo;simple&amp;rdquo; around, since people always tell me that the stuff I claim to be easy and straightforward is rarely so. But since this is my blog, I reserve the right to use whatever stupid and misleading terminology I want. I maintain that what follows IS quite simple, especially when considering the amount of complexity it reduces in your Universal Analytics setup.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>