<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Itp on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/itp/</link><description>Recent content in Itp on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 09:00:56 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/itp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ITP Debug Mode in Safari</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/privacy/itp-debug-mode-in-safari/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 09:00:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/privacy/itp-debug-mode-in-safari/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Intelligent Tracking Prevention&lt;/strong> is the name of the &lt;a href="https://webkit.org/blog/category/privacy/">tracking prevention mechanism&lt;/a> implemented in WebKit and enabled in Safari and &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/privacy/intelligent-tracking-prevention-ios-14-ipados-14-safari-14/">all major browsers running on the iOS platform&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;ve written about it on &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/#itp-list">this blog&lt;/a>, and the &lt;a href="https://www.cookiestatus.com">CookieStatus.com&lt;/a> resource is something you should bookmark for further reading.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose of ITP is to prevent tracking tools&amp;rsquo; access to data stored and processed in the browser. This involves things like &lt;strong>blocking all third-party cookies&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>restricting the lifetime of first-party cookies&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intelligent Tracking Prevention In iOS 14, iPadOS 14, And Safari 14</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/privacy/intelligent-tracking-prevention-ios-14-ipados-14-safari-14/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 07:00:10 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/privacy/intelligent-tracking-prevention-ios-14-ipados-14-safari-14/</guid><description>&lt;p>Apple&amp;rsquo;s annual Worldwide Developer Conference in late June this year included a couple of big announcements around Apple&amp;rsquo;s approach to privacy in their software.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new &lt;strong>Privacy Report&lt;/strong> in Safari 14 (on all platforms) uses &lt;a href="https://github.com/duckduckgo/tracker-radar">DuckDuckGo&amp;rsquo;s tracker radar list&lt;/a> to detail which of the most prominent tracking-capable domains have been flagged by &lt;a href="https://webkit.org/blog/7675/intelligent-tracking-prevention/">Intelligent Tracking Prevention (ITP)&lt;/a> in the user&amp;rsquo;s browser.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apple also announced that the &lt;code>WKWebView&lt;/code> class, which all iOS and iPadOS (the operating systems for iPhones and iPads, respectively) must use, will include WebKit&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>ITP mechanisms on by default&lt;/strong>. The list of major browsers running on these operating systems includes Brave, Chrome, Edge, Firefox, and Safari.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Enable Preview Mode In The Safari Browser</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/enable-preview-mode-safari-browser/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 10:32:02 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/enable-preview-mode-safari-browser/</guid><description>&lt;p>With &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/itp-2-1-and-web-analytics/">Intelligent Tracking Prevention&lt;/a>, the Safari browser is on a crusade against cross-site tracking. One of the most obvious and long-standing ways to battle cross-site tracking has been to &lt;strong>block third-party cookies&lt;/strong> in the web browser, and this is exactly what Safari does by default.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a> Preview mode relies on a third-party cookies, so that it can serve you the draft version of the container while serving the regular, live container to your site visitors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Create A Cookie Rewrite Web Service Using The Google Cloud Platform</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/google-cloud/create-cookie-rewrite-web-service-google-cloud/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/google-cloud/create-cookie-rewrite-web-service-google-cloud/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Last updated 11 September 2020&lt;/strong>: Added &lt;a href="#step-4-map-the-custom-domain-to-the-endpoint">important note&lt;/a> about how the custom domain should be mapped with A/AAAA DNS records rather than a CNAME record.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Ah, Safari&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://webkit.org/blog/category/privacy/">Intelligent Tracking Prevention&lt;/a> - the gift that &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/itp-2-1-and-web-analytics/">keeps on giving&lt;/a>. Having almost milked this cow for all it&amp;rsquo;s worth, I was sure there would be little need to revisit the topic. Maybe, I thought, it would be better to just sit back and watch the world burn.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ITP 2.1 And Web Analytics</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/itp-2-1-and-web-analytics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 10:52:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/itp-2-1-and-web-analytics/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Updated 1 October 2019&lt;/strong> With &lt;a href="https://webkit.org/blog/9521/intelligent-tracking-prevention-2-3/">ITP 2.3&lt;/a> it looks like Safari is reducing the usefulness of &lt;code>localStorage&lt;/code> as well, so using that as an alternative fix to persistence issues should not be considered future-proof. this solution should &lt;strong>not&lt;/strong> be considered future-proof.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Updated &lt;strong>12 March 2019&lt;/strong> with some minor clarifications..&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>On 21st February 2019, &lt;a href="https://webkit.org/">WebKit&lt;/a> announced the release of the latest iteration of Safari&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Intelligent Tracking Prevention&lt;/strong> (ITP), known as &lt;a href="https://webkit.org/blog/8613/intelligent-tracking-prevention-2-1/">ITP 2.1&lt;/a>. For a while now, Safari has been targeting cross-site tracking with ITP, first starting with &lt;a href="https://webkit.org/blog/7675/intelligent-tracking-prevention/">cookies in third-party contexts&lt;/a>, then &lt;a href="https://webkit.org/blog/8311/intelligent-tracking-prevention-2-0/">tightening the noose&lt;/a> after a number of workarounds emerged, and finally with the latest iteration targeting cookies that were moved from a third-party context to a first-party context.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Use localStorage For Client ID Persistence In Google Analytics</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/use-localstorage-client-id-persistence-google-analytics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 12:31:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/use-localstorage-client-id-persistence-google-analytics/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Updated 1 October 2019&lt;/strong> With &lt;a href="https://webkit.org/blog/9521/intelligent-tracking-prevention-2-3/">ITP 2.3&lt;/a> it looks like Safari is reducing the usefulness of &lt;code>localStorage&lt;/code> as well, so this solution should &lt;strong>not&lt;/strong> be considered future-proof. The only stable way to persist client-side data at the moment seems to be &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/google-cloud/create-cookie-rewrite-web-service-google-cloud/">HTTP cookies&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Updated 7 March 2019&lt;/strong> - Added some extra &lt;a href="#caveats">caveats&lt;/a> to this solution. Also, be sure to read my article on &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/itp-2-1-and-web-analytics/">ITP 2.1&lt;/a>, which has far more detail on what Intelligent Tracking Prevention is and how to work with it.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>