<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chrome extension on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/chrome-extension/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chrome extension on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 07:31:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/chrome-extension/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Deploy GTM In Your Chrome Extension</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/gtmtips-deploy-gtm-chrome-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 07:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/gtmtips-deploy-gtm-chrome-extension/</guid>
      <description>Have you created a Chrome Extension, and now you&amp;rsquo;re dying to find out how users are interacting with it? Perhaps you want to see what features are (not) being utilized, or perhaps you&amp;rsquo;re just interested in knowing if people are actually using it.
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to configure Google Tag Manager, so that it works in the restricted sandbox of the Chrome Extension. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to make some tweaks, but it&amp;rsquo;s still perfectly doable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GTM Auto-Event Listener Debugger v1.1</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/gtm-auto-event-listener-debugger-v1-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 15:51:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/gtm-auto-event-listener-debugger-v1-1/</guid>
      <description>(Last updated June 2014: Read the latest post on the extension, GTM Sonar v1.2.)
I updated my Chrome Extension, GTM Auto-Event Listener Debugger v1.1. I released the first version a couple of days ago. The extension can be used to debug Google Tag Manager&amp;rsquo;s auto-event tracking and its compatibility with web page markup.
Download the latest version here.
I did some major changes, and here&amp;rsquo;s the rundown.
 I transferred all debugger actions into a pop-up, which opens when you click the Browser Action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging Auto-Event Tracking in GTM</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/debugging-auto-event-tracking-gtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 06:11:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/debugging-auto-event-tracking-gtm/</guid>
      <description>(Last updated June 2014: Read the latest post on the extension, GTM Sonar v1.2.)
Many of the Google Tag Manager articles on this blog could be considered hacks, in that they extend the out-of-the-box features of GTM in ways that will surely not be officially supported by Google. The crux of the problem is that lots of folks are taken by surprise when GTM refuses to work properly on their site, or when they have trouble tracking key elements on the page template.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>