<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>variables on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/variables/</link>
    <description>Recent content in variables on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 09:46:58 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/variables/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Check For Undefined Value</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/check-for-undefined-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 09:46:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/check-for-undefined-value/</guid>
      <description>This is one of those #GTMTips posts that I was certain I&amp;rsquo;d already written. So it came as a mild surprise when I realized I&amp;rsquo;d never tackled this aspect of Google Tag Manager.
It&amp;rsquo;s a short and sweet tip again. Today we&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to check if a variable is undefined using Google Tag Manager.
Tip 73: Check for undefined variable values   If a variable is undefined, it means that a variable with the given name does not currently have any valid value in memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: URL Source In The URL Variable</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/url-source-in-the-url-variable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 07:53:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/url-source-in-the-url-variable/</guid>
      <description>One of the less-known features of Google Tag Manager, a hidden gem if you will, is the URL Source setting in the URL Variable type. It lets you parse any URL String for its components.
Tip 38: Parse URL strings with the URL Source setting   The setting itself is easy to find. Just edit an existing URL Variable, or create a new one. Then, scroll down to the More Settings divider, expand it, and you&amp;rsquo;ll see the URL Source drop-down list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variable Guide For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/variable-guide-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 08:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/variable-guide-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>(Updated 21 February 2019)
The current version of Google Tag Manager was released in October 2014. With the release, we saw a brand-spanking new UI, a lot of new functionalities (revamped auto-event tracking, for example), plus a new terminology to cope with. We moved away from the programming-centric concepts of Macros and Rules to the more tactile variables and triggers.
It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to rank the changes. The new Auto-Event Tracking is perhaps most impactful, but the improvements done to triggers and variables, when compared to the previous version of GTM, require attention as well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>