<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>google optimize on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/google-optimize/</link>
    <description>Recent content in google optimize on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 09:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/google-optimize/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Way To Measure A/B Test Flicker Impact</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/simple-way-measure-a-b-test-flicker-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 09:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/simple-way-measure-a-b-test-flicker-impact/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Flickering&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Flash Of Original Content&amp;rdquo; (FOOC) is a phenomenon where there&#39;s a (typically) slight but observable delay in the browser updating the site or element layout if the user is included in a variant group for experimentation. This manifests in the original, unmodified element being rendered in the visible portion of the page before the experiment library updates it with the variant.
There are ways to mitigate the flicker:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Send Event And Custom Dimension If Google Optimize Experiment Is Running</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/send-event-custom-dimension-google-optimize-experiment-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 14:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/send-event-custom-dimension-google-optimize-experiment-running/</guid>
      <description>I really like Google Optimize. It has a fairly intuitive UI, setting up experiments is easy, and there&#39;s integrations for both Google Tag Manager and Google Analytics built into the system. It&#39;s still a JavaScript-based, client-side A/B-testing tool, so problems with flicker and asynchronous loading are ever-present (though this is somewhat mitigated by the page-hiding snippet).
One issue with the Google Analytics integration is the difficulty of creating segments for sessions where the users were actively participating in the experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>