<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Slack on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/slack/</link><description>Recent content in Slack on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 09:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/slack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create Slack Notification System For Google Tag Manager Changes</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/create-slack-notification-system-google-tag-manager-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/create-slack-notification-system-google-tag-manager-changes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Until recently, I had a feature on &lt;a href="https://www.gtmtools/">GTM Tools&lt;/a> that polled the user&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> container(s) for a recently published version. If one was found, a notification was sent to a &lt;a href="https://www.slack.com/apps/">Slack app&lt;/a>, which forwarded it to a workspace and channel of the user&amp;rsquo;s choice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was fine, except for the fact that polling the GTM and Slack APIs for dozens upon dozens of containers is a total resource hog, and the only way I can maintain GTM Tools is it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have API leaks like that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DIY Google Ads Account Monitor With R, AdWords API, And Slack API</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/web-development/monitor-google-ads-accounts-r-adwords-api-slack-api/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 09:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/web-development/monitor-google-ads-accounts-r-adwords-api-slack-api/</guid><description>&lt;p>Every now and then I&amp;rsquo;m fortunate enough to be able to publish &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/guest-post/">guest posts&lt;/a> by illustrious people in the analytics and digital marketing industries. This time, I get to work with an old colleague of mine who&amp;rsquo;s a veritable wizard when it comes to building solutions that make our daily work in the digital industry so much smoother.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Erik Grönroos&lt;/strong> works as an analyst in &lt;a href="https://markkinointiakatemia.fi/">MarkkinointiAkatemia&lt;/a>, a Finnish digital customer acquisition agency. Erik&amp;rsquo;s job is to utilize data and analytics to help grow the agency as well as the companies of the clients he works with.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>