<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Php on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/php/</link><description>Recent content in Php on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 09:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/php/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Improve Google Analytics Bot Detection With reCAPTCHA</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/improve-google-analytics-bot-detection-with-recaptcha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 09:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/improve-google-analytics-bot-detection-with-recaptcha/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are thousands upon thousands of bots, crawlers, spiders, and other creepy-crawlies out there doing nothing but crawling through websites and harvesting the content within for whatever purposes they have been fine-tuned to. While &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com/">Google Analytics&lt;/a> provides &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/1010249?hl=en">a bot filtering feature&lt;/a> to filter out &amp;ldquo;spam&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;bot traffic&amp;rdquo; from views, this is far from comprehensive enough to tackle all instances of bot traffic that might enter the site.&lt;/p>


 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/images/2019/09/bot-traffic-in-ga.jpg" title="Bot traffic in GA">
 
 &lt;amp-img src="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/images/2019/09/bot-traffic-in-ga.jpg" layout="responsive" alt="Bot traffic in GA" height="502" width="1634">&lt;/amp-img>
 
 &lt;/a>
 

&lt;p>You might have noticed bot traffic in your data even if you have bot filtering toggled on. For instance, such traffic could be characterized as follows:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Send Mail Upon Google Tag Manager Event</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/send-mail-upon-google-tag-manager-event/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 04:49:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/send-mail-upon-google-tag-manager-event/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s say you want to set up a rudimentary email alert system in your &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/tagmanager">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> implementation. Say, for example, you want to receive an email every time an uncaught error occurs on your website. It&amp;rsquo;s not a very good use case, since a large website can spawn hundreds of uncaught exceptions in a short period of time, but let&amp;rsquo;s just pretend for now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you know your JavaScript, you&amp;rsquo;ll know that you can&amp;rsquo;t send mail using client-side code. That&amp;rsquo;s a browser security thing, and I completely understand it. However, a vast majority of websites are created using a CMS which might provide some mail function or hook for you to use. And even if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a cooperative web server (or there&amp;rsquo;s no way you can persuade your developers to help), you could use any one of the &lt;a href="http://www.programmableweb.com/apis/directory/1?apicat=email">online email APIs&lt;/a> that are out there.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>