<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tips on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/tips/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tips on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 10:18:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>100&#43; Google Tag Manager Learnings</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/100-google-tag-manager-learnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 10:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/100-google-tag-manager-learnings/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve always been proud to avoid the typical headline clickbait of &amp;ldquo;Ultimate guide to pigeon care&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;All you need to know about the Great Vowel Shift&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Did you know that you&#39;ve been smoking peyote wrong your whole life?&amp;quot;. I&#39;m ready to make an exception now by adding a BIG WHOPPING NUMBER to the title. You see, the amount of knowledge one can accumulate about anything they do on a daily basis is mind-blowing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Ecommerce Tips And Learnings</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-tips-and-learnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 07:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-tips-and-learnings/</guid>
      <description>Enhanced Ecommerce is undoubtedly an excellent feature of Google Analytics. It provides us with a set of reports that truly extend the capabilities of funnel-based website analysis. As I&#39;ve shown before, it&#39;s also very useful for tracking other transactional events on your site, such as content engagement.
  However, here&#39;s the thing. It&#39;s not very easy to implement. Even if you get everything right according to the documentation, there are still quite a number of pitfalls, and many of the learnings emerge only through experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun With Google Tag Manager: Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/fun-google-tag-manager-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 06:52:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/fun-google-tag-manager-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Apologies for leaving you hanging. It&#39;s now almost three weeks since I published the first part of this post, and I&#39;m sure you&#39;ve been holding your breath ever since.
There&#39;s been a lot going on since the last post. First, my favorite sports team in the world, San Antonio Spurs, won their fifth NBA championship from the defending champs, Miami Heat. Next, my wife and I moved to our new house, and we&#39;ve been remodeling ever since.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Not About Marketing</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/digital-marketing/its-not-about-marketing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 17:46:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/digital-marketing/its-not-about-marketing/</guid>
      <description>In a recent post, I took a short foray into the world of clumsy analogies by comparing the team work qualities (and necessities) of basketball and digital marketing. In an even earlier post, I made the claim that the single most important facet of content strategy is audience design. Well, now is the time to pull these two threads together all trilogy-like. After this, you can hail me as the Stieg Larsson of marketing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>