<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Extension on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/extension/</link><description>Recent content in Extension on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 07:07:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/extension/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Internalize for Google Analytics v1.0</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/internalize-google-analytics-v1-0/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 07:07:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/internalize-google-analytics-v1-0/</guid><description>&lt;p>I created a new Chrome Extension: Internalize for Google Analytics. This is its very first version. It only works on websites with &lt;strong>Universal Analytics&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/ompkhpfgcljnliggppohceaggjljpgdn/">Click here to download Internalize for Google Analytics v1.0&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The idea is that with the extension you can push a custom dimension value to your currently active session. You can then use a profile filter in GA to block traffic with this custom dimension value. It&amp;rsquo;s useful when blocking internal traffic with more traditional means (IP address or various &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/block-internal-traffic-gtm/">GTM workarounds&lt;/a>) won&amp;rsquo;t work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Tag Manager: DOM Listener</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-dom-listener/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 05:10:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-dom-listener/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through a tutorial on how to create a &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/tagmanager">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> extension. This extension will be a &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/auto-event-tracking-google-tag-manager/">new listener&lt;/a>, whose sole job is to listen for changes in the HTML and CSS markup on the page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The reason I&amp;rsquo;m teaching you how to create a DOM listener is simple. Ever so often I come across people asking for help, but they are unable to touch on-page code. Usually the problem is magnified with &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/form-tracking-google-tag-manager/">form handlers&lt;/a>, since the developers might have installed some custom jQuery form manager, for instance, which simply refuses to cooperate with GTM&amp;rsquo;s form listeners. That is why you might want to fire a GTM event when a certain message pops up on the screen, for example.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>