<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>enhanced ecommerce on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/enhanced-ecommerce/</link>
    <description>Recent content in enhanced ecommerce on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 11:48:29 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/enhanced-ecommerce/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Ecommerce Object Builder Template For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-builder-custom-variable-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 11:48:29 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-builder-custom-variable-template/</guid>
      <description>One of the cool things about Enhanced Ecommerce deployments in Google Tag Manager is that you can use a Custom JavaScript variable to generate the necessary data.
There are many reasons to do so, with the biggest one being the flexibility it offers for manipulating the dataLayer object in case quick changes are required on the site, and it would take too long to wait for a new release of the site JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Use Enhanced Ecommerce Data Layer With Facebook Pixel</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-facebook-pixel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 13:45:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-facebook-pixel/</guid>
      <description>A recurring question in the Google Tag Manager communities (e.g. product forums) is how to use an Enhanced Ecommerce dataLayer object with the Facebook pixel code? It&#39;s a common question since running a Facebook conversion pixel on a site that also collects data from the store into Google Analytics&amp;rsquo; Enhanced Ecommerce reports is probably a very typical scenario.
 Side note: Since Google+ is about to go the way of the dodo, I&#39;ve created an archive of the entire community which you can browse and make text searches against.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>True View Ecommerce Impressions With Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/true-view-impressions-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 11:36:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/true-view-impressions-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m a big fan of Enhanced Ecommerce in Google Analytics. In fact, I think it&#39;s the only valid way to deploy Ecommerce tracking today, especially when using Google Tag Manager. The ability to use a Custom JavaScript variable and the possibility to tackle the full ecommerce funnel are some of the benefits of using Enhanced Ecommerce.
However, tracking certain view-based events, impressions in particular, has a significant problem when it comes to how Google Analytics processes events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prevent Duplicate Transactions In Google Analytics With customTask</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/prevent-google-analytics-duplicate-transactions-with-customtask/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 10:46:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/prevent-google-analytics-duplicate-transactions-with-customtask/</guid>
      <description>One of the big problems in Google Analytics&amp;rsquo; data model is the immutability of historical data. Once a row of data is written into the data table, it is there practically for good. This is especially annoying in two cases: spam and bogus ecommerce hits. The first is a recognized issue with an open and public data collection protocol, the latter is an annoyance that can explode into full-blown sabotage (you can use the Measurement Protocol to send hundreds of huge transactions to your competitor&#39;s GA property, for example).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Ecommerce Guide For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-guide-for-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 08:35:17 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-guide-for-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>Enhanced Ecommerce is certainly one of the finest reporting user interface features that Google Analytics has to offer. Enhanced Ecommerce, as the name implies, is a set of dimensions, metrics, and reports, which combine to provide you with a fairly complete view into how users are interacting with your products in your webstore. The main downside of Enhanced Ecommerce is, as with all good things, that it&#39;s complicated to implement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attribution In Enhanced Ecommerce Reports</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/attribution-enhanced-ecommerce-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 08:42:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/attribution-enhanced-ecommerce-reports/</guid>
      <description>Enhanced Ecommerce is a very useful set of reports in Google Analytics. They extend the standard Ecommerce funnel, which measures only purchases, and allow you to observe products from the very first impression, through various interactions, all the way to the purchase and even beyond, if the user wanted a refund. Google has some solid documentation on how to implement and interpret Enhanced Ecommerce, but if there&#39;s one area that would deserve more illumination, it&#39;s attribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Ecommerce Tips And Learnings</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-tips-and-learnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 07:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-tips-and-learnings/</guid>
      <description>Enhanced Ecommerce is undoubtedly an excellent feature of Google Analytics. It provides us with a set of reports that truly extend the capabilities of funnel-based website analysis. As I&#39;ve shown before, it&#39;s also very useful for tracking other transactional events on your site, such as content engagement.
  However, here&#39;s the thing. It&#39;s not very easy to implement. Even if you get everything right according to the documentation, there are still quite a number of pitfalls, and many of the learnings emerge only through experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Product-Scoped Custom Dimensions And Metrics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/product-scoped-custom-dimensions-and-metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 07:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/product-scoped-custom-dimensions-and-metrics/</guid>
      <description>With the advent of Enhanced Ecommerce for Universal Analytics, a new scope was introduced for Custom Dimensions and Metrics. Product scope can be used to send information about each product that is sent through Enhanced Ecommerce, but it&#39;s not exactly the most logical or intuitive thing to wrap your head around.
In this #GTMTips post, we&#39;ll take a look at how to implement Product-Scoped Custom definitions via Google Tag Manager, and I&#39;ll quickly explain how they work in relation to queries and reports you might want to build on top of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measure Cart Value In Enhanced Ecommerce</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/measure-cart-value-in-enhanced-ecommerce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 15:11:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/measure-cart-value-in-enhanced-ecommerce/</guid>
      <description>One of the glaring omissions in the Enhanced Ecommerce reports of Universal Analytics is the ability to calculate cart value for products. Cart value, here, is the value that has been added to the cart.
This value can be used to query for products that have the highest discrepancy between cart value and generated revenue. These are missed opportunities of the highest caliber.
With some Custom Metrics magic, we can, however, get cart value into our reports, and we can find our most and least &amp;ldquo;effective&amp;rdquo; products with just a glance:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Ecommerce With A Custom JavaScript Variable</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-with-a-custom-javascript-variable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 08:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-with-a-custom-javascript-variable/</guid>
      <description>Enhanced Ecommerce is a very nice improvement to the pretty lame, transaction-based Ecommerce tracking in Universal Analytics. Instead of staring blindly at what happens on a receipt page, Enhanced Ecommerce expands your entire webstore into one large funnel labelled &amp;ldquo;Shopping Behavior&amp;rdquo;, and you&#39;re able to zoom in on the Checkout funnel as well. Also, the addition of product-scoped tracking is incredibly useful, and it&#39;s enabled us to think of any asset (our content, for example) on our site as something we could track through the Enhanced Ecommerce reports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track Content With Enhanced Ecommerce</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-content-enhanced-ecommerce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 12:18:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-content-enhanced-ecommerce/</guid>
      <description>My fingers have been tingling to write this article. Ever since I implemented Enhanced Ecommerce on my blog a couple of weeks ago, I&#39;ve been getting such an impressive amount of useful data that it&#39;s mind-boggling.
In this article, I&#39;ll walk you through the steps I went to implement the solution, along with examples of the data I can now access through Google Analytics&amp;rsquo; reporting interface. As you might have guessed, if you&#39;ve read my articles before, I implemented Enhanced Ecommerce with Google Tag Manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eCommerce Tips For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/ecommerce-tips-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 07:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/ecommerce-tips-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve noticed that setting up eCommerce in Google Tag Manager (and now the new Enhanced ecommerce) is very difficult for many. I&#39;m sure part of the problem is that eCommerce is for many users the moment that GTM forces you to take steps in to the developer&#39;s domain, since it&#39;s obvious that you&#39;ll need to add some code to the web page.
This isn&#39;t a tutorial on how to do eCommerce in Google Tag Manager.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>