<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Customtask on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/customtask/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Customtask on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 16:15:24 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/customtask/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Introducing The customTask Builder</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/introducing-customtask-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 16:15:24 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/introducing-customtask-builder/</guid>
      <description>One of the coolest features of Google Analytics and, as a consequence, Google Tag Manager is customTask. It&amp;rsquo;s a method you can use to add and execute code as the hit to Google Analytics is being generated.
I&amp;rsquo;ve written A LOT about customTask, and much of the feedback I&amp;rsquo;ve received has been around the question of how to combine all these different tricks into one customTask script. The problem is, you see, that a tag or hit can only have one customTask script attached to it, so the code within must combine all the different tricks I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing about over the past months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically Reduce Google Analytics Payload Length</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/automatically-reduce-google-analytics-payload-length/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 11:04:14 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/automatically-reduce-google-analytics-payload-length/</guid>
      <description>Here we are, reunited with customTask. This time, we&amp;rsquo;ll put this wonderful mechanism to work for a very, very good cause. One of the lesser known &amp;ldquo;features&amp;rdquo; of Google Analytics is that when the payload size (the request body that is actually sent to Google Analytics with each request) goes past a certain limit, specifically 8192 bytes, the hit is aborted without warning. This can come as a surprise, because there&amp;rsquo;s no indication anywhere in Google Analytics that you are missing hits because of this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Add Hit Type As A Custom Dimension</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/add-hit-type-custom-dimension/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 15:17:39 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/add-hit-type-custom-dimension/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a considerable amount of time talking and writing about how to improve the granularity of your Google Analytics data, especially when using Google Tag Manager. I&amp;rsquo;ve also gone on and on and on (and on) about customTask, which makes adding metadata to the Google Analytics hits dispatched from your website a breeze.
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll introduce a simple way to add yet another level of detail to your GA hits, using customTask as the method of choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Send Google Analytics Payload Length As Custom Dimension</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/send-google-analytics-payload-length-as-custom-dimension/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 10:02:51 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/send-google-analytics-payload-length-as-custom-dimension/</guid>
      <description>Maybe you knew this, maybe you didn&amp;rsquo;t, but requests sent from your website (or app) to Google Analytics have a maximum size. Or, more specifically, the payload size (meaning the actual content body of the request) has a maximum.
This maximum size of the payload is 8192 bytes. This means, basically, that the entire parameter string sent to Google Analytics servers can be no longer than 8192 characters in length.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>customTask - The Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/customtask-the-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 07:15:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/customtask-the-guide/</guid>
      <description>If you have been reading my blog articles over the past year, you might have noticed a disturbing trend. I&amp;rsquo;ve published 9 articles on customTask since the API was released. It might not sound like much, but I can&amp;rsquo;t think of a single feature in Google Analytics or Google Tag Manager that has so completely convinced me of its usefulness in such a short time.
The customTask API is a feature of the Universal Analytics library (used by Google Tag Manager&amp;rsquo;s tags, too).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Automatically Duplicate Google Analytics Hits To Snowplow</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/automatically-fork-google-analytics-hits-snowplow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 08:30:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/automatically-fork-google-analytics-hits-snowplow/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m back with another customTask tip, but this time I&amp;rsquo;m exploring some new territory. Snowplow just introduced their latest version update, which included (among other things) an adapter for processing Google Analytics payloads. Never heard of Snowplow? It&amp;rsquo;s a collection of open-source libraries designed to let you build your own analytics pipeline, all the way from data collection, through ETL (extract, transform, load), using custom enrichments and JSON schemas, and finally into your own data warehouse, where you can then analyze the data using whatever tools you find preferable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Opt-out Of Google Analytics Tracking</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/opt-out-of-google-analytics-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 16:17:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/opt-out-of-google-analytics-tracking/</guid>
      <description>A while ago I posted a #GTMTips post where I detailed the steps you can take to opt-out of all Google Analytics tracking and the DoubleClick redirects that often follow. It was a fun exercise, but because it relies on preventing requests on a tag-by-tag basis (using the ubiquituous customTask), it can be a chore to handle in large containers.
In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll continue with the theme of opting out from Google Analytics tracking by leveraging a solution provided by the tool itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Auto Link Domains With Regex</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/auto-link-domains-with-regex/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 10:06:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/auto-link-domains-with-regex/</guid>
      <description>Google Tag Manager makes it fairly easy to do cross-domain tracking. Basically, you list the hostnames you want to automatically decorate with linker parameters in the Auto-Link Domains field of your Page View tag, and that takes care of decorating the URLs with the necessary parameter. It&amp;rsquo;s dead easy, even if there are a bunch of traps you need to watch out for (see my post on troubleshooting cross-domain tracking issues).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Send Event And Custom Dimension If Google Optimize Experiment Is Running</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/send-event-custom-dimension-google-optimize-experiment-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 14:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/send-event-custom-dimension-google-optimize-experiment-running/</guid>
      <description>I really like Google Optimize. It has a fairly intuitive UI, setting up experiments is easy, and there&amp;rsquo;s integrations for both Google Tag Manager and Google Analytics built into the system. It&amp;rsquo;s still a JavaScript-based, client-side A/B-testing tool, so problems with flicker and asynchronous loading are ever-present (though this is somewhat mitigated by the page-hiding snippet).
One issue with the Google Analytics integration is the difficulty of creating segments for sessions where the users were actively participating in the experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Respect Opt-Out From Advertising And Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/respect-opt-out-from-advertising-and-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 08:09:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/respect-opt-out-from-advertising-and-analytics/</guid>
      <description>With GDPR looming around the corner, it&amp;rsquo;s time to explore the options you have at your disposal for respecting the new, stricter regulations for tracking users and for collecting data about their visits to your website.
 UPDATE 20 June 2018: Google has released the allowAdFeatures field which renders the solution below redundant (at least for the displayFeaturesTask part of it). Please refer to this article for more details on how to conditionally block the advertising hit to DoubleClick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prevent Site Speed Sampling Rate From Skewing Custom Dimensions And Custom Metrics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/prevent-site-speed-sampling-rate-skewing-custom-dimensions-custom-metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 14:09:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/prevent-site-speed-sampling-rate-skewing-custom-dimensions-custom-metrics/</guid>
      <description>Universal Analytics can collect Page Timing data from users that load your pages. This data is populated in to the Behavior -&amp;gt; Site Speed -&amp;gt; Page Timings report, and it&amp;rsquo;s a very useful feature for optimizing your website.
  However, there&amp;rsquo;s a murky underside to this generous feature. The way Page Timings collection works is that when Pageview hits are sent from the site, a sample of these (1% by default) are automatically followed by a timing hit which includes page performance data grabbed from the Navigation Timing API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Remove PII From Google Analytics Hits</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/remove-pii-google-analytics-hits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 14:31:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/remove-pii-google-analytics-hits/</guid>
      <description>Sending personally identifiable information (PII) to Google Analytics is one of the things you should really avoid doing. For one, it&amp;rsquo;s against the terms of service of the platform, but also you will most likely be in violation of national, federal, or EU legislation drafted to protect the privacy of individuals online.
In this #GTMTips post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you a way to make sure that any tags you configure this solution with will not contain strings that might be construed as PII.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track Users Who Are Offline In Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/track-users-who-are-offline-in-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 08:19:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/track-users-who-are-offline-in-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>The steady increase in mobile use over the last years has introduced some new challenges for web analytics. It&amp;rsquo;s not just about mismatches in the tracking model (the concept of sessions is even more absurd for apps than it is for desktop browsing), but about something more fundamental, more basic. Think about it: if a visitor visits the website using a mobile device, there&amp;rsquo;s a significant chance of them losing internet connectivity and going unintentionally offline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Send Google Analytics Tag To Multiple Properties</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/send-google-analytics-tag-multiple-properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 07:54:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/send-google-analytics-tag-multiple-properties/</guid>
      <description>Here we are again, revisiting an old theme. When using Google Tag Manager, we often want to send the contents of the same tag to multiple Universal Analytics properties. With on-page GA, this used to be quite simple, as all you had to do was create a new tracker and then just remember to run the ga(&#39;trackerName.send&#39;...) commands to all the trackers (or you could use my duplicator plugin). With GTM, your options are more limited, since Google Tag Manager abstracts the tracker object, giving you far fewer tools to work with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Use customTask To Access Tracker Values In Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/use-customtask-access-tracker-values-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 08:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/use-customtask-access-tracker-values-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>One of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve recommended from the get-go is to always send the Client ID to Google Analytics with your users&amp;rsquo; hits. This is very useful for adding a level of granularity to your tracking. At first, I recommended using an Event tag to do this. Then I modified my approach a little so that you could send it with your initial Page View (thus not inflating your hit counts).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>