<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>macros on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/macros/</link>
    <description>Recent content in macros on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 08:20:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/macros/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Variable Guide For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/variable-guide-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 08:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/variable-guide-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>(Updated 21 February 2019)
The current version of Google Tag Manager was released in October 2014. With the release, we saw a brand-spanking new UI, a lot of new functionalities (revamped auto-event tracking, for example), plus a new terminology to cope with. We moved away from the programming-centric concepts of Macros and Rules to the more tactile variables and triggers.
It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to rank the changes. The new Auto-Event Tracking is perhaps most impactful, but the improvements done to triggers and variables, when compared to the previous version of GTM, require attention as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMtips: Chain Macros In Lookup Tables</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/chain-macros-lookup-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 10:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/chain-macros-lookup-tables/</guid>
      <description>One of the cool things about using a tag management solution is that you can leverage variables like never before. In Google Tag Manager, these variables are referred to as macros, and you can identify a macro with the syntax of {{macro name}}. In this tip I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how you can actually call macros from other macros, using a Lookup Table as an example.
Tip 5: Chain Macros In Lookup Tables (And Other Macros)   It&amp;rsquo;s not just Lookup Tables, either.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun With Google Tag Manager: Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/fun-with-google-tag-manager-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 13:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/fun-with-google-tag-manager-part-1/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s time to dig into my tip library for some pretty cool things you can do with Google Tag Manager to enhance your site tagging. Some of these are macro magic through and through, some of these are best practices, and some of these are things that will make your life easier while managing a tag management solution.
  I&amp;rsquo;ve split this post into two parts to make it more Hobbit and less Lord Of the Rings length-wise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Split Test With Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/simple-split-test-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 11:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/simple-split-test-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>Over the last couple of posts I&amp;rsquo;ve mainly been doing proof-of-concept (POC) tests with Google Tag Manager. The great thing about a POC is that you don&amp;rsquo;t really need to have any viable results or insight-driving technological innovations. The point is to showcase some feature of the platform on which the experiment was conducted.
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll take a care-free step into the world of POCs again. My goal is to do a simple split test in order to identify which variant of a landing page (or key element thereof) produces the most conversions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Form Tracking In Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/form-tracking-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 07:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/form-tracking-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>There is a new, updated version of this article for the new version of Google Tag Manager. I strongly suggest you read that as well!
I really enjoy the ad hoc Q&amp;amp;A sessions my blog posts have inspired. I haven&amp;rsquo;t said this enough, but I am really, REALLY grateful to people who take their time to comment on my posts, even if it&amp;rsquo;s just say a quick &amp;ldquo;Hi!&amp;rdquo;. The main reason I enjoy getting blog comments is because they often turn into blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macro Magic For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/macro-magic-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 08:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/macro-magic-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>(Last updated June 2014) This post is an attempt at a whole new level of interaction. These words will transcend the barriers of time and space, bridging together the physical world and its digital counterpart. You see, in an undisclosed number of hours after the publishing of this blog post, I will be talking at the MeasureCamp unconference on this very subject. Or, I hope I will. The whole unconference thing is somewhat confusing, and it involves lighting-fast reflexes and street smarts for slot selection; traits which I sadly lack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Block Internal Traffic With Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/block-internal-traffic-gtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 11:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/block-internal-traffic-gtm/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;ve probably come across a number of guides or posts talking about why it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to block so-called internal traffic from your web analytics reports. The reasons are pretty solid: internal traffic does not emulate normal visitor behavior, it rarely contributes to conversions (skewing up your conversion rate), it inflates page views, and it wreaks havoc on your granular, page-by-page data.
Internal traffic is vaguely described as &amp;ldquo;your employees&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;people really close to your brand&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;your marketing department&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;your web editors&amp;rdquo;, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Awesome Google Tag Manager Resources</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/awesome-google-tag-manager-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 15:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/awesome-google-tag-manager-resources/</guid>
      <description>When push comes to shove, I&amp;rsquo;m a pretty lazy guy. I enjoy nothing more than just to stretch my legs on a couch, pick up my iPad, and read what&amp;rsquo;s going on in the world. I skip the news, since they&amp;rsquo;re just full of depressing stories. Instead, I head over to my favorite Google+ communities to see what&amp;rsquo;s new in the blogosphere.
  This approach has led me to some pretty amazing individuals, whom I follow like a suckerfish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macro Guide For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/macro-guide-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 16:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/macro-guide-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written a new Variable Guide for Google Tag Manager, which covers the new GTM UI. This guide is for the old UI.
You might be vaguely familiar with macros if you&amp;rsquo;ve ever used a computer. Basically, whenever you perform a complicated task with a simple gesture, or reuse complex code with a simple input mechanism, you&amp;rsquo;re using macros. Think keyboard shortcuts.
In Google Tag Manager, this is the essence of macros.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Tag Manager: The Lookup Table Macro</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-lookup-table-macro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 08:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-lookup-table-macro/</guid>
      <description>Having just come hot of the press with my latest article on GTM and Content Grouping which, to my delight, Bounteous had written an amazing tutorial on earlier, Brian Kuhn and the amazing Google Tag Manager development team came out with another incredible new feature: The Lookup Table Macro.
In software engineering, a lookup table is an array which takes away a layer of complexity in runtime computation, and replaces it with a simple value assignment based on array indexing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto-Event Tracking In Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/auto-event-tracking-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2013 05:20:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/auto-event-tracking-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>There is a new version of this post for GTM V2 here.
The Google Analytics Summit came and went, and thanks to the Live Stream, everyone could participate. We were treated to a rapid-fire selection of Google Analytics&amp;rsquo; new features, and this post sheds light on one of these in particular: automated event tracking in Google Tag Manager.
Auto-event tracking introduces a nice feature, which does what tag managers ought to do: it provides functionality without HTML template editing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>