<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tracker on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/tracker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tracker on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 11:58:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/tracker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Fix The Rogue Referral Problem In Single-Page Sites</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/fix-rogue-referral-problem-single-page-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 11:58:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/fix-rogue-referral-problem-single-page-sites/</guid>
      <description>Single-page sites (or single-page apps) typically have just one page load. When navigating the site, subsequent content is either uncovered from the DOM, where it&#39;s been in a hidden state, or loaded from the server using HTTP requests that do not invoke a new page refresh. This behavior, however, has some implications for Google Analytics tracking, especially when configured via Google Tag Manager.
The crux of the problem is this: When you create a Google Analytics tracker, the URL of the page (without a possible #hash) from when the tracker was created is sent as the value of the Document Location field with every hit that uses this tracker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing GA Spy For Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/introducing-ga-spy-for-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 10:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/introducing-ga-spy-for-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>This is a guest post by Stephen Harris from Seer Interactive . He was kind enough to share his awesome solution in this blog, so I&#39;m very grateful indeed for his contribution.
If Google Tag Manager is loaded as the primary instrument for tracking on a webpage (as it should be), then all webpage tracking could and should be configurable via GTM. But we don&#39;t always control the circumstances, and it&#39;s not uncommon to face hardcoded Google Analytics tracking outside of GTM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GA Snippet And GA (GTM) Tag On The Same Page</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/ga-snippet-and-ga-gtm-tag-on-the-same-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 09:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/ga-snippet-and-ga-gtm-tag-on-the-same-page/</guid>
      <description>In this article, I&#39;m going to tackle one of the most frequently asked questions out there:
Can you run Google Analytics using the snippet AND using a Google Tag Manager Tag on the same page?
  There are many facets to this query, so I&#39;ll try to tackle as many of them as I possibly can.
First, a terminology rant. You hear lots of talk about &amp;ldquo;on-page&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;inline&amp;rdquo; Google Analytics tracking, as that&#39;s what&#39;s used to describe the non-GTM way of tracking Google Analytics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Be Careful With The Tracker Name Setting</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/be-careful-with-the-tracker-name-setting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 11:44:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/be-careful-with-the-tracker-name-setting/</guid>
      <description>Hello friends! Today I want to direct your attention to a dangerous setting found within the bowels of the Universal Analytics Tag template in Google Tag Manager. In fact, GTM itself highly discourages you from meddling with it:
  I actually agree with this warning. It should be highly discouraged, as modifying the tracker name introduces a potential hazard to your tracking plan, unless you know what you&#39;re doing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>