<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Events on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/events/</link><description>Recent content in Events on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 07:00:51 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Implementation Guide For Events In Google Analytics 4</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/implementation-guide-events-google-analytics-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 07:00:51 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/implementation-guide-events-google-analytics-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>On the surface, tracking &lt;strong>events&lt;/strong> in &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/ga4">Google Analytics 4&lt;/a> (GA4) is fairly simple. Events are, after all, pretty much the &lt;em>only thing&lt;/em> you can collect in GA4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get tied down with endless comparisons to Universal Analytics, though. While I&amp;rsquo;m steadfastly opposed to the idea that GA4 should resemble Universal Analytics, it&amp;rsquo;s still important to &lt;em>cleanse the palate&lt;/em> and approach GA4&amp;rsquo;s event tracking with an open mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are some comparisons that can be drawn between the new and the old, but what GA4 might lack in some features and use cases, it more than makes up for this with a more flexible data structure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Simple Custom Event Listeners With Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/simple-custom-event-listeners-gtm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 12:12:01 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/simple-custom-event-listeners-gtm/</guid><description>&lt;p>First of all, check out &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/custom-event-listeners-gtm/">this article&lt;/a> for an overview of how custom event listeners work in &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>. The reason I&amp;rsquo;m writing this &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/gtmtips/">#GTMTips&lt;/a> article is that I want to upgrade the solution slightly, and I want to bring it back into the spotlight. Why? Because it&amp;rsquo;s still one of the most effective ways to customize your Google Tag Manager implementation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>custom event listener&lt;/strong> is a handler you write with JavaScript. It lets you handle any &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Events">JavaScript DOM events&lt;/a>, such as click, form submit, mouse hover, drag, touch, error, page load and unload, and so many more. It also lets you leverage the &lt;code>useCapture&lt;/code> parameter which will prove very helpful if you have &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/fix-problems-with-gtm-listeners/">other JavaScript on the site interfering&lt;/a> with GTM&amp;rsquo;s default event &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/trigger-guide-google-tag-manager/">triggers&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMtips: Add The "event" Key To dataLayer Pushes</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/add-the-event-key-to-datalayer-pushes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 09:10:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/add-the-event-key-to-datalayer-pushes/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a href="http://tagmanager.google.com">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>, every single Tag requires a Trigger to fire. Every single Trigger requires an Event condition to activate. Sometimes, these Event conditions are obfuscated under template semantics, but you can also create a Custom Event Trigger, where you specify the value of the &amp;rsquo;event&amp;rsquo; key in &lt;code>dataLayer&lt;/code> that fires your tag. You can read more about the relationship between GTM events and Tags in these two posts:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/gtmtips-rules-nutshell/">#GTMtips: Rules In A Nutshell&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMtips: Create A Generic Event Tag</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/create-a-generic-event-tag/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 08:28:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/create-a-generic-event-tag/</guid><description>&lt;p>With &lt;a href="http://tagmanager.google.com">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>, there are a million different ways to make your tagging setup leaner and more flexible. The reason this should be a priority is because the UI isn&amp;rsquo;t perfect. The more tags you have, the more difficult it becomes to manage your assets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/categories/gtm-tips/">#GTMtips&lt;/a> post, I show you one of my favorite ways to put your container on a diet.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="tip-13-how-to-create-a-generic-event-tag">Tip 13: How to create a Generic Event Tag&lt;/h2>



&lt;div style="aspect-ratio: 1519 / 848;" class="figure nocaption">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2015/01/generic-event-tag.jpg" title="Generic Event Tag">
 
 &lt;img class="fig-img" height="848" width="1519" loading="lazy" src="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2015/01/generic-event-tag.jpg#ZgotmplZ" alt="Generic Event Tag">
 
 &lt;/a>
 
 
&lt;/div>


&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a &lt;strong>lot&lt;/strong> of containers that suffer from the same problem. They have many Event tags which only differ by the &lt;em>Event&lt;/em> that triggers them and/or by the tag fields of &lt;em>Event Category / Action / Label / Value&lt;/em>. There&amp;rsquo;s an easy way to reduce redundancy here. It&amp;rsquo;s the Generic Event Tag (you guessed it!).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>