<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>events on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in events on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 12:12:01 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Simple Custom Event Listeners With Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/simple-custom-event-listeners-gtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 12:12:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/simple-custom-event-listeners-gtm/</guid>
      <description>First of all, check out this article for an overview of how custom event listeners work in Google Tag Manager. The reason I&#39;m writing this #GTMTips article is that I want to upgrade the solution slightly, and I want to bring it back into the spotlight. Why? Because it&#39;s still one of the most effective ways to customize your Google Tag Manager implementation.
A custom event listener is a handler you write with JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMtips: Add The &#34;event&#34; Key To dataLayer Pushes</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/add-the-event-key-to-datalayer-pushes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 09:10:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/add-the-event-key-to-datalayer-pushes/</guid>
      <description>In Google Tag Manager, every single Tag requires a Trigger to fire. Every single Trigger requires an Event condition to activate. Sometimes, these Event conditions are obfuscated under template semantics, but you can also create a Custom Event Trigger, where you specify the value of the &amp;lsquo;event&amp;rsquo; key in dataLayer that fires your tag. You can read more about the relationship between GTM events and Tags in these two posts:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMtips: Create A Generic Event Tag</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/create-a-generic-event-tag/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 08:28:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/create-a-generic-event-tag/</guid>
      <description>With Google Tag Manager, there are a million different ways to make your tagging setup leaner and more flexible. The reason this should be a priority is because the UI isn&#39;t perfect. The more tags you have, the more difficult it becomes to manage your assets.
In this #GTMtips post, I show you one of my favorite ways to put your container on a diet.
Tip 13: How to create a Generic Event Tag   I&#39;ve seen a lot of containers that suffer from the same problem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>