<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>google cloud on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/google-cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in google cloud on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 07:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/google-cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Create A Cookie Rewrite Web Service Using The Google Cloud Platform</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/google-cloud/create-cookie-rewrite-web-service-google-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/google-cloud/create-cookie-rewrite-web-service-google-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Ah, Safari&amp;rsquo;s Intelligent Tracking Prevention - the gift that keeps on giving. Having almost milked this cow for all it&amp;rsquo;s worth, I was sure there would be little need to revisit the topic. Maybe, I thought, it would be better to just sit back and watch the world burn.
But then Mr. Charles Farina, a good friend and so amicable he&amp;rsquo;s practically Canadian, tempted me into testing out a quick proof-of-concept web service that would give us back our first party cookies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrape The URLs Of A Domain And Write The Results To BigQuery</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/google-cloud/scrape-domain-and-write-results-to-bigquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 11:14:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/google-cloud/scrape-domain-and-write-results-to-bigquery/</guid>
      <description>In my intense love affair with the Google Cloud Platform, I&amp;rsquo;ve never felt more inspired to write content and try things out. After starting with a Snowplow Analytics setup guide, and continuing with a Lighthouse audit automation tutorial, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you yet another cool thing you can do with GCP.
  In this guide, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to use an open-source web crawler running in a Google Compute Engine virtual machine (VM) instance to scrape all the internal and external links of a given domain, and write the results into a BigQuery table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audit Multiple Sites With Lighthouse And Write Results To BigQuery</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/google-cloud/lighthouse-bigquery-google-cloud-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 09:03:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/google-cloud/lighthouse-bigquery-google-cloud-platform/</guid>
      <description>Google Cloud Platform is very, very cool. It&amp;rsquo;s a fully capable, enterprise-grade, scalable cloud ecosystem which lets even total novices get started with building their first cloud applications. I wrote a long guide for installing Snowplow on the GCP, and you might want to read that if you want to see how you can build your own analytics tool using some nifty open-source modules.
But this guide will not be about Snowplow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Snowplow On The Google Cloud Platform</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/install-snowplow-on-the-google-cloud-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 07:00:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/install-snowplow-on-the-google-cloud-platform/</guid>
      <description>Last updated 18 Jan 2019: Added details about the free tier limitations, and showed how to avoid the Dataflow jobs auto-scaling out of control.
I&amp;rsquo;m (still) a huge fan of Snowplow Analytics. Their open-source, modular approach to DIY analytics pipelines has inspired me two write articles about them, and to host a meetup in Helsinki. In my previous Snowplow with Amazon Web Services guide, I walked you through setting up a Snowplow pipeline using Amazon Web Services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Site Search With Hugo &#43; App Engine &#43; Search API &#43; Python</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/web-development/static-site-search-google-app-engine-search-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 09:39:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/web-development/static-site-search-google-app-engine-search-api/</guid>
      <description>As the year changed to 2018, I decided to abandon WordPress, which I had been using for over 12 years as my content management system of choice. I had many reasons to do so, but the biggest motivators were the opportunity to try something new and to abandon the bloat and clutter of WordPress for a more simple, more elegant order of things. Spurred on by another adopter, Mark Edmondson, I decided to give Hugo a go (pun intended).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>