<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tag templates on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/tag-templates/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tag templates on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 16:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/tag-templates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Tests For Custom Templates In Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/writing-tests-for-custom-templates-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/writing-tests-for-custom-templates-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>Google Tag Manager introduced the capability to add tests to your Custom Templates. Tests, in this context, refer specifically to unit tests that you write in order to make sure your template code works in a predictable way. Unit tests are also used to drive development, ensuring that you have added contingencies for all the different scenarios that the template, when coupled with user input, might introduce.
  In this guide, I&amp;rsquo;ll introduce how the Tests feature works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Distributor Custom Tag Template For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/user-distributor-tag-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 10:12:19 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/user-distributor-tag-template/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed working with custom templates for Google Tag Manager. A lot. So much so that whenever the need to add some custom code to a container emerges, my first thought is how to turn that into a custom template.
Google has been forthcoming in introducing new APIs steadily, and I think the variety of things you can do with template is improving with every new API release.
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to use a simple tag template for distributing your users to groups, based on a random split.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Create Facebook Pixel Custom Tag Template</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/create-facebook-pixel-custom-tag-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 18:05:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/create-facebook-pixel-custom-tag-template/</guid>
      <description>After the recent release of Custom Templates for Google Tag Manager, my mind has been occupied by very little else. However, I have a nagging feeling that due to how involved the feature set is, there&amp;rsquo;s still a lot of demystifying that needs to take place before templates are fully embraced by the GTM user base.
In this article, I want to show you a concrete example of template creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Templates Guide For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/custom-templates-guide-for-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 18:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/custom-templates-guide-for-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>As I have finally managed to pick up my jaw from the floor, it&amp;rsquo;s now time to tell you what&amp;rsquo;s got me so excited. Google Tag Manager recently released a new feature called Custom Templates. Actually, it&amp;rsquo;s not fair to call it a feature. It&amp;rsquo;s a full-blown paradigm shift in how we use Google Tag Manager. It&amp;rsquo;s a suite of features designed to help brands, companies, and users create and share their own custom JavaScript and HTML setups with ease, while taking care that the code is optimized for delivery in the web browser.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>