<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>preview mode on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/preview-mode/</link>
    <description>Recent content in preview mode on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 11:14:20 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/preview-mode/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: The Mysterious .macro() Call In Custom HTML Tags</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/mysterious-macro-call-custom-html-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 11:14:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/mysterious-macro-call-custom-html-tags/</guid>
      <description>When previewing Custom HTML tags in Google Tag Manager you&amp;rsquo;ve almost certainly run into a situation where the GTM variable shows up as a weird JavaScript method resembling something like this:
google_tag_manager[&amp;quot;GTM-ABCD123&amp;quot;].macro(15)
And this is when you were expecting it to show the actual, resolved value!
It doesn&amp;rsquo;t help that every now and then the preview mode actually shows to correct value in the preview mode.
What&amp;rsquo;s up with that?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: The Errors Tab In Preview Mode</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/new-errors-tab-preview-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 01:01:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/new-errors-tab-preview-mode/</guid>
      <description>While using the Google Tag Manager user interface around Halloween 2018, you might have noticed a new tab in Google Tag Manager&amp;rsquo;s Preview mode. The tab is named Errors and shows you the number of exceptions thrown by GTM&amp;rsquo;s tag templates on the page. In this short #GTMTips post, I&amp;rsquo;ll quickly walk you through what the tab shows.
Tip 90: The Errors Tab In Preview Mode   The tab&amp;rsquo;s name is an apt description of what the tab shows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Prevent Clicks And Form Submits From Redirecting</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/prevent-clicks-and-form-submits-redirect/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 12:06:49 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/prevent-clicks-and-form-submits-redirect/</guid>
      <description>Google Tag Manager offers us some nice built-in triggers so that we can automatically listen for specific user interactions on the website, reacting to them however we wish, though typically it would be to fire a tag. The tricky thing especially with the click triggers and form submission tracking is that the page has a nasty habit of redirecting you to the link or form target page before letting you see the respective data in Google Tag Manager&amp;rsquo;s excellent preview mode.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>