<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Client Id on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/client-id/</link><description>Recent content in Client Id on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 07:04:01 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/client-id/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The FPID Cookie For Google Analytics In Server-side Tagging</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/fpid-cookie-google-analytics-server-side-tagging/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 07:04:01 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/fpid-cookie-google-analytics-server-side-tagging/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Last updated 27 April 2023 with details about preventing FPID access in cookieless scenarios.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>With &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">Server-side tagging&lt;/a>, the developer community has a chance to vastly improve the data collection capabilities of Google&amp;rsquo;s analytics platforms (&lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2790010">Universal Analytics&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/9306384">App+Web&lt;/a>). The ability to build &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/build-custom-universal-analytics-client-server-side-tagging/">our own templates&lt;/a> is particularly potent with a Server container.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, it&amp;rsquo;s not as if Google themselves are just sitting idly by and seeing what the community can come up with.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Add Client ID To Custom Dimension With gtag.js</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/add-clientid-to-custom-dimension-gtag-js/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 06:50:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/add-clientid-to-custom-dimension-gtag-js/</guid><description>&lt;p>When Google released &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/gtagjs/">gtag.js&lt;/a>, the new, global tracking library designed to (eventually) replace &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/">analytics.js&lt;/a>, many Universal Analytics practitioners and users were confused (see e.g. Jeff&amp;rsquo;s great overview &lt;a href="https://www.jeffalytics.com/google-gtag-js/">here&lt;/a>). It seemed like &lt;strong>gtag.js&lt;/strong> wasn&amp;rsquo;t really solving any immediate problem, since analytics.js had done a bang-up job with Universal Analytics tracking for all these years. However, &lt;strong>gtag&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/strong> modus operandi is the ability to leverage the same semantic information (distributed across &lt;code>dataLayer&lt;/code>!) across a number of Google products, starting with GA and AdWords.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Use customTask To Access Tracker Values In Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/use-customtask-access-tracker-values-google-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 08:27:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/use-customtask-access-tracker-values-google-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve recommended from the get-go is to &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/improve-data-collection-with-four-custom-dimensions/">always send the Client ID&lt;/a> to &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com">Google Analytics&lt;/a> with your users&amp;rsquo; hits. This is very useful for adding a level of granularity to your tracking. At first, I recommended using an Event tag to do this. Then I modified my approach a little so that you could send it with your initial &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/access-the-tracker-object-in-your-page-view-tag/">Page View&lt;/a> (thus not inflating your hit counts).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, Universal Analytics recently released a new &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/tasks">task API&lt;/a>, &lt;code>customTask&lt;/code>, which lets you access the model object mid-tag, thus letting you modify the payload that is dispatched to Google Analytics. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how this works by using the classic example of sending the Client ID to Google Analytics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Analytics Client ID In AMP Pages</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-analytics-client-id-amp-pages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 08:59:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-analytics-client-id-amp-pages/</guid><description>&lt;p>This article is a collaboration between Simo and &lt;a href="https://www.bounteous.com/insights/author/danwilkerson/">Dan Wilkerson&lt;/a>. Dan&amp;rsquo;s one of the smartest analytics developers out there, and he&amp;rsquo;s already contributed a great &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/using-document-write-safely-gtm-tags/">#GTMTips guest post&lt;/a>. It&amp;rsquo;s great to have him back here sharing his insight on working with &lt;a href="https://www.ampproject.org/">Accelerated Mobile Pages&lt;/a> (AMP).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, we&amp;rsquo;re back on AMP! Simo wrote a long, sprawling &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/accelerated-mobile-pages-via-google-tag-manager/">AMP for Google Tag Manager guide&lt;/a> a while ago, and Dan has also contributed to the space with his guide for &lt;a href="https://www.bounteous.com/insights/2015/12/08/google-analytics-using-amp/">AMP and Google Analytics&lt;/a>. Both of these guides touched upon a subject that might be one of the reasons to stay away from AMP for now: Client ID matching across AMP, your regular website, and any caches or CDNs that serve the AMP version.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Improve Data Collection With Four Custom Dimensions</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/improve-data-collection-with-four-custom-dimensions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 16:36:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/improve-data-collection-with-four-custom-dimensions/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since writing my rant about the &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/the-schema-conspiracy/">&lt;em>schema conspiracy&lt;/em>&lt;/a> of web analytics platforms, I&amp;rsquo;ve been giving the whole idea of hit-level data collection a lot of thought. Sessionization is very heavily implemented in &lt;a href="http://analytics.google.com">Google Analytics&lt;/a>, which is understandable, but the regular Google Analytics API just doesn&amp;rsquo;t give you the kind of information you&amp;rsquo;d need, if you wanted to stitch hits together differently in your own backend. In fact, there are &lt;strong>four&lt;/strong> distinct levels of aggregation that are not exposed via the API, even though I think they should:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>