<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cookies on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/cookies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cookies on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 11:49:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/cookies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cookie Settings And Subdomain Tracking In Universal Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/cookie-settings-and-subdomain-tracking-in-universal-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 11:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/cookie-settings-and-subdomain-tracking-in-universal-analytics/</guid>
      <description>Welcome back my friends (to the show that never ends)! It&amp;rsquo;s been a couple of weeks since my last barrage of articles, and I think the time is ripe to do some testing!
First things first, here&amp;rsquo;s a picture of me shovelling snow:
  And now back to the topic at hand.
One of the things that seems to be a hot topic in Universal Analytics is cross-domain tracking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Check For New User</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/check-for-new-user/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 11:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/check-for-new-user/</guid>
      <description>Every now and then we want to create a bridge between the stateful machines we send data to (e.g. Google Analytics), and the stateless environment where we collect the data itself (e.g. Google Tag Manager). This is not easy. There is no synergy between Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager which would let the latter understand anything about things like sessions or landing pages or Bounce Rates.
One thing we can reliably measure, however, is whether or not the visitor is a New User in Google Analytics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Ways To Persist Data Via Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/two-ways-to-persist-data-via-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 15:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/two-ways-to-persist-data-via-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>The web is stateless. It&amp;rsquo;s basically blind to your past, and it does a poor job of predicting what you might do in the future. When you browse to a website, the browser requests the page from the web server, and then proceeds to render it for you. This is a detached, clinical process, and any personalized or stateful data transfer is left to the sophistication of your web server.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>