<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mobile on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/mobile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mobile on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 09:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/mobile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Keep iOS And Android Firebase Containers In Sync</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/keep-ios-android-firebase-containers-sync/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/keep-ios-android-firebase-containers-sync/</guid>
      <description>With iOS and Android containers available for Google Tag Manager, it&#39;s tempting to add GTM as an integration into an existing Firebase setup for your apps. It&#39;s also a fine way to get acquainted with Firebase in the first place, as it has a plethora of features to make application development easier.
Furthermore, with the advent of App + Web, there&#39;s even more incentive to integrate your app with Firebase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Analytics For Mobile Apps Getting Shut Down</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-analytics-for-mobile-sunset/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 11:44:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-analytics-for-mobile-sunset/</guid>
      <description>If you&#39;re a user of the free version of Google Analytics, and if you have a free Google Analytics property collecting hits exclusively from the Google Analytics Services SDK (Android or iOS), you might have recently received an email that looks like this (emphasis mine):
  In a nutshell, Google is now starting the process of deprecating the &amp;ldquo;legacy&amp;rdquo; Google Analytics for Mobile Apps. This covers all data collection SDKs that do not have the word &amp;ldquo;Firebase&amp;rdquo; in them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated Mobile Pages Via Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/accelerated-mobile-pages-via-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 08:09:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/accelerated-mobile-pages-via-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>Google Tag Manager recently published support for Accelerated Mobile Pages (AMP). This support comes in the form of a new Container type in Google Tag Manager.
  When you create an AMP container in GTM, you are actually setting up an external configuration for AMP, which leverages AMP&#39;s own analytics module. As befits Google Tag Manager, creating the configuration is done in the familiar Google Tag Manager user interface, and you have (almost) all the tools of regular Google Tag Manager at your disposal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug Google Analytics On Your Mobile Browser</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/debug-google-analytics-on-your-mobile-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 17:43:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/debug-google-analytics-on-your-mobile-browser/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m currently at SMX München, which is still one of my favorite conferences in Europe. The quality of the talks is superb, and the organization is just perfect. So today, after my talk (joint session with the awesome Dave Sottimano), I was listening to the inimitable Mike King give an excellent presentation together with Ari Nahmani on technical skill prerequisites for all digital marketers today. Needless to say, I strongly agree with their view that digital marketing has always been a technical discipline, and the web is getting more and more complex each day that passes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup Google Tag Manager iOS With Swift</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/setup-google-tag-manager-ios-with-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 12:16:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/setup-google-tag-manager-ios-with-swift/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been meaning to write about Google Tag Manager for mobile apps for such a long time. Finally, I have some great use cases to share, as well as some useful examples for implementing GTM for iOS. That&#39;s right, this is an iOS guide, and, to be more specific, geared towards a successful Swift implementation.
  If you didn&#39;t know, Swift is a relatively new programming language, developed by Apple for iOS and OS X programming.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>