<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bigquery on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/bigquery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bigquery on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 07:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/bigquery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cookie Audit With Google BigQuery</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/google-cloud/cookie-audit-with-google-bigquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/google-cloud/cookie-audit-with-google-bigquery/</guid>
      <description>On New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve 2018, I published an article which instructed how to scrape pages of a site and write the results into Google BigQuery. I considered it to be a cool way to build your own web scraper, as it utilized the power and scale of the Google Cloud platform combined with the flexibility of a headless crawler built on top of Puppeteer.
In today&amp;rsquo;s article, I&amp;rsquo;m revisiting this solution in order to share with you its latest version, which includes a feature that you might find extremely useful when auditing the cookies that are dropped on your site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Optimize Anti-flicker Snippet Delay Test</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/optimize-anti-flicker-snippet-delay-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 12:43:16 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/optimize-anti-flicker-snippet-delay-test/</guid>
      <description>Recently I published an article on how to set up an impact test for the &amp;ldquo;flicker effect&amp;rdquo; omnipresent in client-side A/B-testing tools. Be sure to check out that article first to get some context to what we&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking about here.
  In this short follow-up, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to measure the average time of the anti-flicker snippet delaying page visibility, if you choose to deploy the snippet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#BigQueryTips: Query Guide To Google Analytics: App &#43; Web</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/bigquery-query-guide-google-analytics-app-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/bigquery-query-guide-google-analytics-app-web/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve thoroughly enjoyed writing short (and sometimes a bit longer) bite-sized tips for my #GTMTips topic. With the advent of Google Analytics: App + Web and particularly the opportunity to access raw data through BigQuery, I thought it was a good time to get started on a new tip topic: #BigQueryTips.
For Universal Analytics, getting access to the BigQuery export with Google Analytics 360 has been one of the major selling points for the expensive platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable BigQuery Export For Google Analytics: App &#43; Web Properties</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enable-bigquery-export-google-analytics-app-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 13:51:29 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enable-bigquery-export-google-analytics-app-web/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s yet another article inspired by the fairly recent release of Google Analytics: App + Web properties. This new property type surfaces Firebase&amp;rsquo;s analytics capabilities for websites as well, when before they were restricted to mobile apps only (see my guides for iOS and Android).
Even though the feature set of Google Analytics for Firebase is still somewhat bare in the user interface, here&amp;rsquo;s a perk which might push you over the edge and give the new measurement model a shot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Build A Google Tag Manager Monitor</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-monitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 11:49:15 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-monitor/</guid>
      <description>Google Tag Manager is strictly a tag delivery system, and it&amp;rsquo;s very careful not to collect any analytics data on its own. This is most likely a deliberate choice, because if GTM was to start collecting data, it would introduce additional barriers to adoption.
Nevertheless, being a tool that consolidates the design, development, deployment, and testing of all the marketing and analytics pixels, code snippets, and utilities running on a website or a mobile app, lacking the necessary features for auditing and monitoring has always seemed like an oversight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrape The URLs Of A Domain And Write The Results To BigQuery</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/google-cloud/scrape-domain-and-write-results-to-bigquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 11:14:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/google-cloud/scrape-domain-and-write-results-to-bigquery/</guid>
      <description>In my intense love affair with the Google Cloud Platform, I&amp;rsquo;ve never felt more inspired to write content and try things out. After starting with a Snowplow Analytics setup guide, and continuing with a Lighthouse audit automation tutorial, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you yet another cool thing you can do with GCP.
  In this guide, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to use an open-source web crawler running in a Google Compute Engine virtual machine (VM) instance to scrape all the internal and external links of a given domain, and write the results into a BigQuery table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audit Multiple Sites With Lighthouse And Write Results To BigQuery</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/google-cloud/lighthouse-bigquery-google-cloud-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 09:03:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/google-cloud/lighthouse-bigquery-google-cloud-platform/</guid>
      <description>Google Cloud Platform is very, very cool. It&amp;rsquo;s a fully capable, enterprise-grade, scalable cloud ecosystem which lets even total novices get started with building their first cloud applications. I wrote a long guide for installing Snowplow on the GCP, and you might want to read that if you want to see how you can build your own analytics tool using some nifty open-source modules.
But this guide will not be about Snowplow.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>