<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cookies on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/cookies/</link><description>Recent content in Cookies on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 07:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/cookies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Expiration Cap Removed From JavaScript Cookies In WebKit Browsers</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/privacy/first-party-cookies-webkit-revisited/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/privacy/first-party-cookies-webkit-revisited/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you recall, in February 2019, Apple published a post on the &lt;a href="https://webkit.org/blog/8613/intelligent-tracking-prevention-2-1/">WebKit blog&lt;/a>, which introduced version &lt;strong>2.1&lt;/strong> of their &lt;strong>Intelligent Tracking Prevention&lt;/strong> browser mechanism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this version, Safari (and soon &lt;strong>all&lt;/strong> WebKit browsers, including browser apps on iOS and iPadOS) placed an &lt;strong>expiration limit&lt;/strong> on browser cookies set with JavaScript. It was no longer possible to set the expiration date further than &lt;strong>7 days in the future&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a recent 2022 release (I don&amp;rsquo;t have the exact date or version number), WebKit has now modified this mechanism to &lt;strong>no longer set an expiration cap on JavaScript cookies&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What's In A CNAME</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/web-development/whats-in-a-cname/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/web-development/whats-in-a-cname/</guid><description>&lt;p>With the rise of &lt;strong>ad and content blockers&lt;/strong> (think &lt;a href="https://www.ghostery.com/">Ghostery&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/ublock-origin/cjpalhdlnbpafiamejdnhcphjbkeiagm?hl=fi">uBlock Origin&lt;/a>), as well as &lt;strong>browser tracking protections&lt;/strong> (see &lt;a href="https://www.cookiestatus.com/">www.cookiestatus.com&lt;/a>), marketing technology vendors have their work cut out for them. And when I refer to &lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;their work&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>, I mean they have to proactively identify and exploit any loopholes they can find to keep on collecting their precious data.&lt;/p>



&lt;div style="aspect-ratio: 3056 / 1198;" class="figure nocaption">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2020/06/whats-in-a-cname.jpg" title="What&amp;#39;s in a CNAME">
 
 &lt;img class="fig-img" height="1198" width="3056" loading="lazy" src="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2020/06/whats-in-a-cname.jpg#ZgotmplZ" alt="What&amp;#39;s in a CNAME">
 
 &lt;/a>
 
 
&lt;/div>


&lt;p>In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll take a look at one such exploit vector, the Canonical Name (&lt;code>CNAME&lt;/code>) DNS record, in particular.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cookie Audit With Google BigQuery</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/google-cloud/cookie-audit-with-google-bigquery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/google-cloud/cookie-audit-with-google-bigquery/</guid><description>&lt;p>On New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve 2018, I published an article which instructed &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/google-cloud/scrape-domain-and-write-results-to-bigquery/">how to scrape pages of a site and write the results into Google BigQuery&lt;/a>. I considered it to be a cool way to build your own web scraper, as it utilized the power and scale of the Google Cloud platform combined with the flexibility of a &lt;a href="https://github.com/yujiosaka/headless-chrome-crawler">headless crawler&lt;/a> built on top of &lt;a href="https://github.com/puppeteer/puppeteer">Puppeteer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In today&amp;rsquo;s article, I&amp;rsquo;m revisiting this solution in order to share with you its latest version, which includes a feature that you might find extremely useful when &lt;a href="https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-pecr/guidance-on-the-use-of-cookies-and-similar-technologies/how-do-we-comply-with-the-cookie-rules/">auditing the cookies&lt;/a> that are dropped on your site.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Chrome Samesite Warnings For Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/chrome-samesite-warnings-google-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 14:00:02 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/chrome-samesite-warnings-google-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update 17 February 2020&lt;/strong>: Google Tag Manager&amp;rsquo;s Preview mode cookies &lt;em>have&lt;/em> been updated with the necessary flags, so they will not break once SameSite enforcement begins.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;ve opened the &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/web/tools/chrome-devtools/console">browser console&lt;/a> in Google Chrome (since &lt;a href="https://blog.chromium.org/2019/05/improving-privacy-and-security-on-web.html">Chrome 76&lt;/a>), you might have seen a bunch of warnings in a yellow background related to something called a &lt;code>SameSite&lt;/code> cookie attribute that is either missing or incompletely set for cookies set on external domains. If you use Google Tag Manager, especially in Preview mode, you might have seen a warning about the &lt;code>http(s)://www.googletagmanager.com&lt;/code> domain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cookie Settings And Subdomain Tracking In Universal Analytics</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/cookie-settings-and-subdomain-tracking-in-universal-analytics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 11:49:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/cookie-settings-and-subdomain-tracking-in-universal-analytics/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome back my friends (to the show that never ends)! It&amp;rsquo;s been a couple of weeks since my last barrage of articles, and I think the time is ripe to do some &lt;strong>testing&lt;/strong>!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First things first, here&amp;rsquo;s a picture of me shovelling snow:&lt;/p>



&lt;div style="aspect-ratio: 960 / 720;" class="figure nocaption">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2016/01/simo.jpg" title="Shovelling snow">
 
 &lt;img class="fig-img" height="720" width="960" loading="lazy" src="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2016/01/simo.jpg#ZgotmplZ" alt="Shovelling snow">
 
 &lt;/a>
 
 
&lt;/div>


&lt;p>And now back to the topic at hand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the things that seems to be a hot topic in Universal Analytics is cross-domain tracking. I&amp;rsquo;ve never really tackled the beast head-on, since there&amp;rsquo;s such a wealth of &lt;a href="https://www.bounteous.com/search_gcse/?q=cross-domain">excellent articles&lt;/a> about it out there. However, I have taken a plunge into the deep end with some specific stuff, such as &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/iframe-cross-domain-tracking-in-google-tag-manager/">iframe&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/cross-domain-tracking-across-subdomains/">subdomain&lt;/a> tracking.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Check For New User</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/check-for-new-user/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 11:13:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/check-for-new-user/</guid><description>&lt;p>Every now and then we want to create a bridge between the stateful machines we send data to (e.g. &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com/">Google Analytics&lt;/a>), and the stateless environment where we collect the data itself (e.g. &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>). This &lt;em>is not easy&lt;/em>. There is no synergy between Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager which would let the latter understand anything about things like &lt;em>sessions&lt;/em> or &lt;em>landing pages&lt;/em> or &lt;em>Bounce Rates&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing we can reliably measure, however, is whether or not the visitor is a &lt;strong>New User&lt;/strong> in Google Analytics. This is done by checking whether or not the Universal Analytics cookie &lt;code>_ga&lt;/code> exists in the user&amp;rsquo;s browser when they enter the site. Naturally, this check needs to happen before the Universal Analytics Tag has time to create the cookie, which is the only difficult thing to solve here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Two Ways To Persist Data Via Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/two-ways-to-persist-data-via-google-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 15:30:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/two-ways-to-persist-data-via-google-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>The web is stateless. It&amp;rsquo;s basically blind to your past, and it does a poor job of predicting what you might do in the future. When you browse to a website, the browser requests the page from the web server, and then proceeds to render it for you. This is a detached, clinical process, and any &lt;em>personalized&lt;/em> or &lt;em>stateful&lt;/em> data transfer is left to the sophistication of your web server.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>