<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personal on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/personal/</link><description>Recent content in Personal on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 07:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Thank You</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/personal/thank-you/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/personal/thank-you/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today marks the date of exactly &lt;strong>10 years of marriage&lt;/strong> to my wife, my friend, the loving mother to our children, and my business partner at &lt;a href="https://www.teamsimmer.com/">Simmer&lt;/a>. And yes, they are all the same person – I&amp;rsquo;m that lucky!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thank you, &lt;strong>Mari&lt;/strong>, for everything.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Just Breathe</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/personal/just-breathe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/personal/just-breathe/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Content warning: introspection, parenthood, &amp;ldquo;Floating Butt&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When Benjamin (our first child) was born, my life as an individual was unraveled.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With every bellow from the newborn&amp;rsquo;s lungs, I could feel my personal agency slipping away from me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From that magical moment onwards, I&amp;rsquo;ve been gripped by the polarizing emotions of parenthood.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At any given time, I&amp;rsquo;m galvanized by fear for the well-being of my children, or existentially deadlocked by the calamities of all the possible (terrible) futures for this planet, or (figuratively) high from the amazing content and purpose my children bring to my life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>10 Truths About Data - Revisited</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/10-truths-about-data-revisited/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 20:37:05 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/10-truths-about-data-revisited/</guid><description>&lt;p>Seven years ago, I wrote on my former employer&amp;rsquo;s (the amazing &lt;a href="https://www.reaktor.com/">Reaktor&lt;/a>) blog a tongue-in-the-cheek article titled &lt;a href="https://www.reaktor.com/blog/10-truths-about-data/">10 Truths About Data&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Looking back on it today, I&amp;rsquo;m still proud of the handiwork, but I can&amp;rsquo;t help but think that some of the truths were wasted just to reach the magic number 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, today, I want to revisit these truths and provide a rehashed version for you, my dear reader.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>You might cynically think that this article is just a way for me to prevent having the first month in this blog&amp;rsquo;s history with no new articles published. And you would be partially right.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>100th Post: Big Changes</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/personal/100th-post-big-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 06:23:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/personal/100th-post-big-changes/</guid><description>&lt;p>A year ago, I wrote a &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/personal/year-in-review-2013-2014/">Year In Review&lt;/a> post for one of the craziest 365 days of my life, both personally (got married), and professionally (started at NetBooster, and toured the world talking about &lt;a href="http://analytics.google.com">Google Analytics&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://tagmanager.google.com">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>). Now it&amp;rsquo;s time for another recap, and the chance to announce a big change in the Simoverse.&lt;/p>


 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/images/2015/04/google.jpg" title="Simo and Mari at Google">
 
 &lt;amp-img src="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/images/2015/04/google.jpg" layout="responsive" alt="Simo and Mari at Google" height="264" width="713">&lt;/amp-img>
 
 &lt;/a>
 

&lt;p>No, I will not be joining Google (made you think so!).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Year In Review 2013-2014</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/personal/year-in-review-2013-2014/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 08:34:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/personal/year-in-review-2013-2014/</guid><description>&lt;p>&amp;hellip;or How My Organic Traffic Went Through The Roof.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been one of the craziest 365 days in my life, and I thought it would be apt to write a bit about all the stuff that&amp;rsquo;s taken place. I haven&amp;rsquo;t really been talking about myself in my guides and other previous posts, so please indulge me, for once!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-beginning">The beginning&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A year ago I had just quit my job at my previous employer, &lt;a href="http://www.innofactor.com">Innofactor Plc&lt;/a>. When I quit, I&amp;rsquo;d been working as a product owner for Microsoft SharePoint CMS (content management system) components, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really seeing any future in it. To be honest, I still don&amp;rsquo;t think &amp;ldquo;Microsoft SharePoint&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;CMS&amp;rdquo; should ever be uttered in the same sentence, but Innofactor did do some pretty cool stuff that made the relationship between the two a bit smoother.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>