<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>google ads on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/google-ads/</link>
    <description>Recent content in google ads on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 07:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/google-ads/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Mistakes When Working With Click Identifiers</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/common-mistakes-click-identifiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/common-mistakes-click-identifiers/</guid>
      <description>This is a guest post by Jude Nwachukwu Onyejekwe. He is a prolific content creator, and he curates the DumbData portal, which is full of great, free resources for measurement enthusiasts.
In this article, he shares some useful learnings for working with click identifiers.
Click IDs are URL parameters used by ad platforms. They are attached to outgoing links (ad clicks), so that when the user lands on a website, the URL would include this identifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Google Ads Remarketing In GTM Server Containers</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/google-ads-remarketing-gtm-server-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 07:22:22 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/google-ads-remarketing-gtm-server-containers/</guid>
      <description>Google has released the Google Ads Remarketing tag for server-side tagging in Google Tag Manager.
Functionally, it&amp;rsquo;s remarkably similar to the Conversion Tracking tag they released previously. In fact, you should go ahead and read that article first, so that you have an understanding of how Google Ads tracking works through Server containers!
Follow this link to read the official documentation.
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through how to set things up, and I&amp;rsquo;ll also provide an overview of how it works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Ads Conversion Tracking With Server-side Tagging In Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-ads-server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-ads-server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>One of the biggest blockers for Google Tag Manager&amp;rsquo;s server-side tagging to slip out of beta is Google Ads. Until server-side tagging supports a solution for both conversions and remarketing capabilities to be reproduced server-side, it&amp;rsquo;s unlikely that Server containers will lose their beta label.
  While I can&amp;rsquo;t say what will happen to the beta label now, the fact is that Google Tag Manager has now released support for Conversion tracking using server-side tagging.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>