<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 07:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts On Education</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/personal/thoughts-on-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/personal/thoughts-on-education/</guid>
      <description>As my LinkedIn inbox graciously reminded me that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on Simmer for a full three years now, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share a couple of observations about education – particularly in the world of technical digital marketing.
Online courses are an interesting vehicle for education. The medium offers a plethora of different approaches to knowledge transfer, student assessment, and collaboration. It seems like a no-brainer in today&amp;rsquo;s day and age, particularly for someone who wants to build a platform that scales beyond in-person tuition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank You</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/personal/thank-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/personal/thank-you/</guid>
      <description>Today marks the date of exactly 10 years of marriage to my wife, my friend, the loving mother to our children, and my business partner at Simmer. And yes, they are all the same person – I&amp;rsquo;m that lucky!
Thank you, Mari, for everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Breathe</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/personal/just-breathe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/personal/just-breathe/</guid>
      <description>Content warning: introspection, parenthood, &amp;ldquo;Floating Butt&amp;rdquo;.
When Benjamin (our first child) was born, my life as an individual was unraveled.
With every bellow from the newborn&amp;rsquo;s lungs, I could feel my personal agency slipping away from me.
From that magical moment onwards, I&amp;rsquo;ve been gripped by the polarizing emotions of parenthood.
At any given time, I&amp;rsquo;m galvanized by fear for the well-being of my children, or existentially deadlocked by the calamities of all the possible (terrible) futures for this planet, or (figuratively) high from the amazing content and purpose my children bring to my life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simmer Is Live</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/personal/simmer-is-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/personal/simmer-is-live/</guid>
      <description>This will likely be the shortest blog article I have ever written, but I have just one short thing to say:
SIMMER IS LIVE!
Simmer is a new online course platform, where we bring technical marketing courses to your computer (or mobile device) screen with a straightforward, task-based approach.
Our first class is aptly Server-side Tagging In Google Tag Manager, and it is open for enrollment right now, all the way until March 14th.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Public Speaking</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/on-public-speaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 09:21:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/on-public-speaking/</guid>
      <description>Speaking in front of an audience can be downright intimidating.
As a speaker, you are offering yourself for unsolicited feedback and criticism, you will most likely be ridiculed for the vacuity of your arguments, and you will be berated for your rhetoric or told exactly what you did wrong and why, when all you want is to have a cup of coffee, wind down, and enjoy the rest of the event in a good mood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100th Post: Big Changes</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/personal/100th-post-big-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 06:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/personal/100th-post-big-changes/</guid>
      <description>A year ago, I wrote a Year In Review post for one of the craziest 365 days of my life, both personally (got married), and professionally (started at NetBooster, and toured the world talking about Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager). Now it&amp;rsquo;s time for another recap, and the chance to announce a big change in the Simoverse.
  No, I will not be joining Google (made you think so!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year In Review 2013-2014</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/personal/year-in-review-2013-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 08:34:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/personal/year-in-review-2013-2014/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip;or How My Organic Traffic Went Through The Roof.
It&amp;rsquo;s been one of the craziest 365 days in my life, and I thought it would be apt to write a bit about all the stuff that&amp;rsquo;s taken place. I haven&amp;rsquo;t really been talking about myself in my guides and other previous posts, so please indulge me, for once!
The beginning A year ago I had just quit my job at my previous employer, Innofactor Plc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>