<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Analytics on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/analytics/</link><description>Recent content in Analytics on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 10:52:16 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ITP 2.1 And Web Analytics</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/itp-2-1-and-web-analytics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 10:52:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/itp-2-1-and-web-analytics/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Updated 1 October 2019&lt;/strong> With &lt;a href="https://webkit.org/blog/9521/intelligent-tracking-prevention-2-3/">ITP 2.3&lt;/a> it looks like Safari is reducing the usefulness of &lt;code>localStorage&lt;/code> as well, so using that as an alternative fix to persistence issues should not be considered future-proof. this solution should &lt;strong>not&lt;/strong> be considered future-proof.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Updated &lt;strong>12 March 2019&lt;/strong> with some minor clarifications..&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>On 21st February 2019, &lt;a href="https://webkit.org/">WebKit&lt;/a> announced the release of the latest iteration of Safari&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Intelligent Tracking Prevention&lt;/strong> (ITP), known as &lt;a href="https://webkit.org/blog/8613/intelligent-tracking-prevention-2-1/">ITP 2.1&lt;/a>. For a while now, Safari has been targeting cross-site tracking with ITP, first starting with &lt;a href="https://webkit.org/blog/7675/intelligent-tracking-prevention/">cookies in third-party contexts&lt;/a>, then &lt;a href="https://webkit.org/blog/8311/intelligent-tracking-prevention-2-0/">tightening the noose&lt;/a> after a number of workarounds emerged, and finally with the latest iteration targeting cookies that were moved from a third-party context to a first-party context.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Definition Of Success</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/definition-of-success/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 08:00:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/definition-of-success/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.google.fi/search?q=%22agile+analytics%22">&lt;em>Agile analytics&lt;/em>&lt;/a> isn&amp;rsquo;t a novel concept in any shape or form. Things like &lt;a href="https://www.infoq.com/news/2011/03/agile-feedback-loops">feedback loops&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/from-project-to-process/">process-oriented development&lt;/a> seem to integrate flawlessly into the analytics paradigm, at least on paper. Heck, there&amp;rsquo;s even the &lt;a href="https://www.mindtools.com/pages/article/build-measure-learn.htm">Build-&lt;strong>Measure&lt;/strong>-Learn&lt;/a> framework for continuous development. It would be difficult to argue that analytics doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a role in something with &lt;em>measure&lt;/em> in the name!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, past three years of working at &lt;a href="https://www.reaktor.com/">Reaktor&lt;/a>, one of the world&amp;rsquo;s top agile technology houses, have introduced me to a whole new set of problems with integrating an &amp;ldquo;analytics mindset&amp;rdquo; into an agile workflow, or an &amp;ldquo;agile mindset&amp;rdquo; into the analytics process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>From Project To Process</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/from-project-to-process/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 11:33:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/from-project-to-process/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year I had the opportunity to present at &lt;a href="http://emetrics-summit.co.uk/london2015/">eMetrics London&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://emetrics-summit.de/berlin2015/">Berlin&lt;/a> on a topic that is very close to my heart. I&amp;rsquo;m psychotically neurotic about &lt;strong>data quality&lt;/strong>. I&amp;rsquo;ve written about it &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/data-is-difficult/">many&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/the-schema-conspiracy/">times&lt;/a> before, and it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much why I want to keep on blogging and writing about analytics and tag management customizations. At eMetrics, I stepped out of my comfort zone of development and implementation, and chose to talk about organization practices.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Context Is King: Measure Everything!</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/context-king-measure-everything/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/context-king-measure-everything/</guid><description>&lt;p>Have you ever stopped to think about what the chain of events was that led you to a particular decision? Maybe not, but in web analytics it is something that should be considered. After all, there is something counter-intuitive about analytics tools such as &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/">Google Analytics&lt;/a>, which require us to think in terms of &lt;strong>clicks&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>recorded events&lt;/strong> that occur &lt;em>on the website, during the visit&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thankfully, we have evolved as a species, and we no longer place too much emphasis on &lt;strong>last click attribution&lt;/strong>. In short, last click attribution is a model where success of a particular goal is attributed to the conditions underlying the active session. So if a person visits a page via bookmark and downloads a PDF file on that page, the direct visit channel (which covers, by default, bookmarked visits) is the &lt;strong>only&lt;/strong> one which receives the kudos for the file download. Nothing is attributed to other channels, which might have exposed the user to the brand, the product, and the file itself. Ridiculous, right? &lt;a href="https://www.portent.com/blog/analytics/rip-last-click-attribution.htm">R.I.P. last click attribution&lt;/a>!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How To (Not) Make A Splash</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/web-design/how-to-not-make-a-splash/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 19:36:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/web-design/how-to-not-make-a-splash/</guid><description>&lt;p>A word of warning. This is not a developers&amp;rsquo; post, a guide, or a thought experiment. This is a bona fide rant. Sometimes we just need to vent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A couple of weeks ago, I checked one of our (inactive) client&amp;rsquo;s Google Analytics accounts I still had access to. What I saw in the acquisition report was this:&lt;/p>



&lt;div style="aspect-ratio: 957 / 221;" class="figure nocaption">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2013/12/splash-page-organic-direct.jpg" title="Splash page affect on Google Analytics">
 
 &lt;img class="fig-img" height="221" width="957" loading="lazy" src="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2013/12/splash-page-organic-direct.jpg#ZgotmplZ" alt="Splash page affect on Google Analytics">
 
 &lt;/a>
 
 
&lt;/div>


&lt;p>See how direct traffic gobbles up a great big share of organic traffic in late October?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>