<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>google analytics on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/google-analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in google analytics on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 09:00:29 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/google-analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Parameter Reporting In Google Analytics: App &#43; Web</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/custom-parameter-reporting-google-analytics-app-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 09:00:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/custom-parameter-reporting-google-analytics-app-web/</guid>
      <description>In Google Analytics: App + Web, you collect events. One event differs from another event by the name it uses. An event with the name page_view is different from, say, an event with the name file_download.
This is all run-of-the-mill stuff. You know this.
However, the fundamental change that App + Web introduces, when compared to Universal Analytics, is how event parameters are collected and processed.
  This gets more complicated than it should be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculate Readability Scores For Content</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/calculate-readability-scores-for-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 09:00:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/calculate-readability-scores-for-content/</guid>
      <description>There are lots of different readability formulas out there, which seek to provide an index on how readable any given excerpt of text is. Typically, these formulas output a grade-level score, which indicates, roughly, the level of education required to read the text excerpt with ease.
Any &amp;ldquo;quality index&amp;rdquo; that seeks to reduce the complexity of something as multi-faceted as reading should be subject to scrutiny. This is true for Bounce Rate, this is true for Time On Page, and this is true for a readability score.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve Google Analytics Bot Detection With reCAPTCHA</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/improve-google-analytics-bot-detection-with-recaptcha/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 09:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/improve-google-analytics-bot-detection-with-recaptcha/</guid>
      <description>There are thousands upon thousands of bots, crawlers, spiders, and other creepy-crawlies out there doing nothing but crawling through websites and harvesting the content within for whatever purposes they have been fine-tuned to. While Google Analytics provides a bot filtering feature to filter out &amp;ldquo;spam&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;bot traffic&amp;rdquo; from views, this is far from comprehensive enough to tackle all instances of bot traffic that might enter the site.
  You might have noticed bot traffic in your data even if you have bot filtering toggled on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable BigQuery Export For Google Analytics: App &#43; Web Properties</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enable-bigquery-export-google-analytics-app-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 13:51:29 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enable-bigquery-export-google-analytics-app-web/</guid>
      <description>Here&#39;s yet another article inspired by the fairly recent release of Google Analytics: App + Web properties. This new property type surfaces Firebase&#39;s analytics capabilities for websites as well, when before they were restricted to mobile apps only (see my guides for iOS and Android).
Even though the feature set of Google Analytics for Firebase is still somewhat bare in the user interface, here&#39;s a perk which might push you over the edge and give the new measurement model a shot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create A Cookie Rewrite Web Service Using The Google Cloud Platform</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/google-cloud/create-cookie-rewrite-web-service-google-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/google-cloud/create-cookie-rewrite-web-service-google-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Ah, Safari&#39;s Intelligent Tracking Prevention - the gift that keeps on giving. Having almost milked this cow for all it&#39;s worth, I was sure there would be little need to revisit the topic. Maybe, I thought, it would be better to just sit back and watch the world burn.
But then Mr. Charles Farina, a good friend and so amicable he&#39;s practically Canadian, tempted me into testing out a quick proof-of-concept web service that would give us back our first party cookies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Send Event Hits Before Pageview Hits In Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/send-event-before-pageview-in-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 09:23:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/send-event-before-pageview-in-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>One of the myths surrounding Google Analytics is that the first hit of a session should always be a pageview. It makes sense - sessions are initialized with a landing page, and thus need a page view to have one.
  However, in this article I want to show you empirically how this myth is just that - a myth.
There is little discernible impact if the first hit of a session is an event, and GA is more than capable of stitching the first event together with the subsequent pageview into a session entity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obfuscate And Duplicate Google Analytics Data</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/obfuscate-and-duplicate-google-analytics-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 11:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/obfuscate-and-duplicate-google-analytics-data/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps you didn&#39;t know this, but there&#39;s a really handy demo account for Google Analytics you can use to check out how Google Analytics works in a real business context (the data is from the Google Merchandise Store). However, you can access the account with nothing more than read-only access. This is annoying if you wanted to customize the setup.
Worry not, I have a solution for you! Harnessing the awesome power of customTask, you can create a duplicate of the data collected on any website where you can modify the tracking (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Unset A User-scoped Custom Dimension In Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/how-to-unset-a-user-scoped-custom-dimension-in-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 10:20:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/how-to-unset-a-user-scoped-custom-dimension-in-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>Scope in Google Analytics&amp;rsquo; Custom Dimensions refers to how the value in the Custom Dimension is extended to all hits in the same scope.
Hit- and product-scoped Custom Dimensions apply to the given hit alone - they are not extended to any other hits in the session or by the same user.
Session-scoped Custom Dimensions apply the last value sent during the session to all the hits in that session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Analytics For Mobile Apps Getting Shut Down</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-analytics-for-mobile-sunset/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 11:44:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-analytics-for-mobile-sunset/</guid>
      <description>If you&#39;re a user of the free version of Google Analytics, and if you have a free Google Analytics property collecting hits exclusively from the Google Analytics Services SDK (Android or iOS), you might have recently received an email that looks like this (emphasis mine):
  In a nutshell, Google is now starting the process of deprecating the &amp;ldquo;legacy&amp;rdquo; Google Analytics for Mobile Apps. This covers all data collection SDKs that do not have the word &amp;ldquo;Firebase&amp;rdquo; in them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create And Update Google Analytics Session Timeout Cookie</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/create-and-update-google-analytics-session-timeout-cookie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 11:49:23 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/create-and-update-google-analytics-session-timeout-cookie/</guid>
      <description>In Google Analytics, the concept of a session is the key aggregation unit of all the data you work with. It&#39;s so central to all the key metrics you use (Conversion Rate, Bounce Rate, Session Duration, Landing Page), and yet there&#39;s an underlying complexity that I&#39;m pretty certain is unrecognized by many of GA&#39;s users. And yet, since this idea of a session is so focal to GA (to the point of being overbearing), it&#39;s annoying that the browser isn&#39;t privy to any of the sessionization parameters that Google Analytics applies to the hits sent from the browser to its servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically Reduce Google Analytics Payload Length</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/automatically-reduce-google-analytics-payload-length/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 11:04:14 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/automatically-reduce-google-analytics-payload-length/</guid>
      <description>Here we are, reunited with customTask. This time, we&#39;ll put this wonderful mechanism to work for a very, very good cause. One of the lesser known &amp;ldquo;features&amp;rdquo; of Google Analytics is that when the payload size (the request body that is actually sent to Google Analytics with each request) goes past a certain limit, specifically 8192 bytes, the hit is aborted without warning. This can come as a surprise, because there&#39;s no indication anywhere in Google Analytics that you are missing hits because of this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Allow And Block Advertising Features In Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/allow-block-advertising-features-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 15:16:55 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/allow-block-advertising-features-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>After writing yet another customTask article on how to respect client-side opt-out using Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager, the analytics.js core library was enhanced with a new field that makes it all a lot easier to do. The field, allowAdFeatures, lets you either allow or block the request to DoubleClick that is initiated when Advertising Features have been enabled.
In this very short article, I&#39;ll quickly show you what the field does and why it&#39;s useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13 Useful Custom Dimensions For Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/13-useful-custom-dimensions-for-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 11:08:09 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/13-useful-custom-dimensions-for-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite (and most popular) articles in my blog is Improve Data Collection With Four Custom Dimensions. In that article, I show how you can improve the quality and granularity of your Google Analytics data set with just four Custom Dimensions. The reason I chose the four dimensions (Hit Timestamp, Session ID, Client ID, and User ID) is because I firmly believe that they should be in Google Analytics&amp;rsquo; standard set of dimensions, but for some inexplicable reason they aren&#39;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track Browsing Behavior In Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-browsing-behavior-in-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-browsing-behavior-in-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>Last updated 22 May 2019: Added expiration of currently open tabs.
 In this article, Jethro Nederhof of Snowflake Analytics fame and I will introduce you to some pretty neat web browser APIs. The purpose of these APIs is to find out more about how the user navigated to the current page, and what&#39;s going on with their browser tabs.
  There are so many things you can do with this new information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Send Google Analytics Payload Length As Custom Dimension</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/send-google-analytics-payload-length-as-custom-dimension/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 10:02:51 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/send-google-analytics-payload-length-as-custom-dimension/</guid>
      <description>Maybe you knew this, maybe you didn&#39;t, but requests sent from your website (or app) to Google Analytics have a maximum size. Or, more specifically, the payload size (meaning the actual content body of the request) has a maximum.
This maximum size of the payload is 8192 bytes. This means, basically, that the entire parameter string sent to Google Analytics servers can be no longer than 8192 characters in length. The thing is, if the payload exceeds this, Google Analytics simply drops the hit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>customTask - The Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/customtask-the-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 07:15:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/customtask-the-guide/</guid>
      <description>Last updated 4 September 2018
If you have been reading my blog articles over the past year, you might have noticed a disturbing trend. I&#39;ve published 9 articles on customTask since the API was released. It might not sound like much, but I can&#39;t think of a single feature in Google Analytics or Google Tag Manager that has so completely convinced me of its usefulness in such a short time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Edit Google Analytics Tag Settings</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/edit-google-analytics-tag-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 08:39:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/edit-google-analytics-tag-settings/</guid>
      <description>When the Google Analytics Settings variable was introduced in May 2017, it resulted in a significant change in the Google Analytics tag user interface in Google Tag Manager. The default UI for editing a tag was stripped down of all GA-specific settings, and the new Google Analytics Settings drop-down was the replacement.
Unfortunately, the bulk of Google Tag Manager articles online (including those on this blog) still refer to the old interface in screenshots and instructions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Opt-out Of Google Analytics Tracking</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/opt-out-of-google-analytics-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 16:17:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/opt-out-of-google-analytics-tracking/</guid>
      <description>A while ago I posted a #GTMTips post where I detailed the steps you can take to opt-out of all Google Analytics tracking and the DoubleClick redirects that often follow. It was a fun exercise, but because it relies on preventing requests on a tag-by-tag basis (using the ubiquituous customTask), it can be a chore to handle in large containers.
In this article, we&#39;ll continue with the theme of opting out from Google Analytics tracking by leveraging a solution provided by the tool itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Send Event And Custom Dimension If Google Optimize Experiment Is Running</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/send-event-custom-dimension-google-optimize-experiment-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 14:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/send-event-custom-dimension-google-optimize-experiment-running/</guid>
      <description>I really like Google Optimize. It has a fairly intuitive UI, setting up experiments is easy, and there&#39;s integrations for both Google Tag Manager and Google Analytics built into the system. It&#39;s still a JavaScript-based, client-side A/B-testing tool, so problems with flicker and asynchronous loading are ever-present (though this is somewhat mitigated by the page-hiding snippet).
One issue with the Google Analytics integration is the difficulty of creating segments for sessions where the users were actively participating in the experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track Users Who Are Offline In Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-users-who-are-offline-in-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 08:19:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-users-who-are-offline-in-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>The steady increase in mobile use over the last years has introduced some new challenges for web analytics. It&#39;s not just about mismatches in the tracking model (the concept of sessions is even more absurd for apps than it is for desktop browsing), but about something more fundamental, more basic. Think about it: if a visitor visits the website using a mobile device, there&#39;s a significant chance of them losing internet connectivity and going unintentionally offline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two New Unofficial GA Add-ons For Google Sheets</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/two-new-unofficial-ga-add-ons-for-google-sheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 09:26:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/two-new-unofficial-ga-add-ons-for-google-sheets/</guid>
      <description>More often than not, much of what we do in web analytics can be automated. This applies especially to implementations, audits, configurations, and reporting. So when I&#39;m faced with a menial, manual task that might take hours for me to complete if done by hand, I always look at what could be done with some scripting and API work. I want to introduce a couple of Google Sheets add-ons I&#39;ve written and released to the public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track Autocomplete Search In Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-autocomplete-search-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 07:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-autocomplete-search-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>Autocomplete search is a tricky thing to track. The underlying logic is that when the user starts feeding characters into a search form, the search suggests results based on a limited input. If the user is not satisfied with the results, they can continue adding characters to the search, thus increasing the accuracy. Often there&#39;s also the option to revert to a regular search with what they&#39;ve already written. Tracking this logic in tools like Google Analytics is difficult, because there&#39;s really no way to know if the search was successful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Cross-domain Tracking With Multiple GA Trackers</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/cross-domain-tracking-with-multiple-ga-trackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 15:15:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/cross-domain-tracking-with-multiple-ga-trackers/</guid>
      <description>To be fair, this tip isn&#39;t just for Google Tag Manager but for regular old on-page Google Analytics as well. It&#39;s one of those little things that&#39;s corroding your data quality without you ever realizing it. Namely, this tip is about how to handle cross-domain tracking in situations where you are sending data to multiple Google Analytics properties on the same page.
It&#39;s a very typical scenario - you have a &amp;ldquo;local&amp;rdquo; property, which tracks only the traffic of the current site, and then a &amp;ldquo;rollup&amp;rdquo; property, where you send data from all your organization&#39;s websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Log Failed Google Analytics Requests In Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/log-failed-google-analytics-requests-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 13:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/log-failed-google-analytics-requests-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>READ THIS (26 Aug 2019)!! Unfortunately, the update I made in 2016 contained code that was incomplete and broken. I nevert noticed this until it was pointed out to me almost three years later. At this point, I don&#39;t have a working backup of the solution, so unless some internet archive / cache service manages to surface the code, this article is basically lost.
 UPDATE 20 December 2016: I made some fixes to the solution - be sure to grab the latest code snippet from below!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Analytics Client ID In AMP Pages</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-analytics-client-id-amp-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 08:59:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-analytics-client-id-amp-pages/</guid>
      <description>This article is a collaboration between Simo and Dan Wilkerson. Dan&#39;s one of the smartest analytics developers out there, and he&#39;s already contributed a great #GTMTips guest post. It&#39;s great to have him back here sharing his insight on working with Accelerated Mobile Pages (AMP).
So, we&#39;re back on AMP! Simo wrote a long, sprawling AMP for Google Tag Manager guide a while ago, and Dan has also contributed to the space with his guide for AMP and Google Analytics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated Mobile Pages Via Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/accelerated-mobile-pages-via-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 08:09:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/accelerated-mobile-pages-via-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>Google Tag Manager recently published support for Accelerated Mobile Pages (AMP). This support comes in the form of a new Container type in Google Tag Manager.
  When you create an AMP container in GTM, you are actually setting up an external configuration for AMP, which leverages AMP&#39;s own analytics module. As befits Google Tag Manager, creating the configuration is done in the familiar Google Tag Manager user interface, and you have (almost) all the tools of regular Google Tag Manager at your disposal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Fix The Rogue Referral Problem In Single-Page Sites</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/fix-rogue-referral-problem-single-page-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 11:58:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/fix-rogue-referral-problem-single-page-sites/</guid>
      <description>Single-page sites (or single-page apps) typically have just one page load. When navigating the site, subsequent content is either uncovered from the DOM, where it&#39;s been in a hidden state, or loaded from the server using HTTP requests that do not invoke a new page refresh. This behavior, however, has some implications for Google Analytics tracking, especially when configured via Google Tag Manager.
The crux of the problem is this: When you create a Google Analytics tracker, the URL of the page (without a possible #hash) from when the tracker was created is sent as the value of the Document Location field with every hit that uses this tracker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing GA Spy For Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/introducing-ga-spy-for-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 10:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/introducing-ga-spy-for-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>This is a guest post by Stephen Harris from Seer Interactive . He was kind enough to share his awesome solution in this blog, so I&#39;m very grateful indeed for his contribution.
If Google Tag Manager is loaded as the primary instrument for tracking on a webpage (as it should be), then all webpage tracking could and should be configurable via GTM. But we don&#39;t always control the circumstances, and it&#39;s not uncommon to face hardcoded Google Analytics tracking outside of GTM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 JavaScript Concepts For Web Analytics Implementation</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/10-javascript-concepts-for-web-analytics-implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 15:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/10-javascript-concepts-for-web-analytics-implementation/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve already written extensively about JavaScript in web analytics implementation. Suffice to say, understanding at least the basics is absolutely necessary to survive in the technical medium of the web browser.
  This article expands on a conference talk I gave at MeasureCamp IX, London a short while ago. I&#39;ve always been quite single-minded about the importance of JavaScript in web analytics development, and it was a pleasure for me to get some of that off my chest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting Cross-Domain Tracking In Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/troubleshooting-cross-domain-tracking-in-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 08:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/troubleshooting-cross-domain-tracking-in-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>Cross-domain tracking, in Google Analytics, is the process of passing information stored in browser cookies from one domain to another. Due to web browsers&amp;rsquo; same-origin policy, a browser cookie is only available to the domain it is written on and all its subdomains (by default). Since Google Analytics uses cookies to persist the Client ID, once the user moves from domain to domain it&#39;s important to somehow pass this Client ID, too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Google Tag Manager And Google Analytics In Local Files</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/run-google-tag-manager-google-analytics-local-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 13:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/run-google-tag-manager-google-analytics-local-files/</guid>
      <description>Last updated 2 March 2018.
Every now and then you might be urged to run Google Tag Manager and/or Google Analytics locally, meaning without the benefit of a web server serving your files. In other words, you&#39;re loading an HTML file from your computer in the web browser. You can identify a locally run file by the file:/// protocol in the address bar.
  Now, deploying Google Tag Manager onto that file with the hopes of running Google Analytics requests locally isn&#39;t quite simple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Use eventTimeout With eventCallback</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/use-eventtimeout-eventcallback/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 08:43:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/use-eventtimeout-eventcallback/</guid>
      <description>There are times when I&#39;m disappointed with Google&#39;s developer documentation, especially for Google Tag Manager. Most of the time they get it right, and I&#39;d say around 80% of questions being thrown around the forums can be answered just by reading through the documentation. But there are some cases where the documentation is misleading or even downright dangerous. One of these cases is Enhanced Ecommerce.
This isn&#39;t going to be a thorough critique of said documentation, but the tip in this post has to do with one of the examples that the documentation gives for measuring Product Clicks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attribution In Enhanced Ecommerce Reports</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/attribution-enhanced-ecommerce-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 08:42:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/attribution-enhanced-ecommerce-reports/</guid>
      <description>Enhanced Ecommerce is a very useful set of reports in Google Analytics. They extend the standard Ecommerce funnel, which measures only purchases, and allow you to observe products from the very first impression, through various interactions, all the way to the purchase and even beyond, if the user wanted a refund. Google has some solid documentation on how to implement and interpret Enhanced Ecommerce, but if there&#39;s one area that would deserve more illumination, it&#39;s attribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Deploy GTM In Your Chrome Extension</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/gtmtips-deploy-gtm-chrome-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 07:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/gtmtips-deploy-gtm-chrome-extension/</guid>
      <description>Have you created a Chrome Extension, and now you&#39;re dying to find out how users are interacting with it? Perhaps you want to see what features are (not) being utilized, or perhaps you&#39;re just interested in knowing if people are actually using it.
In this article, I&#39;ll show you how to configure Google Tag Manager, so that it works in the restricted sandbox of the Chrome Extension. You&#39;ll need to make some tweaks, but it&#39;s still perfectly doable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Dashboard With Klipfolio And Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/content-dashboard-klipfolio-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 11:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/content-dashboard-klipfolio-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>I have very little against Google Analytics&amp;rsquo; default dashboards. The reason I shy away from them is because they lack the type of customization I&#39;ve come to expect from a dashboarding tool. On top of that, they only let you look at GA data, and I learned early on in my career that focusing on just one vertical is one of the cardinal sins you can make as an analyst.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: 10 Blogs, 10 Articles, 10 People To Follow</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/gtmtips-10-blogs-10-articles-10-people-follow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 15:11:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/gtmtips-10-blogs-10-articles-10-people-follow/</guid>
      <description>Quite a while ago, I wrote an article on what I considered (then) to be my favorite Google Tag Manager resources. Many of them are still very valid, but I still wanted to write a follow-up. Times have changed, and GTM is very different from what it was two years ago when I wrote the post.
So in this article, I want to divert your attention to 10 blogs, 10 articles, and 10 people - all which are and/or share excellent Google Tag Manager content on a periodic basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug Google Analytics On Your Mobile Browser</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/debug-google-analytics-on-your-mobile-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 17:43:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/debug-google-analytics-on-your-mobile-browser/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m currently at SMX München, which is still one of my favorite conferences in Europe. The quality of the talks is superb, and the organization is just perfect. So today, after my talk (joint session with the awesome Dave Sottimano), I was listening to the inimitable Mike King give an excellent presentation together with Ari Nahmani on technical skill prerequisites for all digital marketers today. Needless to say, I strongly agree with their view that digital marketing has always been a technical discipline, and the web is getting more and more complex each day that passes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track Content Engagement Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-content-engagement-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 16:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-content-engagement-part-2/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days ago, I wrote an article on tracking content engagement. Even though the solution itself works, and it&#39;s a really neat trick if I can say so myself, it has its problems.
After all the glory I showered on User Timings in Google Analytics, they have one serious flaw: they cap at 10,000 samples per day. What a ridiculous, arbitrary limit.
In any case, this means that if you have enough traffic to accumulate 10K user timing hits per day, it means that the solution I provided in the previous article will not work for you, as the Pageviews will not be capped, meaning the calculation of Total Engaged Time / Pageviews will be skewed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track Content Engagement Via GTM</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-content-engagement-via-gtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 15:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-content-engagement-via-gtm/</guid>
      <description>When looking at Google Analytics reports, you&#39;d think you get a pretty good idea of how people are interacting with your site, right? I mean, you&#39;re tracking events here, pageviews there, and user timings, custom dimensions, custom metrics, and calculated metrics are all part of your daily lingo. But you&#39;re also probably aware of how futile this tracking is. After all, all you&#39;re seeing are numbers that reflect certain outcomes the visitors have produced on the website, and how these outcomes match against your preconceived goals and objectives, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Analytics Endpoint Debugger</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-analytics-endpoint-debugger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 09:59:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-analytics-endpoint-debugger/</guid>
      <description>This is a really cool feature for Google Analytics data collection, of which I&#39;ve heard very, very little buzz. It&#39;s a way to debug any and all hits sent to the Google Analytics endpoint at https://www.google-analytics.com/collect.
  In all simplicity, you just need to copy the entire URL of the HTTP request to your clipboard, paste it into a web browser, and add /debug between the hostname and /collect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GA Snippet And GA (GTM) Tag On The Same Page</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/ga-snippet-and-ga-gtm-tag-on-the-same-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 09:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/ga-snippet-and-ga-gtm-tag-on-the-same-page/</guid>
      <description>In this article, I&#39;m going to tackle one of the most frequently asked questions out there:
Can you run Google Analytics using the snippet AND using a Google Tag Manager Tag on the same page?
  There are many facets to this query, so I&#39;ll try to tackle as many of them as I possibly can.
First, a terminology rant. You hear lots of talk about &amp;ldquo;on-page&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;inline&amp;rdquo; Google Analytics tracking, as that&#39;s what&#39;s used to describe the non-GTM way of tracking Google Analytics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cookie Settings And Subdomain Tracking In Universal Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/cookie-settings-and-subdomain-tracking-in-universal-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 11:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/cookie-settings-and-subdomain-tracking-in-universal-analytics/</guid>
      <description>Welcome back my friends (to the show that never ends)! It&#39;s been a couple of weeks since my last barrage of articles, and I think the time is ripe to do some testing!
First things first, here&#39;s a picture of me shovelling snow:
  And now back to the topic at hand.
One of the things that seems to be a hot topic in Universal Analytics is cross-domain tracking. I&#39;ve never really tackled the beast head-on, since there&#39;s such a wealth of excellent articles about it out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iframe Cross-Domain Tracking In Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/iframe-cross-domain-tracking-in-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 10:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/iframe-cross-domain-tracking-in-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>NOTE! This solution has been upgraded, and the new approach can be found here.
 If you&#39;re unfamiliar with the lingo, cross-domain tracking is a hack used by Google Analytics to circumvent the web browser&#39;s same-origin policy. Essentially, the policy dictates that browser cookies can only be shared with a parent domain and all its sub-domains. In other words, domainA.com and domainB.com do not share cookies.
Since Google Analytics calculates sessions and users by using a cookie, this is problematic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup Google Tag Manager iOS With Swift</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/setup-google-tag-manager-ios-with-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 12:16:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/setup-google-tag-manager-ios-with-swift/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been meaning to write about Google Tag Manager for mobile apps for such a long time. Finally, I have some great use cases to share, as well as some useful examples for implementing GTM for iOS. That&#39;s right, this is an iOS guide, and, to be more specific, geared towards a successful Swift implementation.
  If you didn&#39;t know, Swift is a relatively new programming language, developed by Apple for iOS and OS X programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measure Ad And Content Blocker Impact</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/measure-ad-content-blocker-impact-on-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 08:52:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/measure-ad-content-blocker-impact-on-traffic/</guid>
      <description>So, looks like iOS 9 has built-in support for integrating &amp;ldquo;content blocking&amp;rdquo; extensions on your iPhone. Now, blocking ads and other intrusive content is nothing new, nor do I want to get into a debate about whether it&#39;s a good thing or not. But as a data geek I&#39;m very interested in knowing just what share of my site tracking has some content blocker enabled. In this post, I&#39;ll show two tricks (easy and advanced) to expose these content blockers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measure SERP Bounce Time With GTM</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/measure-serp-bounce-time-with-gtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 12:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/measure-serp-bounce-time-with-gtm/</guid>
      <description>Here&#39;s an interesting and hacky use case for you. It&#39;s all about uncovering bounce metrics for visits which originate from organic Google search results. In particular, the metric we&#39;re interested in is how long user dwelled on the landing page after arriving from organic Google search AND returned to the search engine results page (SERP) using the browser&#39;s back button.
  The inspiration for this post came from an audience question at the Best Internet Conference in Lithuania, which I recently attended as a speaker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Ecommerce Tips And Learnings</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-tips-and-learnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 07:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-tips-and-learnings/</guid>
      <description>Enhanced Ecommerce is undoubtedly an excellent feature of Google Analytics. It provides us with a set of reports that truly extend the capabilities of funnel-based website analysis. As I&#39;ve shown before, it&#39;s also very useful for tracking other transactional events on your site, such as content engagement.
  However, here&#39;s the thing. It&#39;s not very easy to implement. Even if you get everything right according to the documentation, there are still quite a number of pitfalls, and many of the learnings emerge only through experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Prevent Tag From Firing In iFrame</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/prevent-tag-from-firing-in-iframe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 10:35:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/prevent-tag-from-firing-in-iframe/</guid>
      <description>Unfortunately, iFrames still exist. They are used to embed content from one page into another. Frames are horrible, nasty things, very often riddled with cross-domain problems, performance issues, responsive design obstructions and other crap from the nether pits of hell. Regardless, if you&#39;re stuck with an iFrame which also collects data to your Google Analytics property, for example, you probably want to prevent at least the first Page View from firing, since otherwise you&#39;ll be double-counting Page Views: once on the main page and once in the iFrame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track Form Engagement With Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-form-engagement-with-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 07:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-form-engagement-with-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>(Updated 13 August 2017)
A little over a year ago, in April 2014, I wrote the post &amp;ldquo;Advanced Form Tracking In Google Tag Manager&amp;quot;, and it&#39;s been at the top of my best seller list ever since. Turns out that many people are rightfully passionate about making the web forms on their websites as fluid and intuitive as possible, since a web form is often the only thing that stands between a prospect and their transformation into clienthood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Implement Referral Exclusions Via GTM</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/implement-referral-exclusions-via-gtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 11:46:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/implement-referral-exclusions-via-gtm/</guid>
      <description>Maintaining the list of Referral Exclusions in Google Analytics admin is a pain. Especially if you have a webstore, the number of referral sources you need to exclude to avoid sessions being split can grow really fast. Also, it&#39;s not like the list is has the most intuitive UI. Instead of a handy text area where you could just copy-paste stuff, you&#39;re left with a horrible line-by-line list, and there&#39;s no way of copying lists across properties or anything useful like that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measure Cart Value In Enhanced Ecommerce</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/measure-cart-value-in-enhanced-ecommerce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 15:11:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/measure-cart-value-in-enhanced-ecommerce/</guid>
      <description>One of the glaring omissions in the Enhanced Ecommerce reports of Universal Analytics is the ability to calculate cart value for products. Cart value, here, is the value that has been added to the cart.
This value can be used to query for products that have the highest discrepancy between cart value and generated revenue. These are missed opportunities of the highest caliber.
With some Custom Metrics magic, we can, however, get cart value into our reports, and we can find our most and least &amp;ldquo;effective&amp;rdquo; products with just a glance:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Tag Manager: SoundCloud Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-soundcloud-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 12:28:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-soundcloud-integration/</guid>
      <description>According to their website, SoundCloud is &amp;ldquo;the world’s leading social sound platform where anyone can create sounds and share them everywhere&amp;rdquo;. For artists, it&#39;s a channel for distributing previews of their tracks, and for people like me it&#39;s a nice way to do some API tinkering. To each their own, I guess!
  I saw a number of requests in the Google+ Google Tag Manager community about a SoundCloud integration, so I decided to look into it to see if I could just build one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data is difficult</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/data-is-difficult/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 14:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/data-is-difficult/</guid>
      <description>Data is difficult. Growing a business is difficult. Measuring success is difficult. And you know what? They should be difficult. Otherwise we&#39;d all be equally stupid, whereas now those of us ambitious enough to exert themselves are winning the race.
  And it&#39;s not just working with data that&#39;s difficult. The whole Web is a mess! Search engine optimization consultants, for example, are trigger-happy in doling out advice about server-side redirects without stopping to consider the implications of what they&#39;re recommending.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spam Filter Insertion Tool</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/spam-filter-insertion-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 18:04:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/spam-filter-insertion-tool/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend, I wrote a very simple web app that automatically creates a number of referral spam filters to tackle the problem that seems to have everybody all riled up.
  For a nice recap of the situation, take a look at this post by Jeff Sauer, or this article by Mike Sullivan.
This isn&#39;t an opinion piece, even though I&#39;ve got a great number of opinions about this issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Schema Conspiracy</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/the-schema-conspiracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 08:17:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/the-schema-conspiracy/</guid>
      <description>A schema is something that data processing platforms such as Google Analytics apply to the raw hit data coming in from the data source (usually a website). The most visible aspect of Google Analytics&amp;rsquo; schema is how it groups, or stitches, the arbitrary, hit-level data coming in from the website into discrete sessions, and these are actually grouped under yet another aggregate bucket: users.
But you already know this. You&#39;re looking at metrics like Sessions, Bounce Rate, Conversion Rate, and you&#39;re using them or variations of them as KPIs in your dashboards and whatnot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track Non-JavaScript Visits In Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-non-javascript-visits-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 15:48:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-non-javascript-visits-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>One of the big mysteries in browser-based data collection platforms like Google Analytics is what happens when the visitor is not being tracked. This is most obvious in cases where the user explicitly opts out of tracking, when the user does not have JavaScript active in their browser, in bounced sessions, and on exit pages.
Opt-outing means that the user explicitly prohibits a website from tracking them. In some cases, it&#39;s possible that opt-out is the default, and the user must explicitly opt-in to allow GA to record their visits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Analytics And The Page Load</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-analytics-page-load/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 16:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-analytics-page-load/</guid>
      <description>If you use Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager, or any JavaScript-based data collection or analytics platform, have you ever stopped to wonder how they actually work? I mean, you obviously care about getting the data in, but are you taking the machinations of these tools for granted?
This is something I&#39;ve been thinking about for a long while, because I&#39;m not so sure that many who work with these platforms actually understand how the browser and the web page interact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript 101 For GTM: Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/javascript-101-gtm-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 06:50:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/javascript-101-gtm-part-2/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s been an awesome summer, with temperatures soaring in the global warming range throughout our northern country. The heat has given me ample reason to not be near a computer, but now it&#39;s time to mine some JavaScript wisdom again. Here&#39;s the second part of my JavaScript for Google Tag Manager series. The first part focused on GTM specific tips and tricks, and I hope that while reading it, you were treated to another grand example of the flexibility of this wonderful tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internalize for Google Analytics v1.0</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/internalize-google-analytics-v1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 07:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/internalize-google-analytics-v1-0/</guid>
      <description>I created a new Chrome Extension: Internalize for Google Analytics. This is its very first version. It only works on websites with Universal Analytics.
Click here to download Internalize for Google Analytics v1.0
The idea is that with the extension you can push a custom dimension value to your currently active session. You can then use a profile filter in GA to block traffic with this custom dimension value. It&#39;s useful when blocking internal traffic with more traditional means (IP address or various GTM workarounds) won&#39;t work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Tag Manager: Content Grouping</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-content-grouping/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 16:45:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-content-grouping/</guid>
      <description>Content Grouping is a nice new feature from the good folks at Google Analytics. Basically, it allows you to group your content according to a logical structure. You can create up to five Content Groupings, and you can have as many Content Groups within these groupings as you like. The difference between a Content Grouping and Content Group is hierarchy. The second is a member of the first. Read Justin Cutroni&#39;s post on Content Groupings to get you started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal Analytics: Send Custom Dimension With Event</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/universal-analytics-send-custom-dimension-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 16:32:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/universal-analytics-send-custom-dimension-event/</guid>
      <description>(Last updated March 2014) This post is the final chapter of a trilogy. The ultimate refinement, if you will. It all started with my foray into the murky waters of context, when I tested how weather data could be used to provide extra information about site visits. When I wrote that post, I had two trepidations: 1) does sending the API call with every single page view affect site performance negatively, and 2) does forcing the page view call to wait for the API call to complete affect the quality of visit metrics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal Analytics: Fire Script Just Once Per Session</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/universal-analytics-fire-script-just-per-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 11:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/universal-analytics-fire-script-just-per-session/</guid>
      <description>There is a new version of this post for GTM V2 here.
While going over my previous post about using weather conditions to segment data in Google Analytics, I started thinking about performance issues. Since I&#39;m using a visit-scope custom dimension, it seems futile to have it send the weather details with every single page load. The odds of the weather changing drastically during one visit are slim (unless you live in the UK), and I have yet to come up with a good reason to change my on-site behavior because the weather changed from a drizzle to a downpour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot Google Analytics: 9-Step Program</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/troubleshoot-google-analytics-9-step-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 16:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/troubleshoot-google-analytics-9-step-program/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve had such a blast in the Google+ Google Analytics community. Not only are the people super-duper-nice, but I have the wonderful opportunity of helping people with their Google Analytics problems without feeling obligated to invoice them or ask for compensation for my troubles. I do it because I love to help, because I feel like I have a lot to share with the community, and because I&#39;ve always believed that the more knowledge you share the more you accumulate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal Analytics: Weather As A Custom Dimension</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/web-development/universal-analytics-weather-custom-dimension/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 16:51:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/web-development/universal-analytics-weather-custom-dimension/</guid>
      <description>There is a new version of this post for GTM V2 here.
[Last updated June 2014] I&#39;ve fallen in love with Universal Analytics and Google Tag Manager. Together they form an incredibly powerful tool for marketing professionals. In most cases, I no longer need to post recommendations to my client for yet another page template revision, since with the tag manager in place, I can just add custom code via the admin panel.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>