<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Event Listener on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/event-listener/</link><description>Recent content in Event Listener on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 11:21:51 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/event-listener/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#GTMTips: Add A Load Listener To Script Elements</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/add-load-listener-script-elements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 11:21:51 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/add-load-listener-script-elements/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the challenges in working with &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> (or any JavaScript-based platform for that matter) is what to do with &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-analytics-page-load/">race conditions&lt;/a>. A &lt;strong>race condition&lt;/strong> emerges when you have two resources competing for execution in the browser, and there is a degree of unpredictability to which &amp;ldquo;wins&amp;rdquo; the race.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A prime example is working with &lt;a href="https://www.jquery.com/">jQuery&lt;/a>. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the most popular JavaScript libraries out there, and websites utilize it for a multitude of things, many useful for Google Tag Manager, too. For example, jQuery trivializes &lt;a href="http://api.jquery.com/jquery.ajax/">asynchronous HTTP requests&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://api.jquery.com/category/traversing/">DOM traversal&lt;/a>, both of which can cause headaches to GTM users.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Track Selection In Drop-Down List</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/track-selection-drop-list/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 07:49:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/track-selection-drop-list/</guid><description>&lt;p>Tracking what a user selects in a drop-down (or &lt;code>select&lt;/code>) list/menu can be very useful. This is particularly the case when the selection immediately does something, such as initiate a download or navigate the user to another page. But even if there is no immediate action, it&amp;rsquo;s still interesting to know what selections users might be doing, if only to uncover yet another piece of the engagement puzzle. Here&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> way to do it!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Node Relationships And GTM</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/node-relationships-gtm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 13:25:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/node-relationships-gtm/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>There&amp;rsquo;s a much easier, native-to-GTM way to do this now: the &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/matches-css-selector-operator-in-gtm-triggers/">Matches CSS Selector&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Behind this tragically boring title is a simple solution to many problems with Google Tag Manager&amp;rsquo;s auto-event tracking. The common denominator to these problems is poor website markup. Selectors are used sparingly, and element hierarchy is messy. This disregard for proper node relationships means you have to resort to Data Layer Variable Macros which look like&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>gtm.element.parentElement.parentElement.id&lt;/code>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>