<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Big Data on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/big-data/</link><description>Recent content in Big Data on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 11:30:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/big-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Context Is King: Measure Everything!</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/context-king-measure-everything/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/context-king-measure-everything/</guid><description>&lt;p>Have you ever stopped to think about what the chain of events was that led you to a particular decision? Maybe not, but in web analytics it is something that should be considered. After all, there is something counter-intuitive about analytics tools such as &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/">Google Analytics&lt;/a>, which require us to think in terms of &lt;strong>clicks&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>recorded events&lt;/strong> that occur &lt;em>on the website, during the visit&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thankfully, we have evolved as a species, and we no longer place too much emphasis on &lt;strong>last click attribution&lt;/strong>. In short, last click attribution is a model where success of a particular goal is attributed to the conditions underlying the active session. So if a person visits a page via bookmark and downloads a PDF file on that page, the direct visit channel (which covers, by default, bookmarked visits) is the &lt;strong>only&lt;/strong> one which receives the kudos for the file download. Nothing is attributed to other channels, which might have exposed the user to the brand, the product, and the file itself. Ridiculous, right? &lt;a href="https://www.portent.com/blog/analytics/rip-last-click-attribution.htm">R.I.P. last click attribution&lt;/a>!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>