<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>piwik pro on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/piwik-pro/</link>
    <description>Recent content in piwik pro on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 07:01:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/piwik-pro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GA4 to Piwik PRO Using Server-side Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/ga4-to-piwik-pro-using-server-side-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 07:01:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/ga4-to-piwik-pro-using-server-side-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>There are two new custom templates available in server-side Google Tag Manager. These templates have been designed to facilitate Piwik PRO tracking in a server-side container.
 Piwik PRO Client -&amp;gt; This Client template interacts with the Piwik PRO JavaScript tracker and lets you route Piwik PRO tracking through a server-side GTM container. GitHub repo. Piwik PRO -&amp;gt; The tag template works in unison with the Piwik PRO Client, forwarding the hits to the Piwik PRO endpoint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Piwik PRO Templates In Server-side Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/new-piwik-pro-templates-server-side-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/new-piwik-pro-templates-server-side-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>Piwik PRO has two new server-side Google Tag Manager templates, and this article explains what they are and how they work.
The first template, Piwik PRO Client, is designed to work in unison with the Piwik PRO HTTP API. Most often these requests are generated by the Piwik PRO JavaScript tracker, but theoretically any HTTP source that uses the same schema can send requests for the Client to claim. Once the Client claims the request, it generates an event data object that can be consumed by tags in the server-side Google Tag Manager container.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>