<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>app engine on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/app-engine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in app engine on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 07:00:01 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/app-engine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Setup IAM For Manual Installation Of Server-side GTM</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtmtips/setup-iam-manual-installation-server-side-gtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 07:00:01 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtmtips/setup-iam-manual-installation-server-side-gtm/</guid>
      <description>If you want to manually install server-side Google Tag Manager on App Engine in the Google Cloud Platform, you are of course welcome to do so.
The main benefits of doing this are that you get to choose the region where App Engine is deployed and that you can use existing project resources instead of having a new project automatically created for you.
However, to run the script without errors, there are a number of things you need to enable first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Map Multiple Domains To A Server-side Tagging Endpoint</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/map-multiple-domains-server-side-tagging-endpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 14:38:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/map-multiple-domains-server-side-tagging-endpoint/</guid>
      <description>One of the biggest perks of working with server-side tagging is that you can establish a first-party context between the site sending the data and the server-side tagging endpoint itself.
This leads to many benefits, including improved control of the data streams, the possibility to set cookies that extend beyond ITP&amp;rsquo;s restrictions, and reduced stress on an already very likely overloaded Content Security Policy.
However, by default you only map a single custom domain to any given tagging server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create A Cookie Rewrite Web Service Using The Google Cloud Platform</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/google-cloud/create-cookie-rewrite-web-service-google-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/google-cloud/create-cookie-rewrite-web-service-google-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Last updated 11 September 2020: Added important note about how the custom domain should be mapped with A/AAAA DNS records rather than a CNAME record.
 Ah, Safari&amp;rsquo;s Intelligent Tracking Prevention - the gift that keeps on giving. Having almost milked this cow for all it&amp;rsquo;s worth, I was sure there would be little need to revisit the topic. Maybe, I thought, it would be better to just sit back and watch the world burn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Site Search With Hugo &#43; App Engine &#43; Search API &#43; Python</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/web-development/static-site-search-google-app-engine-search-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 09:39:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/web-development/static-site-search-google-app-engine-search-api/</guid>
      <description>As the year changed to 2018, I decided to abandon WordPress, which I had been using for over 12 years as my content management system of choice. I had many reasons to do so, but the biggest motivators were the opportunity to try something new and to abandon the bloat and clutter of WordPress for a more simple, more elegant order of things. Spurred on by another adopter, Mark Edmondson, I decided to give Hugo a go (pun intended).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>