<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>server-side on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/server-side/</link>
    <description>Recent content in server-side on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 07:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/server-side/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>First-Party Mode For Google Tags</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/first-party-mode-google-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/first-party-mode-google-tags/</guid>
      <description>Google has released a new feature, First-Party Mode (FPM), into public beta.
  Image source
First-Party Mode seeks to make it easier to wrap Google&amp;rsquo;s measurement and advertising technologies in a first-party, same-origin context.
This means that the user&amp;rsquo;s browser, when visiting a website running FPM, would no longer communicate directly with Google&amp;rsquo;s domains when fetching measurement libraries such as Google Tag or Google Tag Manager.
Instead, the requests would be sent to a subfolder of the website itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agency, Transparency, And Control: Unsolved Problems With Server-side Tagging</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/agency-transparency-control-unsolved-problems-server-side-tagging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/agency-transparency-control-unsolved-problems-server-side-tagging/</guid>
      <description>I have been a strong supporter of server-side tagging, in particular Google&amp;rsquo;s server-side tag management solution.
I admire the way it seeks to readjust the balance of control that typically has been in favor of the marketing vendors whose JavaScript libraries have been free to wreak havoc in the user&amp;rsquo;s browser.
  By inserting a buffer between the user and the vendor, the owner of the server-side tagging setup can take control over what data the marketing vendors can actually process of the user.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>