<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Workspaces on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/workspaces/</link><description>Recent content in Workspaces on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 10:01:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/workspaces/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#GTMTips: Change Management With Workspaces</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/change-management-workspaces/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 10:01:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/change-management-workspaces/</guid><description>&lt;p>A while ago, the &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> team published one of my favorite feature releases in the history of GTM: &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/tagmanager/answer/7059647?hl=en">Workspaces&lt;/a>. I was so thrilled by this release that I went ahead and published &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-tag-manager-workspaces/">a guide&lt;/a> on how to implement and leverage this new feature.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Workspaces is a very comprehensive feature in Google Tag Manager. This is because it changed the entire underlying data model. We no longer work directly with a single container draft. Instead, our work is done in a cordoned section of the container, protected from changes made to other workspaces until such a time that we choose to sync the latest container version to our workspace, or vice versa.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Revamped User Interface In Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/revamped-user-interface-in-google-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 15:08:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/revamped-user-interface-in-google-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a crazy week. Just crazy. Not only did &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> introduce &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-tag-manager-workspaces/">Workspaces&lt;/a>, arguably one of its most important releases ever for GTM, but they also revamped the user interface! So very big changes have been underfoot, and I&amp;rsquo;m so happy to be writing about them, because in my completely biased opinion these changes are amazing and well worth the long wait.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, I want to quickly walk you through what I think are the most meaningful changes in the interface. A lot has changed, but the underlying mechanisms of GTM are still the same. You&amp;rsquo;re still creating Tags, Triggers, and Variables, and you&amp;rsquo;re still debugging the container using Debug Mode. However, the new user interfaces enhances and streamlines the various creation processes in the container, and the new &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-tag-manager-workspaces/">Abandon / View Changes&lt;/a> feature allows you to debug and diff the changes you or your team has made.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Tag Manager Workspaces</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-tag-manager-workspaces/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 15:07:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-tag-manager-workspaces/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well, well, well. Welcome to the Enterprise Game, &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>! You know, if you took a look at all the feature requests and complaints that pass through the &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/communities/104865292981489764063">Google+ community&lt;/a> or the &lt;a href="https://productforums.google.com/forum/#!forum/tag-manager">Product Forums&lt;/a>, you&amp;rsquo;d notice that a large portion of them revolve around lack of multi-user and multi-team support in the tool. Well GTM has taken a gigantic leap forward to soothe these concerns, with the release of its latest feature: &lt;strong>WORKSPACES&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>