<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Universal Analytics on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/universal-analytics/</link><description>Recent content in Universal Analytics on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 07:04:01 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/universal-analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The FPID Cookie For Google Analytics In Server-side Tagging</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/fpid-cookie-google-analytics-server-side-tagging/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 07:04:01 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/fpid-cookie-google-analytics-server-side-tagging/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Last updated 27 April 2023 with details about preventing FPID access in cookieless scenarios.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>With &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">Server-side tagging&lt;/a>, the developer community has a chance to vastly improve the data collection capabilities of Google&amp;rsquo;s analytics platforms (&lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2790010">Universal Analytics&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/9306384">App+Web&lt;/a>). The ability to build &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/build-custom-universal-analytics-client-server-side-tagging/">our own templates&lt;/a> is particularly potent with a Server container.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, it&amp;rsquo;s not as if Google themselves are just sitting idly by and seeing what the community can come up with.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Build A Custom Universal Analytics Client For Server-side Tagging</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/build-custom-universal-analytics-client-server-side-tagging/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 07:03:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/build-custom-universal-analytics-client-server-side-tagging/</guid><description>&lt;p>You can utilize &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">&lt;em>Server-side tagging&lt;/em>&lt;/a> in &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> to build your own custom Universal Analytics proxy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This proxy comes in the shape of a new &lt;strong>Client&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/custom-templates-guide-for-google-tag-manager/">custom template&lt;/a>, which takes the incoming &lt;code>/collect&lt;/code> requests and sends them to Google Analytics. While doing so, it also returns the &lt;code>_ga&lt;/code> cookie in a &lt;code>Set-Cookie&lt;/code> header, thus preventing Safari&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://www.cookiestatus.com/safari/">Intelligent Tracking Prevention&lt;/a> from capping its expiration to just 7 days.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>You might also be interested in reading what &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/fpid-cookie-google-analytics-server-side-tagging/">Google&amp;rsquo;s own solution&lt;/a> is for migrating from JavaScript cookies to those set in HTTP headers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Simple Way To Exclude Internal Visits From Google Analytics</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/simple-way-exclude-internal-visits-google-analytics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 14:55:54 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/simple-way-exclude-internal-visits-google-analytics/</guid><description>&lt;p>With so many people working from home or remotely in these turbulent times, it&amp;rsquo;s time to revisit one of my &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/block-internal-traffic-gtm/">oldest articles&lt;/a>, and discuss the options you have for excluding or segmenting internal traffic in &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com/">Google Analytics&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The traditional method of &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/1034840?hl=en">IP address exclusion&lt;/a> is not necessarily the best option anymore, unless all your employees use a specific VPN to connect to the site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll go through some of the tools you have at your disposal.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tracking Cross-domain Iframes - Upgraded Solution</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/tracking-cross-domain-iframes-upgraded-solution/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 10:31:15 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/tracking-cross-domain-iframes-upgraded-solution/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>**Last updated &lt;strong>18 September 2020&lt;/strong>: Due to how &lt;a href="https://www.cookiestatus.com/">most browsers now have third-party cookie protections&lt;/a> in place, this solution will be very ineffective going forwards. You should instead take a look at a &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/cookieless-tracking-cross-site-iframes/">cookieless solution&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Some years ago, I wrote a post on &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/iframe-cross-domain-tracking-in-google-tag-manager/">how to track cross-domain iframes&lt;/a> when using &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com">Google Analytics&lt;/a>. That solution relied on &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/hitcallback-eventcallback/">&lt;code>hitCallback&lt;/code>&lt;/a> to decorate the iframe, and now that I look back on it, it has its shortcomings.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Add Client ID To Custom Dimension With gtag.js</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/add-clientid-to-custom-dimension-gtag-js/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 06:50:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/add-clientid-to-custom-dimension-gtag-js/</guid><description>&lt;p>When Google released &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/gtagjs/">gtag.js&lt;/a>, the new, global tracking library designed to (eventually) replace &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/">analytics.js&lt;/a>, many Universal Analytics practitioners and users were confused (see e.g. Jeff&amp;rsquo;s great overview &lt;a href="https://www.jeffalytics.com/google-gtag-js/">here&lt;/a>). It seemed like &lt;strong>gtag.js&lt;/strong> wasn&amp;rsquo;t really solving any immediate problem, since analytics.js had done a bang-up job with Universal Analytics tracking for all these years. However, &lt;strong>gtag&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/strong> modus operandi is the ability to leverage the same semantic information (distributed across &lt;code>dataLayer&lt;/code>!) across a number of Google products, starting with GA and AdWords.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Send Event And Custom Dimension If Google Optimize Experiment Is Running</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/send-event-custom-dimension-google-optimize-experiment-running/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 14:52:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/send-event-custom-dimension-google-optimize-experiment-running/</guid><description>&lt;p>I really like &lt;a href="https://optimize.google.com/optimize/home/">Google Optimize&lt;/a>. It has a fairly intuitive UI, setting up experiments is easy, and there&amp;rsquo;s integrations for both &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com/">Google Analytics&lt;/a> built into the system. It&amp;rsquo;s still a JavaScript-based, client-side A/B-testing tool, so problems with flicker and asynchronous loading are ever-present (though this is somewhat mitigated by the &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/optimize/#the_page-hiding_snippet_code">page-hiding snippet&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One issue with the Google Analytics integration is the difficulty of creating segments for sessions where the users were actively participating in the experiment. In fact, there&amp;rsquo;s no specific signal in Google Analytics that tells you the &lt;strong>NOW&lt;/strong> the user is &amp;ldquo;experiencing&amp;rdquo; an experiment. You&amp;rsquo;ll find the &lt;strong>Experiment Name&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Experiment ID&lt;/strong> dimensions, yes, but they have one drawback:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Respect Opt-Out From Advertising And Analytics</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/respect-opt-out-from-advertising-and-analytics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 08:09:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/respect-opt-out-from-advertising-and-analytics/</guid><description>&lt;p>With &lt;a href="https://piwik.pro/blog/gdpr-interview-aurelie-pols/">GDPR&lt;/a> looming around the corner, it&amp;rsquo;s time to explore the options you have at your disposal for respecting the new, stricter regulations for tracking users and for collecting data about their visits to your website.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>UPDATE 20 June 2018: Google has released the &lt;code>allowAdFeatures&lt;/code> field which renders the solution below redundant (at least for the &lt;code>displayFeaturesTask&lt;/code> part of it). Please refer to &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/allow-block-advertising-features-google-analytics/">this article&lt;/a> for more details on how to conditionally block the advertising hit to DoubleClick.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prevent Site Speed Sampling Rate From Skewing Custom Dimensions And Custom Metrics</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/prevent-site-speed-sampling-rate-skewing-custom-dimensions-custom-metrics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 14:09:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/prevent-site-speed-sampling-rate-skewing-custom-dimensions-custom-metrics/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com">Universal Analytics&lt;/a> can collect &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/1205784">Page Timing&lt;/a> data from users that load your pages. This data is populated in to the &lt;strong>Behavior&lt;/strong> -&amp;gt; &lt;strong>Site Speed&lt;/strong> -&amp;gt; &lt;strong>Page Timings&lt;/strong> report, and it&amp;rsquo;s a very useful feature for optimizing your website.&lt;/p>


 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/images/2017/09/page-timings.jpg" title="Page Timings in Universal Analytics">
 
 &lt;amp-img src="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/images/2017/09/page-timings.jpg" layout="responsive" alt="Page Timings in Universal Analytics" height="872" width="2270">&lt;/amp-img>
 
 &lt;/a>
 

&lt;p>However, there&amp;rsquo;s a murky underside to this generous feature. The way Page Timings collection works is that when &lt;strong>Pageview&lt;/strong> hits are sent from the site, a sample of these (1% by default) are automatically followed by a &lt;code>timing&lt;/code> hit which includes page performance data grabbed from the Navigation Timing API.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Send Google Analytics Tag To Multiple Properties</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/send-google-analytics-tag-multiple-properties/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 07:54:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/send-google-analytics-tag-multiple-properties/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here we are again, revisiting an old theme. When using &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>, we often want to send the contents of the same tag to multiple &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com">Universal Analytics&lt;/a> properties. With on-page GA, this used to be quite simple, as all you had to do was create a new tracker and then just remember to run the &lt;code>ga('trackerName.send'...)&lt;/code> commands to all the trackers (or you could use my &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/simple-tracker-duplication-universal-analytics/">duplicator&lt;/a> plugin). With GTM, your options are more limited, since Google Tag Manager abstracts the tracker object, giving you far fewer tools to work with.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Use customTask To Access Tracker Values In Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/use-customtask-access-tracker-values-google-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 08:27:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/use-customtask-access-tracker-values-google-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve recommended from the get-go is to &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/improve-data-collection-with-four-custom-dimensions/">always send the Client ID&lt;/a> to &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com">Google Analytics&lt;/a> with your users&amp;rsquo; hits. This is very useful for adding a level of granularity to your tracking. At first, I recommended using an Event tag to do this. Then I modified my approach a little so that you could send it with your initial &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/access-the-tracker-object-in-your-page-view-tag/">Page View&lt;/a> (thus not inflating your hit counts).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, Universal Analytics recently released a new &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/tasks">task API&lt;/a>, &lt;code>customTask&lt;/code>, which lets you access the model object mid-tag, thus letting you modify the payload that is dispatched to Google Analytics. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how this works by using the classic example of sending the Client ID to Google Analytics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Analytics Settings Variable In GTM</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-analytics-settings-variable-in-gtm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 04:05:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-analytics-settings-variable-in-gtm/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s face it - most of us use &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> for one main purpose: to deploy and configure &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com">Google Analytics&lt;/a> tracking on a website. I&amp;rsquo;d wager that once you start using GTM, you won&amp;rsquo;t be implementing Universal Analytics the old-fashioned way, with on-page code, any more. But running Universal Analytics tags through GTM isn&amp;rsquo;t yet a perfect workflow. We&amp;rsquo;re still missing things like proper &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/universal-analytics-plugins-explained/">plugin&lt;/a> support and the option to properly differentiate between the &lt;em>tracker&lt;/em> and the &lt;em>hit&lt;/em> - both of which are easy to do with an on-page implementation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Site Speed Sample Rate And Multiple Page Views</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/site-speed-sample-rate-multiple-page-views/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 11:34:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/site-speed-sample-rate-multiple-page-views/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com/">Google Analytics&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/1205784?hl=en">Site Speed reports&lt;/a> are pretty darn great. They report automatically on various milestones in the process the browser undertakes when rendering content. These reports leverage the &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Navigation_timing_API">Navigation Timing API&lt;/a> of the web browser, and they are (typically) collected on the first Page View hit of a page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And this is all fine. As I said, it&amp;rsquo;s a great feature of Google Analytics, and lends itself handily to spotting issues in the quite complex client-server negotiation that goes on when your web browser requests content from the web server.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introducing GA Spy For Google Analytics</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/introducing-ga-spy-for-google-analytics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 10:16:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/introducing-ga-spy-for-google-analytics/</guid><description>&lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/images/2016/09/stephen-harris.jpg" title="Stephen Harris (c) Seer Interactive">
 
 &lt;amp-img src="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/images/2016/09/stephen-harris.jpg" layout="responsive" alt="Stephen Harris (c) Seer Interactive" height="400" width="400">&lt;/amp-img>
 
 &lt;/a>
 

&lt;p>&lt;em>This is a guest post by &lt;a href="http://www.seerinteractive.com/about/team/stephen-harris/?utm_source=simoahava.com&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=ana-tech">Stephen Harris&lt;/a> from &lt;a href="http://www.seerinteractive.com/?utm_source=simoahava.com&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=ana-tech">Seer Interactive&lt;/a>
. He was kind enough to share his awesome solution in this blog, so I&amp;rsquo;m very grateful indeed for his contribution.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> is loaded as the primary instrument for tracking on a webpage (as it should be), then all webpage tracking could and should be configurable via GTM. But we don&amp;rsquo;t always control the circumstances, and it&amp;rsquo;s not uncommon to face hardcoded &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com">Google Analytics&lt;/a> tracking outside of GTM.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Simple Tracker Duplication For Universal Analytics</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/simple-tracker-duplication-universal-analytics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 10:49:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/simple-tracker-duplication-universal-analytics/</guid><description>&lt;p>First of all, I&amp;rsquo;m sorry about the title. I should really stop throwing the word &amp;ldquo;simple&amp;rdquo; around, since people always tell me that the stuff I claim to be easy and straightforward is rarely so. But since this is my blog, I reserve the right to use whatever stupid and misleading terminology I want. I maintain that what follows IS quite simple, especially when considering the amount of complexity it reduces in your &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com/">Universal Analytics&lt;/a> setup.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Be Careful With The Tracker Name Setting</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/be-careful-with-the-tracker-name-setting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 11:44:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/be-careful-with-the-tracker-name-setting/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello friends! Today I want to direct your attention to a &lt;strong>dangerous&lt;/strong> setting found within the bowels of the Universal Analytics Tag template in &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>. In fact, GTM itself &lt;em>highly discourages&lt;/em> you from meddling with it:&lt;/p>


 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/images/2016/01/highly-discouraged-tracker-name.jpg" title="Use of tracker name is highly discouraged">
 
 &lt;amp-img src="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/images/2016/01/highly-discouraged-tracker-name.jpg" layout="responsive" alt="Use of tracker name is highly discouraged" height="180" width="1254">&lt;/amp-img>
 
 &lt;/a>
 

&lt;p>I actually agree with this warning. It should be highly discouraged, as modifying the tracker name introduces a potential hazard to your tracking plan, &lt;em>unless you know what you&amp;rsquo;re doing&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cookie Settings And Subdomain Tracking In Universal Analytics</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/cookie-settings-and-subdomain-tracking-in-universal-analytics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 11:49:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/cookie-settings-and-subdomain-tracking-in-universal-analytics/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome back my friends (to the show that never ends)! It&amp;rsquo;s been a couple of weeks since my last barrage of articles, and I think the time is ripe to do some &lt;strong>testing&lt;/strong>!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First things first, here&amp;rsquo;s a picture of me shovelling snow:&lt;/p>


 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/images/2016/01/simo.jpg" title="Shovelling snow">
 
 &lt;amp-img src="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/images/2016/01/simo.jpg" layout="responsive" alt="Shovelling snow" height="720" width="960">&lt;/amp-img>
 
 &lt;/a>
 

&lt;p>And now back to the topic at hand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the things that seems to be a hot topic in Universal Analytics is cross-domain tracking. I&amp;rsquo;ve never really tackled the beast head-on, since there&amp;rsquo;s such a wealth of &lt;a href="https://www.bounteous.com/search_gcse/?q=cross-domain">excellent articles&lt;/a> about it out there. However, I have taken a plunge into the deep end with some specific stuff, such as &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/iframe-cross-domain-tracking-in-google-tag-manager/">iframe&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/cross-domain-tracking-across-subdomains/">subdomain&lt;/a> tracking.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Enhanced Ecommerce With A Custom JavaScript Variable</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-with-a-custom-javascript-variable/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 08:15:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-with-a-custom-javascript-variable/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/enhanced-ecommerce">Enhanced Ecommerce&lt;/a> is a very nice improvement to the pretty lame, &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/ecommerce">transaction-based Ecommerce&lt;/a> tracking in Universal Analytics. Instead of staring blindly at what happens on a receipt page, Enhanced Ecommerce expands your entire webstore into one large funnel labelled &amp;ldquo;Shopping Behavior&amp;rdquo;, and you&amp;rsquo;re able to zoom in on the Checkout funnel as well. Also, the addition of product-scoped tracking is incredibly useful, and it&amp;rsquo;s enabled us to think of &lt;em>any&lt;/em> asset (&lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/track-content-enhanced-ecommerce/">our content&lt;/a>, for example) on our site as something we could track through the Enhanced Ecommerce reports.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Universal Analytics Plugins Explained</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/universal-analytics-plugins-explained/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 13:21:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/universal-analytics-plugins-explained/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are many tools and methods to make &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/">Google Analytics&lt;/a> more manageable. &lt;a href="http://tagmanager.google.com">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> is probably the best known of these, and you can find many, many &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/google-tag-manager/">articles about GTM&lt;/a> on these pages as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, today I want to tell you about one of the features of Universal Analytics that hasn&amp;rsquo;t, as far as I know, received too much attention. It&amp;rsquo;s funny, because at the same time almost everyone uses the feature in the shape of &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/ecommerce">eCommerce&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2558867?hl=en">enhanced link attribution&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cross-domain#autolink">cross-domain tracking&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;m talking, of course, about &lt;strong>Universal Analytics plugins&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Access The Tracker Object In Your Page View Tag</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/access-the-tracker-object-in-your-page-view-tag/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 10:29:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/access-the-tracker-object-in-your-page-view-tag/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you read my &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/improve-data-collection-with-four-custom-dimensions/">previous post&lt;/a> on fetching the &lt;em>Client ID&lt;/em> from the Universal Analytics tracker object with &lt;a href="http://tagmanager.google.com">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>, you might have agreed with me that it sucks you can&amp;rsquo;t access the tracker object interface in real time using Google Tag Manager. This is because all of the &lt;code>set&lt;/code> commands you add to a Universal Analytics tag template take place before the &lt;strong>analytics.js&lt;/strong> is loaded and the tracker object is properly created.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMtips: Setting Google Analytics Fields In GTM</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/setting-google-analytics-fields-in-gtm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 08:06:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/setting-google-analytics-fields-in-gtm/</guid><description>&lt;p>Due to a recent change in the UI (see entry for February 12, 2015 in &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/tagmanager/answer/4620708">the release notes&lt;/a>), the large and ever-expanding group of fields you could set for your Universal Analytics tags has been mostly removed. Instead, the often obscure &lt;strong>Fields to Set&lt;/strong> selection has been promoted to the top of More Settings, and you control most of the Universal Analytics fields through this selector.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/categories/gtm-tips/">#GTMtips&lt;/a>, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a quick look at what&amp;rsquo;s changed, how it&amp;rsquo;s changed, and how to work with this new, slimmed-down tag template.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMtips: Once userId, Always userId</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/once-userid-always-userid/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 18:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/once-userid-always-userid/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/3123663">User ID&lt;/a> is definitely one of the coolest things about Universal Analytics, &lt;em>if used correctly&lt;/em>. It might reveal some surprising insights about your visitors, since now you&amp;rsquo;re not restricted to analysing visitors as just browser or device instances as before, but rather you can build your stories around all the touch points the user might have had on their journey to and through your web properties.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this simple tip, you can extend User ID tracking to return users without them needing to authenticate. This is done with a cookie.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Universal Analytics: Fire Script Just Once Per Session</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/universal-analytics-fire-script-just-per-session/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 11:54:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/universal-analytics-fire-script-just-per-session/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>There is a new version of this post for GTM V2 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/send-weather-data-to-google-analytics-in-gtm-v2/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While going over my previous post about using &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/web-development/universal-analytics-weather-custom-dimension/">weather conditions to segment data&lt;/a> in Google Analytics, I started thinking about performance issues. Since I&amp;rsquo;m using a visit-scope custom dimension, it seems futile to have it send the weather details with every single page load. The odds of the weather changing drastically during one visit are slim (unless you live in the UK), and I have yet to come up with a good reason to change my on-site behavior because the weather changed from a drizzle to a downpour.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Tag Manager: Track Social Interactions</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-tag-manager-track-social-interactions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 15:02:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-tag-manager-track-social-interactions/</guid><description>&lt;p>(Last updated June 2014) &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/analytics">Google Analytics&lt;/a> provides us with a nifty way of &lt;a href="http://www.seotakeaways.com/social-interactions-tracking-through-google-analytics/">tracking social interactions&lt;/a>. With a simple plugin, you can track how many +1s and Likes your pages accumulate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This guide shows you how to activate social interaction tagging with Google Tag Manager and Universal Analytics. The instructions are for Facebook Likes, Google+ +1s (now deprecated since &lt;strong>Google Analytics tracks +1s automatically&lt;/strong>), Twitter Tweets and Pinterest Pins.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that if you use a third-party API (e.g. &lt;a href="http://www.addthis.com">AddThis&lt;/a>) these tricks probably won&amp;rsquo;t work. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to use the API functions themselves to enable tracking.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Universal Analytics: Grab Offline Data From Excel</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/universal-analytics-grab-offline-data-excel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2013 18:21:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/universal-analytics-grab-offline-data-excel/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>UPDATE 9 Oct 2013&lt;/strong> - This works in Google Spreadsheets now as well! Feel free to make a copy of the sheet and work with the code. It&amp;rsquo;s still just a prototype, but I&amp;rsquo;m happy to see data bouncing from spreadsheets to Google Analytics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0AtS7TQFsl6BhdEVUMkd3ZXd6MElNWWF6MkFxUVNFUVE&amp;amp;usp=sharing">View the Google Spreadsheet here&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>ORIGINAL POST&lt;/strong>
Inspired by Daniel Waisberg&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://online-behavior.com/analytics/measurement-protocol">excellent post&lt;/a> detailing the use of Google Web Forms to send data to your Analytics account, I decided to create something similar.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Auto-Event Tracking In Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/auto-event-tracking-google-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2013 05:20:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/auto-event-tracking-google-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>There is a new version of this post for GTM V2 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/auto-event-tracking-gtm-2-0/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="http://analytics.blogspot.fi/2013/10/the-rundown-new-products-and-features.html">Google Analytics Summit&lt;/a> came and went, and thanks to the Live Stream, everyone could participate. We were treated to a rapid-fire selection of Google Analytics&amp;rsquo; new features, and this post sheds light on one of these in particular: automated event tracking in Google Tag Manager.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Auto-event tracking introduces a nice feature, which does what tag managers ought to do: it provides functionality without HTML template editing. This isn&amp;rsquo;t always a good thing, since automation is usually generic and only works for a couple of viable scenarios, but especially for these generic use cases, this new feature is a great addition to GTM&amp;rsquo;s already impressive feature list.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Track Adjusted Bounce Rate In Universal Analytics</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/track-adjusted-bounce-rate-universal-analytics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2013 09:09:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/track-adjusted-bounce-rate-universal-analytics/</guid><description>&lt;p>So here we are again. &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2790010?hl=en">Universal Analytics&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/tagmanager">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>, the dynamic duo, ready to strike again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, remember to check my previous two tips for UA and GTM use in custom scenarios:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/web-development/universal-analytics-weather-custom-dimension/">Weather as a custom dimension&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/page-load-time-universal-analytics/">Tracking page load time&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>In this post, I visit the idea of &lt;a href="http://analytics.blogspot.fi/2012/07/tracking-adjusted-bounce-rate-in-google.html">adjusted bounce rate&lt;/a>, which I came across a year ago in the &lt;a href="http://analytics.google.com">Google Analytics&lt;/a> blog.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adjusted bounce rate basically refers to tweaking the traditional bounce rate collection method (single engagement hits / total visits) so that visits which only included a single page view would not count towards a bounce, as long as they met some qualitative requirements.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Page Load Time In Universal Analytics</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/page-load-time-universal-analytics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2013 14:49:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/page-load-time-universal-analytics/</guid><description>&lt;p>In Google Analytics, you can monitor your &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/1205784?hl=en">site speed&lt;/a> and get a decent overview of what pages are contributing positively and negatively to site speed. The problem with page load time metric is that it&amp;rsquo;s an average based on a sample. You can modify the sample rate with &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/gajs/methods/gaJSApiBasicConfiguration?csw=1#_gat.GA_Tracker_._setSiteSpeedSampleRate">setSiteSpeedSampleRate()&lt;/a>, but for me &lt;em>that&amp;rsquo;s not bloody well good enough&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(&lt;strong>UPDATE 28.3.2014&lt;/strong>: This post is still valid, but an implementation with &lt;em>User Timings&lt;/em> is a much smarter way to measure actual page load time. I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing a short update at some point in the near future.)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Universal Analytics: Weather As A Custom Dimension</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/web-development/universal-analytics-weather-custom-dimension/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 16:51:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/web-development/universal-analytics-weather-custom-dimension/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>There is a new version of this post for GTM V2 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/send-weather-data-to-google-analytics-in-gtm-v2/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[Last updated June 2014] I&amp;rsquo;ve fallen in love with &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2790010?hl=en">Universal Analytics&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/tagmanager/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>. Together they form an incredibly powerful tool for marketing professionals. In most cases, I no longer need to post recommendations to my client for yet another page template revision, since with the tag manager in place, I can just add custom code via the admin panel. Add to that the power of Universal Analytics with its ultra-sensitive Measurement Protocol, and the ability to craft custom dimensions and metrics, and voila! I&amp;rsquo;m in a happy place.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>