<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>guest post on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/guest-post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in guest post on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 09:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/guest-post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY Google Ads Account Monitor With R, AdWords API, And Slack API</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/web-development/monitor-google-ads-accounts-r-adwords-api-slack-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 09:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/web-development/monitor-google-ads-accounts-r-adwords-api-slack-api/</guid>
      <description>Every now and then I&#39;m fortunate enough to be able to publish guest posts by illustrious people in the analytics and digital marketing industries. This time, I get to work with an old colleague of mine who&#39;s a veritable wizard when it comes to building solutions that make our daily work in the digital industry so much smoother.
Erik Grönroos works as an analyst in MarkkinointiAkatemia, a Finnish digital customer acquisition agency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track Users Who Are Offline In Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/track-users-who-are-offline-in-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 08:19:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/track-users-who-are-offline-in-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>The steady increase in mobile use over the last years has introduced some new challenges for web analytics. It&#39;s not just about mismatches in the tracking model (the concept of sessions is even more absurd for apps than it is for desktop browsing), but about something more fundamental, more basic. Think about it: if a visitor visits the website using a mobile device, there&#39;s a significant chance of them losing internet connectivity and going unintentionally offline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Analytics Client ID In AMP Pages</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-analytics-client-id-amp-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 08:59:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-analytics-client-id-amp-pages/</guid>
      <description>This article is a collaboration between Simo and Dan Wilkerson. Dan&#39;s one of the smartest analytics developers out there, and he&#39;s already contributed a great #GTMTips guest post. It&#39;s great to have him back here sharing his insight on working with Accelerated Mobile Pages (AMP).
So, we&#39;re back on AMP! Simo wrote a long, sprawling AMP for Google Tag Manager guide a while ago, and Dan has also contributed to the space with his guide for AMP and Google Analytics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing GA Spy For Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/introducing-ga-spy-for-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 10:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/introducing-ga-spy-for-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>This is a guest post by Stephen Harris from Seer Interactive . He was kind enough to share his awesome solution in this blog, so I&#39;m very grateful indeed for his contribution.
If Google Tag Manager is loaded as the primary instrument for tracking on a webpage (as it should be), then all webpage tracking could and should be configurable via GTM. But we don&#39;t always control the circumstances, and it&#39;s not uncommon to face hardcoded Google Analytics tracking outside of GTM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Using document.write Safely In GTM Tags</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/using-document-write-safely-gtm-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 07:25:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/using-document-write-safely-gtm-tags/</guid>
      <description>This article is a guest article by someone from the analytics community I really look up to. Dan Wilkerson is an analytics developer at Bounteous, a company I hold in high esteem. Dan is one of the smartest technical analytics experts out there, and a large bulk of the awesome scripts and hacks that Bounteous produces (almost on a daily basis) have been orchestrated by him. So I&#39;m very pleased to give the floor to Dan, so that he can tell you all about using the pesky document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firing A Single Tag Multiple Times In GTM</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/firing-a-single-tag-multiple-times-in-gtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 07:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/firing-a-single-tag-multiple-times-in-gtm/</guid>
      <description>There might be many reasons you&#39;d want to fire a single Tag multiple times in Google Tag Manager. The most common one is when you want to deploy multiples of a single tracking point on the web. Perhaps you have a roll-up account you want to send the hits to, in addition to the site-specific tracking property.
Quite a while ago, I gave a solution for this with a specific focus on Google Analytics Tags.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>