<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>session on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/session/</link>
    <description>Recent content in session on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 09:23:07 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/session/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Send Event Hits Before Pageview Hits In Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/send-event-before-pageview-in-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 09:23:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/send-event-before-pageview-in-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>One of the myths surrounding Google Analytics is that the first hit of a session should always be a pageview. It makes sense - sessions are initialized with a landing page, and thus need a page view to have one.
  However, in this article I want to show you empirically how this myth is just that - a myth.
There is little discernible impact if the first hit of a session is an event, and GA is more than capable of stitching the first event together with the subsequent pageview into a session entity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create And Update Google Analytics Session Timeout Cookie</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/create-and-update-google-analytics-session-timeout-cookie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 11:49:23 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/create-and-update-google-analytics-session-timeout-cookie/</guid>
      <description>In Google Analytics, the concept of a session is the key aggregation unit of all the data you work with. It&amp;rsquo;s so central to all the key metrics you use (Conversion Rate, Bounce Rate, Session Duration, Landing Page), and yet there&amp;rsquo;s an underlying complexity that I&amp;rsquo;m pretty certain is unrecognized by many of GA&amp;rsquo;s users. And yet, since this idea of a session is so focal to GA (to the point of being overbearing), it&amp;rsquo;s annoying that the browser isn&amp;rsquo;t privy to any of the sessionization parameters that Google Analytics applies to the hits sent from the browser to its servers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>