<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tags on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/tags/</link><description>Recent content in Tags on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 12:08:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/tags/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GTM Listener Firing Order Test</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/gtm-listener-firing-order-test/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 12:08:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/gtm-listener-firing-order-test/</guid><description>&lt;p>Because I was bored, I did a quick test to sort out the firing order of competing GTM listeners. If you&amp;rsquo;ve done your homework (i.e. read my &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/dont-gtm-listeners-work/">article on GTM listeners&lt;/a>), you&amp;rsquo;ll remember that GTM listeners are set up on the &lt;strong>document&lt;/strong> node of the document object model (DOM). I wanted to test what the firing order is if you have multiple competing listeners on the same page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I tested with the following listeners (make sure you read up on &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/auto-event-tracking-google-tag-manager/">auto-event tracking&lt;/a> if you are completely baffled at this point):&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Tag Manager: The History Listener</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-history-listener/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2014 10:16:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-history-listener/</guid><description>&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s a new listener in town! It&amp;rsquo;s a few days now since the &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/tagmanager">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> team unleashed the &lt;strong>History Listener&lt;/strong>, and the time has come for me to tell you what this baby can do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The History Listener is designed to be used on websites where content is loaded dynamically. Typically, these websites make heavy use of &lt;a href="https://www.w3schools.com/xml/ajax_intro.asp">AJAX&lt;/a> (&lt;strong>A&lt;/strong>synchronous &lt;strong>J&lt;/strong>avaScript &lt;strong>a&lt;/strong>nd &lt;strong>X&lt;/strong>ML), which is designed for loading content in the background and serving it dynamically without having to reload the page.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Some Awesome Google Tag Manager Resources</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/awesome-google-tag-manager-resources/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 15:06:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/awesome-google-tag-manager-resources/</guid><description>&lt;p>When push comes to shove, I&amp;rsquo;m a pretty lazy guy. I enjoy nothing more than just to stretch my legs on a couch, pick up my iPad, and read what&amp;rsquo;s going on in the world. I skip the news, since they&amp;rsquo;re just full of depressing stories. Instead, I head over to my favorite &lt;a href="http://plus.google.com">Google+&lt;/a> communities to see what&amp;rsquo;s new in the blogosphere.&lt;/p>



&lt;div style="aspect-ratio: 689 / 495;" class="figure nocaption">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2014/02/suckerfish.jpg" title="Google Tag Manager master and me">
 
 &lt;img class="fig-img" height="495" width="689" loading="lazy" src="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2014/02/suckerfish.jpg#ZgotmplZ" alt="Google Tag Manager master and me">
 
 &lt;/a>
 
 
&lt;/div>


&lt;p>This approach has led me to some pretty amazing individuals, whom I follow like a suckerfish. These people have written a bunch of great articles, which have helped countless people with their &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/tagmanager">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> installations. Or they might be really active in the online communities which people turn to for advice.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Auto-Event Tracking In Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/auto-event-tracking-google-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2013 05:20:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/auto-event-tracking-google-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>There is a new version of this post for GTM V2 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/auto-event-tracking-gtm-2-0/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="http://analytics.blogspot.fi/2013/10/the-rundown-new-products-and-features.html">Google Analytics Summit&lt;/a> came and went, and thanks to the Live Stream, everyone could participate. We were treated to a rapid-fire selection of Google Analytics&amp;rsquo; new features, and this post sheds light on one of these in particular: automated event tracking in Google Tag Manager.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Auto-event tracking introduces a nice feature, which does what tag managers ought to do: it provides functionality without HTML template editing. This isn&amp;rsquo;t always a good thing, since automation is usually generic and only works for a couple of viable scenarios, but especially for these generic use cases, this new feature is a great addition to GTM&amp;rsquo;s already impressive feature list.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>