<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Google Analytics Settings on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/google-analytics-settings/</link><description>Recent content in Google Analytics Settings on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 08:39:44 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/google-analytics-settings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#GTMTips: Edit Google Analytics Tag Settings</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/edit-google-analytics-tag-settings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 08:39:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/edit-google-analytics-tag-settings/</guid><description>&lt;p>When the &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-analytics-settings-variable-in-gtm/">Google Analytics Settings variable&lt;/a> was introduced in May 2017, it resulted in a significant change in the &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com/">Google Analytics&lt;/a> tag user interface in &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>. The default UI for editing a tag was stripped down of all GA-specific settings, and the new &lt;strong>Google Analytics Settings&lt;/strong> drop-down was the replacement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, the bulk of Google Tag Manager articles online (including those on this blog) still refer to the old interface in screenshots and instructions. This &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/gtmtips/">#GTMTips&lt;/a> article is a very quick tip to show you how to reveal tag-specific settings without using a Google Analytics Settings variable.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Analytics Settings Variable In GTM</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-analytics-settings-variable-in-gtm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 04:05:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-analytics-settings-variable-in-gtm/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s face it - most of us use &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> for one main purpose: to deploy and configure &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com">Google Analytics&lt;/a> tracking on a website. I&amp;rsquo;d wager that once you start using GTM, you won&amp;rsquo;t be implementing Universal Analytics the old-fashioned way, with on-page code, any more. But running Universal Analytics tags through GTM isn&amp;rsquo;t yet a perfect workflow. We&amp;rsquo;re still missing things like proper &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/universal-analytics-plugins-explained/">plugin&lt;/a> support and the option to properly differentiate between the &lt;em>tracker&lt;/em> and the &lt;em>hit&lt;/em> - both of which are easy to do with an on-page implementation.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>