<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>recaptcha on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/recaptcha/</link>
    <description>Recent content in recaptcha on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 07:00:58 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/recaptcha/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>reCAPTCHA v3 With Google Tag Manager Server-side Tagging</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/recaptcha-v3-server-side-tagging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 07:00:58 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/recaptcha-v3-server-side-tagging/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written about Google&amp;rsquo;s reCAPTCHA v3 before. It&amp;rsquo;s a verification API, which analyzes the signals fed into it and returns a bot score, based on how &amp;ldquo;bot-like&amp;rdquo; the hits are.
It&amp;rsquo;s a great way to validate whether or not to collect data from certain sources that exhibit bot-like behavior. You&amp;rsquo;ll want to ignore those in your analytics tools, for example, as they tend to add a lot of (unrealistic) noise to the data set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve Google Analytics Bot Detection With reCAPTCHA</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/improve-google-analytics-bot-detection-with-recaptcha/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 09:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/improve-google-analytics-bot-detection-with-recaptcha/</guid>
      <description>There are thousands upon thousands of bots, crawlers, spiders, and other creepy-crawlies out there doing nothing but crawling through websites and harvesting the content within for whatever purposes they have been fine-tuned to. While Google Analytics provides a bot filtering feature to filter out &amp;ldquo;spam&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;bot traffic&amp;rdquo; from views, this is far from comprehensive enough to tackle all instances of bot traffic that might enter the site.
  You might have noticed bot traffic in your data even if you have bot filtering toggled on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>