<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>google analytics 4 on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/google-analytics-4/</link>
    <description>Recent content in google analytics 4 on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 07:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/google-analytics-4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Track Core Web Vitals In GA4 With Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-core-web-vitals-in-ga4-with-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-core-web-vitals-in-ga4-with-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>Core Web Vitals is described on the dedicated web.dev resource as (emphasis mine):
 &amp;ldquo;Core Web Vitals are the subset of Web Vitals that apply to all pages, should be measured by all site owners, and will be surfaced across all Google tools.&amp;rdquo;
  Recommended Core Web Vitals thresholds - from https://web.dev/vitals/  The Core Web Vitals measurement as suggested by Google are:
 Largest Contentful Paint (LCP), which measures the time it took to load the largest image or text block in the viewport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Write Client ID And Other GTAG Fields Into dataLayer</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtmtips/write-client-id-other-gtag-fields-datalayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtmtips/write-client-id-other-gtag-fields-datalayer/</guid>
      <description>One of the big omissions, at least for now, in Google Analytics 4 is the customTask. It is unfortunate, but no such mechanism exists in the client-side SDKs.
This means that you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to do all the magical things that customTask enables in Universal Analytics. One of the biggest headaches is how to collect extremely useful fields such as the Client ID, as these are not available by default in the Google Analytics 4 reporting interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementation Guide For Events In Google Analytics 4</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/implementation-guide-events-google-analytics-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 07:00:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/implementation-guide-events-google-analytics-4/</guid>
      <description>On the surface, tracking events in Google Analytics 4 (GA4) is fairly simple. Events are, after all, pretty much the only thing you can collect in GA4.
It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get tied down with endless comparisons to Universal Analytics, though. While I&amp;rsquo;m steadfastly opposed to the idea that GA4 should resemble Universal Analytics, it&amp;rsquo;s still important to cleanse the palate and approach GA4&amp;rsquo;s event tracking with an open mind.
There are some comparisons that can be drawn between the new and the old, but what GA4 might lack in some features and use cases, it more than makes up for this with a more flexible data structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Analytics 4: Ecommerce Guide For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-analytics-4-ecommerce-guide-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-analytics-4-ecommerce-guide-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>This is an implementation guide for Google Analytics 4. The guide is aimed at Google Tag Manager users and has been designed to complement the official documentation.
  A thing to keep in mind is that Google Analytics 4 (GA4) is still very new. The Google Tag Manager integration is still in its infancy, and implementation places a lot of responsibility on accurate tagging and proper dataLayer instrumentation.
In this guide, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain the new data model from an implementation perspective, and walk you through the nuts and bolts on how to get the different parts of GA4&amp;rsquo;s Ecommerce machine to work in unison.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>