<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>google analytics 4 on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/google-analytics-4/</link>
    <description>Recent content in google analytics 4 on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 07:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/google-analytics-4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Track And Categorize All Link Clicks On The Site With Google Analytics 4</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-and-categorize-all-link-clicks-on-the-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-and-categorize-all-link-clicks-on-the-site/</guid>
      <description>This is a guest post by Sebastian Pospischil, Evangelist Digital Analytics at TRKKN. All credit for the solution goes to him. The Summary section is the only one authored by Simo Ahava.
 You know the deal.
Each and every day, clients reach out to you asking for custom click tracking for this call-to-action on that slider, or that button in this section of a page. They reach out to you because such things cannot be answered out of the box in Google Analytics 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Analysis With GA4, BigQuery, R, Sheets, And Data Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/content-analysis-using-ga4-bigquery-r-google-sheets-data-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/content-analysis-using-ga4-bigquery-r-google-sheets-data-studio/</guid>
      <description>This is a guest post – the first one in a long time! The foreword and summary are written by me, Simo, and the rest is by my esteemed guest author.
How fortunate was I to have been contacted by Arben Kqiku, Digital Marketing &amp;amp; Data Manager from comtogether. Arben is one of our many Simmer students, and he&amp;rsquo;s walked through the Query GA4 Data In Google BigQuery course, learning a lot along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Cross-domain Tracking In Google Analytics 4</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/cross-domain-tracking-google-analytics-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/cross-domain-tracking-google-analytics-4/</guid>
      <description>Setting up cross-domain tracking in Google Analytics 4 has been well-documented.
The main departure from Universal Analytics is how cross-domain measurement is something you configure through the Google Analytics user interface rather than through implementation and JavaScript.
While this approach is obviously beneficial especially for those who lack the know-how or the resources to configure the JavaScript trackers, it does lead to problems, too.
In this article, I want to tackle these edge cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track Core Web Vitals In GA4 With Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-core-web-vitals-in-ga4-with-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-core-web-vitals-in-ga4-with-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>Updated 26 May 2021: Added details about the new Namespace Objects option in the template.
 Core Web Vitals is described on the dedicated web.dev resource as (emphasis mine):
 &amp;ldquo;Core Web Vitals are the subset of Web Vitals that apply to all pages, should be measured by all site owners, and will be surfaced across all Google tools.&amp;rdquo;
  Recommended Core Web Vitals thresholds - from https://web.dev/vitals/  The Core Web Vitals measurement as suggested by Google are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Write Client ID And Other GTAG Fields Into dataLayer</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtmtips/write-client-id-other-gtag-fields-datalayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtmtips/write-client-id-other-gtag-fields-datalayer/</guid>
      <description>One of the big omissions, at least for now, in Google Analytics 4 is the customTask. It is unfortunate, but no such mechanism exists in the client-side SDKs.
This means that you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to do all the magical things that customTask enables in Universal Analytics. One of the biggest headaches is how to collect extremely useful fields such as the Client ID, as these are not available by default in the Google Analytics 4 reporting interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementation Guide For Events In Google Analytics 4</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/implementation-guide-events-google-analytics-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 07:00:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/implementation-guide-events-google-analytics-4/</guid>
      <description>On the surface, tracking events in Google Analytics 4 (GA4) is fairly simple. Events are, after all, pretty much the only thing you can collect in GA4.
It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get tied down with endless comparisons to Universal Analytics, though. While I&amp;rsquo;m steadfastly opposed to the idea that GA4 should resemble Universal Analytics, it&amp;rsquo;s still important to cleanse the palate and approach GA4&amp;rsquo;s event tracking with an open mind.
There are some comparisons that can be drawn between the new and the old, but what GA4 might lack in some features and use cases, it more than makes up for this with a more flexible data structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Analytics 4: Ecommerce Guide For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-analytics-4-ecommerce-guide-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-analytics-4-ecommerce-guide-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>Last updated 24 August 2022: The GA4 Event tags in Google Tag Manager have been updated to allow you to load the Ecommerce data directly from the dataLayer (if following the GA4 schema) or from a Custom JavaScript variable (or a custom template), as long as it returns an object in the GA4 ecommerce schema.
 This is an implementation guide for Google Analytics 4. The guide is aimed at Google Tag Manager users and has been designed to complement the official documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>