<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ecommerce on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/ecommerce/</link><description>Recent content in Ecommerce on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 07:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/ecommerce/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Google Analytics 4: Ecommerce Guide For Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-analytics-4-ecommerce-guide-google-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-analytics-4-ecommerce-guide-google-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Last updated 17 March 2023&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/9164320?hl=en#031623">Item-scoped Custom Dimensions&lt;/a> are now available in Google Analytics 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This is an &lt;strong>implementation guide&lt;/strong> for &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/app-web/tag-guide">Google Analytics 4&lt;/a>. The guide is aimed at &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> users and has been designed to complement the &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/tag-manager/ecommerce-appweb">official documentation&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>



&lt;div style="aspect-ratio: 1796 / 922;" class="figure nocaption">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2020/10/app-web-ecommerce.jpg" title="Google Analytics 4 ecommerce">
 
 &lt;img class="fig-img" height="922" width="1796" loading="lazy" src="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2020/10/app-web-ecommerce.jpg#ZgotmplZ" alt="Google Analytics 4 ecommerce">
 
 &lt;/a>
 
 
&lt;/div>


&lt;p>A thing to keep in mind is that Google Analytics 4 (GA4) is &lt;strong>still very new&lt;/strong>. The Google Tag Manager integration is still in its infancy, and implementation places a lot of responsibility on accurate tagging and proper &lt;code>dataLayer&lt;/code> instrumentation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prevent Duplicate Transactions In Google Analytics With customTask</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/prevent-google-analytics-duplicate-transactions-with-customtask/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 10:46:43 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/prevent-google-analytics-duplicate-transactions-with-customtask/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the big problems in &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com/">Google Analytics&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a> data model is the immutability of historical data. Once a row of data is written into the data table, it is there practically for good. This is especially annoying in two cases: &lt;a href="https://help.analyticsedge.com/article/definitive-guide-to-removing-google-analytics-spam/">spam&lt;/a> and bogus ecommerce hits. The first is a recognized issue with an &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/protocol/v1/">open and public data collection protocol&lt;/a>, the latter is an annoyance that can explode into full-blown sabotage (you can use the Measurement Protocol to send hundreds of huge transactions to your competitor&amp;rsquo;s GA property, for example).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Referral Exclusion On Receipt Page</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/referral-exclusion-on-receipt-page/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 07:27:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/referral-exclusion-on-receipt-page/</guid><description>&lt;p>You might have noticed that the &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2795830?hl=en">Referral Exclusion List&lt;/a> in &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com/">Google Analytics&lt;/a> is difficult to maintain. You can&amp;rsquo;t copy a list from one property to another, the list is a wildcard match for domain names (so all subdomains are automatically excluded), and it&amp;rsquo;s just about the clunkiest user interface we&amp;rsquo;ve seen since ERP tools from the 1990s. A while ago, I &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/implement-referral-exclusions-via-gtm/">wrote of a solution&lt;/a> which lets you manage referral exclusions using &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>, and it&amp;rsquo;s still a neat trick, as it&amp;rsquo;s way more flexible than said clunky UI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Track Content With Enhanced Ecommerce</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-content-enhanced-ecommerce/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 12:18:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-content-enhanced-ecommerce/</guid><description>&lt;p>My fingers have been tingling to write this article. Ever since I implemented &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/enhanced-ecommerce">Enhanced Ecommerce&lt;/a> on my blog a couple of weeks ago, I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting such an impressive amount of useful data that it&amp;rsquo;s mind-boggling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through the steps I went to implement the solution, along with examples of the data I can now access through Google Analytics&amp;rsquo; reporting interface. As you might have guessed, if you&amp;rsquo;ve read my articles before, I implemented Enhanced Ecommerce with Google Tag Manager. Note, this is not a step-by-step guide, but should rather provide inspiration for you to think out-of-the-box when it comes to Google Analytics&amp;rsquo; features.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Prevent Repeat Transactions</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/prevent-repeat-transactions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 08:46:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/prevent-repeat-transactions/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this tip, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a look at how to leverage a custom first-party cookie to prevent repeat hits of any kind. This is most useful for transactions, since a &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/26697898/google-analytics-duplicate-transactions">common problem&lt;/a> with &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/">Google Analytics&lt;/a> (traditional) &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/ecommerce">eCommerce tracking&lt;/a> is that a transaction hit is sent again upon subsequent entries to the receipt page, for example using the Back button of the browser. In some cases, and this is not a good practice, a receipt e-mail is sent to the user with a link &lt;em>back to the receipt page&lt;/em>, where the transaction is sent over and over again upon entry.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>eCommerce Tips For Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/ecommerce-tips-google-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 07:10:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/ecommerce-tips-google-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/tagmanager/answer/3002596?hl=en">setting up eCommerce&lt;/a> in &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/tagmanager">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> (and now the new &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/tag-manager/enhanced-ecommerce">Enhanced ecommerce&lt;/a>) is very difficult for many. I&amp;rsquo;m sure part of the problem is that eCommerce is for many users the moment that GTM forces you to take steps in to the developer&amp;rsquo;s domain, since it&amp;rsquo;s obvious that you&amp;rsquo;ll need to add some code to the web page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This isn&amp;rsquo;t a tutorial on how to do eCommerce in Google Tag Manager. To get started, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to check out the official documentation. Sure, it might be inaccurate in places, and especially the translations are lacking, but &lt;code>dataLayer&lt;/code> form and function is nicely described within.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>