<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Search on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/search/</link><description>Recent content in Search on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 07:12:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/search/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#GTMTips: Pagination And Quick Search</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/pagination-and-quick-search/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 07:12:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/pagination-and-quick-search/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you open the &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager user interface&lt;/a> and browser your tags, triggers, and variables, you might notice that the UI now has two new features:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Pagination, where only 50 results are shown per page&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A quick search / filter bar at the top of each list, which lets you narrow the list down to results that match your query&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Pagination&lt;/strong> might be a nuisance in large containers, but it was implemented to improve performance. Fetching the list of assets and rendering them on the screen can be a pretty hefty amount of API work, especially if the container is bloated. By introducing pagination, only 50 items are processed at a time, which speeds up the UI. However, being forced to plow through pages of assets can get tedious.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Track Autocomplete Search In Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/track-autocomplete-search-google-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 07:40:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/track-autocomplete-search-google-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>Autocomplete search is a tricky thing to track. The underlying logic is that when the user starts feeding characters into a search form, the search suggests results based on a limited input. If the user is not satisfied with the results, they can continue adding characters to the search, thus increasing the accuracy. Often there&amp;rsquo;s also the option to revert to a regular search with what they&amp;rsquo;ve already written. Tracking this logic in tools like &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com">Google Analytics&lt;/a> is difficult, because there&amp;rsquo;s really no way to know &lt;em>if the search was successful&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>