<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CMS on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/cms/</link><description>Recent content in CMS on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2013 10:51:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/cms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Website Redesign With SEO And Common Sense</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/seo/website-redesign-with-seo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2013 10:51:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/seo/website-redesign-with-seo/</guid><description>&lt;p>So it&amp;rsquo;s been a while, I know. I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying my summer vacation, either swimming in the lush blue waters of Finland&amp;rsquo;s lakes or in the murky, greenish, (only slightly toxic) chemistry lab reject also known as the Baltic Sea. I&amp;rsquo;ve also had the pleasure of playing golf only to realize I&amp;rsquo;m roughly at the same skill level I was at when I first started.&lt;/p>



&lt;div style="aspect-ratio: 287 / 230;" class="figure nocaption">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2013/07/charles-barkley.gif" title="Charles Barkley golf swing">
 
 &lt;img class="fig-img" height="230" width="287" loading="lazy" src="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2013/07/charles-barkley.gif#ZgotmplZ" alt="Charles Barkley golf swing">
 
 &lt;/a>
 
 
&lt;/div>


&lt;p>I blame the fact I&amp;rsquo;ve played less than ever before due to some unexpected patellofemoral pain in my right knee (yes, I know it&amp;rsquo;s called the Runner&amp;rsquo;s Knee, but if I know words like patellofemoral, I will use them). However, now it&amp;rsquo;s time to OPTIMIZE again! And what better way to start this new season of invigorating blog posts than to tackle one of my favorite subjects: website redesign.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Content Strategy: Know Your Audience</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/seo/content-strategy-know-your-audience/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2013 05:54:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/seo/content-strategy-know-your-audience/</guid><description>&lt;p>For years and years, the one constant in the chaotic world of SEO has been a simple statement: Content is King. This statement has been the cornerstone of content strategy in SEO projects, and its validity has hardly been contested. This is not due to lack of trying. Many posts in the blogosphere have taken an opposing stand (Heidi Cohen: &lt;a href="http://heidicohen.com/blogging-content-is-not-king/">format is king&lt;/a>, Carl Ocab: &lt;a href="http://www.carlocab.com/i-have-a-secret-content-is-not-king/">marketing is king&lt;/a>, Bernadette Coleman: &lt;a href="http://www.seomoz.org/blog/content-isnt-king-trust-is-king">trust is king&lt;/a>). The message of the opposition is this: content cannot be king, as it is only a small part of the audience experience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modern CMS: Top 5 Features</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/content-management/modern-cms-top-5-features/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 15:01:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/content-management/modern-cms-top-5-features/</guid><description>&lt;p>You are right now enjoying the fruits of a very popular content management system, or CMS, whether you know it or not. This blog is published via &lt;a href="http://www.wordpress.org">WordPress&lt;/a>, a modern CMS if there ever was one. In fact, if you add a comment to this post with the form below (hint, hint), you will be participating in content creation, using tools that come out-of-the-box in this particular platform.&lt;/p>



&lt;div style="aspect-ratio: 1214 / 575;" class="figure nocaption">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2013/05/modern-cms-wordpress.jpg" title="WordPress is an example of a modern CMS">
 
 &lt;img class="fig-img" height="575" width="1214" loading="lazy" src="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2013/05/modern-cms-wordpress.jpg#ZgotmplZ" alt="WordPress is an example of a modern CMS">
 
 &lt;/a>
 
 
&lt;/div>


&lt;p>But what makes a modern CMS? Is WordPress the perfect choice for you or your business? Well, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to review the products on the market, so I&amp;rsquo;ll leave the second question to you or your IT manager. However, I will take a stand on the first question, as I look at what makes a modern content management system. What are the must-have features it should boast, and what can you live without? My word is not doctrine, but I do have a long history of working with CMS&amp;rsquo;s and with clients who only want the best.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>