<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Server-Side Tagging on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/server-side-tagging/</link><description>Recent content in Server-Side Tagging on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 07:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/server-side-tagging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#GTMTips: Quickly Duplicate Tags In Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtmtips/quickly-duplicate-tags-google-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtmtips/quickly-duplicate-tags-google-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are many reasons why you might want to duplicate your tags (or triggers, or variables, or templates) in Google Tag Manager.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One prime example is &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">server-side tagging&lt;/a>, where it&amp;rsquo;s sensible to first build and validate your tracking setup before migrating fully to a server-side approach.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alternatively, you might want to collect analytics data to a second property, for example when you want to have a local &lt;em>and&lt;/em> a global dataset for site visit data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Automatic Page View Hits In SGTM After Consent Granted</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtmtips/automatic-page-view-hits-to-sgtm-after-consent-granted/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtmtips/automatic-page-view-hits-to-sgtm-after-consent-granted/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re using &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/tag-platform/tag-manager/server-side">server-side Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/consent-mode-v2-google-tags/">Google (Advanced) Consent Mode&lt;/a> and you&amp;rsquo;re collecting hits to Google Analytics 4, you might have noticed something odd happening when switching consent to &lt;code>granted&lt;/code> state.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It looks as if your &lt;code>page_view&lt;/code> hits as well as any other hits marked as &amp;ldquo;Conversions&amp;rdquo; (or &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/13965727">key events&lt;/a> now, I guess) are &lt;strong>automatically redispatched&lt;/strong> to the server-side Google Tag Manager endpoint when consent is granted!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This sounds incredibly useful. You no longer need to reconfigure the dispatch of important events after consent is granted.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cloud Run With Server-side Tagging In Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/cloud-run-server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 07:37:11 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/cloud-run-server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>In a recent update to &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/tag-platform/tag-manager/server-side/overview">server-side tagging in Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>, Google switched the &lt;strong>default&lt;/strong> deployment of a server-side tagging backend from &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/tag-platform/tag-manager/server-side/app-engine-setup">Google App Engine&lt;/a> to &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/tag-platform/tag-manager/server-side/cloud-run-setup-guide">Google Cloud Run&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, when you create a new container and choose the &lt;strong>automatically provisioned tagging server&lt;/strong> option, this service will be created in Google Cloud Run instead of in Google App Engine.&lt;/p>



&lt;div style="aspect-ratio: 1468 / 712;" class="figure nocaption">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2023/10/cloud-run-auto-provision.jpg" title="Cloud Run automatic provisioning">
 
 &lt;img class="fig-img" height="712" width="1468" loading="lazy" src="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2023/10/cloud-run-auto-provision.jpg#ZgotmplZ" alt="Cloud Run automatic provisioning">
 
 &lt;/a>
 
 
&lt;/div>


&lt;p>While I&amp;rsquo;ve written &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/gtmtips/setup-google-tag-manager-server-cloud-run/">about Cloud Run before&lt;/a>, this update gives me an opportunity to review what actually happens when you provision a Cloud Run environment, how you can upgrade it, and how you can add enhancements such as &lt;strong>multi-region load balancing&lt;/strong> to it (with ease, I might add!).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Transformations In Server-side Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/transformations-server-side-google-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 07:09:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/transformations-server-side-google-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>In January 2020, when &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/tag-platform/tag-manager/server-side">Google Tag Manager&amp;rsquo;s server-side tagging&lt;/a> was first introduced to the general public at &lt;a href="https://www.superweek.hu">SuperWeek&lt;/a>, I wrote a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SimoAhava/status/1222459714614841346">flurry of tweets&lt;/a>, sharing my vision of a server-side tagging future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In one of the tweets, I discussed how you could do these:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Hit validation and fixing before the hit is sent to the endpoint&lt;/li>
&lt;li>PII and privacy controls for the requests before dispatch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>



&lt;div style="aspect-ratio: 1084 / 538;" class="figure nocaption">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2023/04/simo-twitter.jpg" title="Tweet about server-side tagging">
 
 &lt;img class="fig-img" height="538" width="1084" loading="lazy" src="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2023/04/simo-twitter.jpg#ZgotmplZ" alt="Tweet about server-side tagging">
 
 &lt;/a>
 
 
&lt;/div>


&lt;p>Fast forward to today, over three years later, and we are &lt;em>finally&lt;/em> treated to a feature that grants us scalable controls to properly interrupt data flows within server-side GTM.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Prevent SGTM From Setting The FPID Cookie</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/prevent-sgtm-from-setting-fpid-cookie/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 07:47:46 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/prevent-sgtm-from-setting-fpid-cookie/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/fpid-cookie-google-analytics-server-side-tagging/">&lt;code>FPID&lt;/code> cookie&lt;/a> is what &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">server-side Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> would prefer to use for your &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/tag-platform/tag-manager/server-side/send-data">Google Analytics 4&lt;/a> tracking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a cookie set in the &lt;strong>HTTP response&lt;/strong> from the server, and it&amp;rsquo;s flagged as &lt;code>HttpOnly&lt;/code>, which means it&amp;rsquo;s only accessible by a web server running on the domain on which it was set.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with the technology, and I do recommend that server-side setups toggle it on by default.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, there might be cases where you want the server-side &lt;strong>GA4 client&lt;/strong> (which handles the incoming GA4 requests) to occasionally &lt;em>not&lt;/em> use the &lt;code>FPID&lt;/code> cookie. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s because you have a custom consent system in place, or perhaps you want some GA4 measurement IDs to use the regular JavaScript cookies and others to use the &lt;code>FPID&lt;/code>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Override Google Analytics 4 Fields In Server-Side GTM</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/override-ga4-fields-in-server-side-gtm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 06:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/override-ga4-fields-in-server-side-gtm/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">Server-side tagging&lt;/a> is all about &lt;em>control&lt;/em>. Being able to intercept, modify, and even block requests as they come in &lt;em>before&lt;/em> they are dispatched to their actual endpoints is extremely valuable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The built-in &lt;strong>Google Analytics 4&lt;/strong> tag template has options for modifying event parameters and user properties in the Google Analytics 4 request, but did you know you can use these options to modify some of the &lt;strong>fields&lt;/strong> as well, such as Client ID, User ID, and event Engagement Time?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Agency, Transparency, And Control: Unsolved Problems With Server-side Tagging</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/agency-transparency-control-unsolved-problems-server-side-tagging/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/agency-transparency-control-unsolved-problems-server-side-tagging/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have been a strong supporter of &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/#server-side-tagging-list">server-side tagging&lt;/a>, in particular Google&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/tag-platform/tag-manager/server-side">server-side tag management solution&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I admire the way it seeks to readjust the balance of &lt;strong>control&lt;/strong> that typically has been in favor of the marketing vendors whose &lt;strong>JavaScript libraries&lt;/strong> have been free to wreak havoc in the user&amp;rsquo;s browser.&lt;/p>



&lt;div style="aspect-ratio: 842 / 596;" class="figure nocaption">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2022/10/regular-vs-server-tagging.jpg" title="Regular vs server-side tagging">
 
 &lt;img class="fig-img" height="596" width="842" loading="lazy" src="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2022/10/regular-vs-server-tagging.jpg#ZgotmplZ" alt="Regular vs server-side tagging">
 
 &lt;/a>
 
 
&lt;/div>


&lt;p>By inserting a &lt;em>buffer&lt;/em> between the user and the vendor, the owner of the server-side tagging setup can &lt;strong>take control&lt;/strong> over what data the marketing vendors can actually process of the user.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Preflight Requests in Server-side Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/preflight-requests-in-server-side-google-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/preflight-requests-in-server-side-google-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>With certain types of &lt;strong>HTTP requests&lt;/strong>, the web browser might first dispatch a request with the &lt;strong>OPTIONS&lt;/strong> method, also known as a &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Glossary/Preflight_request">preflight request&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose of the preflight request is to &amp;ldquo;check&amp;rdquo; with the web server that it&amp;rsquo;s equipped to handle the type of cross-origin request the browser wants to dispatch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the server doesn&amp;rsquo;t handle this preflight request, or if it returns a response that doesn&amp;rsquo;t agree with what the web browser wants to actually dispatch, the check fails and the browser refuses to send the actual request.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Preview Requests In Server-side Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtmtips/preview-server-side-google-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtmtips/preview-server-side-google-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">Server-side Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> has an &lt;em>excellent&lt;/em> &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/tag-platform/tag-manager/server-side/debug">Preview mode&lt;/a>, which lets you &lt;strong>inspect incoming requests&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>monitor the event data object&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>view console messages&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>identify outgoing requests&lt;/strong>, among other things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To enable this Preview mode on the web, you simply need to click the &lt;strong>Preview&lt;/strong> button in the container, after which any requests sent from the &lt;strong>same browser instance&lt;/strong> will be automatically shown in the Preview mode window.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, what about if you want to send requests from another browser? Or from a non-browser data source? Or what if you want to play with &lt;strong>XHR&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Fetch&lt;/strong> without having access to cookie credentials?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Setup IAM For Manual Installation Of Server-side GTM</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtmtips/setup-iam-manual-installation-server-side-gtm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 07:00:01 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtmtips/setup-iam-manual-installation-server-side-gtm/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you want to &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/provision-server-side-tagging-application-manually/">manually install server-side Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> on App Engine in the Google Cloud Platform, you are of course welcome to do so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main benefits of doing this are that you get to &lt;strong>choose the region where App Engine is deployed&lt;/strong> and that you can use &lt;strong>existing project resources&lt;/strong> instead of having a new project automatically created for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, to run the script without errors, there are a number of things you need to enable first. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through the required permissions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Enrich Server-side Data With Cloud Firestore</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enrich-server-side-data-with-cloud-firestore/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 07:00:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enrich-server-side-data-with-cloud-firestore/</guid><description>&lt;p>With &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/asynchronous-variables-server-side-google-tag-manager/">asynchronous variables&lt;/a> recently released in &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/tag-platform/tag-manager/server-side">server-side Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>, it&amp;rsquo;s time to dig into &lt;strong>data enrichment flows&lt;/strong> using &lt;em>another&lt;/em> release from the Google team.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>* drum roll *&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have a new Google Cloud Platform API!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s fast. It&amp;rsquo;s sleek. It&amp;rsquo;s beautiful. It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Firestore&lt;/strong>!&lt;/p>



&lt;div style="aspect-ratio: 2140 / 554;" class="figure nocaption">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2022/02/cloud-firestore.jpg" title="Firestore">
 
 &lt;img class="fig-img" height="554" width="2140" loading="lazy" src="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2022/02/cloud-firestore.jpg#ZgotmplZ" alt="Firestore">
 
 &lt;/a>
 
 
&lt;/div>


&lt;p>Firestore is a &lt;strong>NoSQL&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>transactional&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>scalable&lt;/strong> database that offers near-real-time write/read and sync operations for data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In practice, it&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;em>great&lt;/em> way to enrich and widen the data that you pass through your Server container.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Asynchronous Variables In Server-side Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/asynchronous-variables-server-side-google-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 07:00:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/asynchronous-variables-server-side-google-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>OK, that&amp;rsquo;s one unappealing title for a blog post, but rest assured that the content more than makes up for this obscurity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, my favorite toy in the world, &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/tag-platform/tag-manager/server-side">Google Tag Manager&amp;rsquo;s server container&lt;/a>, introduced the capability to handle &lt;strong>asynchronous operations&lt;/strong> in variables.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is done through a JavaScript interface known as &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Global_Objects/Promise">Promise&lt;/a>. A &lt;strong>Promise&lt;/strong> is a way to run code in JavaScript without knowing what its eventual value will be. The &amp;ldquo;promise&amp;rdquo; part of this concept means that the code &lt;em>promises&lt;/em> that it will reach a value eventually, so other code that relies on this value can execute accordingly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Setup A Google Tag Manager Server Using Cloud Run</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtmtips/setup-google-tag-manager-server-cloud-run/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtmtips/setup-google-tag-manager-server-cloud-run/</guid><description>&lt;p>While &lt;strong>Google App Engine&lt;/strong>, the default implementation pattern of &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">server-side Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>, is straightforward to setup with the &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/tag-platform/tag-manager/server-side#set_up_a_gcp_tagging_server">automatic provisioning steps&lt;/a>, it&amp;rsquo;s certainly not the only way to deploy the server.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/deploy-server-side-google-tag-manager-aws/">You can set it up in Amazon AWS&lt;/a> (this blog)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-azure-app-service/">You can set it up in Microsoft Azure&lt;/a> (this blog)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://code.markedmondson.me/gtm-serverside-cloudrun/">You can set it up with Cloud Run&lt;/a> (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/holomarked">Mark Edmondson&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a> blog)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>In fact, the &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/tag-platform/tag-manager/server-side/manual-setup-guide">manual setup guide&lt;/a> gives you the details on how to deploy a Google Tag Manager Server in &lt;em>any&lt;/em> environment that runs Docker.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Manipulate Response Headers In Server-side Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/manipulate-response-headers-server-side-google-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 07:00:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/manipulate-response-headers-server-side-google-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>Although &lt;em>most&lt;/em> of &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">Server-side Tagging in Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> revolves, quite rightfully, around &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/tag-platform/tag-manager/server-side/intro#how_clients_work">&lt;strong>Clients&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, there&amp;rsquo;s still plenty of value to be derived from &lt;strong>tags&lt;/strong>, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Naturally, the most common use case for server-side tags is to map the incoming requests to the Server container (filtered through Clients) and dispatch them to their respective endpoints.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But in addition to dispatching HTTP requests, tags can do &lt;em>so much&lt;/em> more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll share with you a neat way how to utilize tags to manipulate the &lt;strong>HTTP responses&lt;/strong> the Server container sends back to the request source.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Server-side Tagging With Azure App Service</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-azure-app-service/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-azure-app-service/</guid><description>&lt;p>To continue my extensive collection of &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/server-side-tagging/">server-side tagging articles&lt;/a>, in this guide I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through how to set up a Server container in &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/app-service/">Microsoft Azure&amp;rsquo;s App Service&lt;/a> platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For my previous guides on manually provisioning a Server container, follow these links:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Amazon AWS (Elastic Beanstalk): &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/deploy-server-side-google-tag-manager-aws/">Deploy Server-side Google Tag Manager In AWS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Google Cloud (App Engine): &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/provision-server-side-tagging-application-manually/">Provision Server-side Tagging Application Manually&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Azure&amp;rsquo;s App Service is similar to AWS Elastic Beanstalk and GCP App Engine, in that it lets you create a web application from scratch with minimal effort.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Measure Ad Blocker Impact With Server-side GTM</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/measure-ad-blocker-impact-server-side-gtm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 09:10:11 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/measure-ad-blocker-impact-server-side-gtm/</guid><description>&lt;p>For many, it seems, one of the most important justifications for &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">server-side Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> is its resilience to &lt;strong>ad and content blockers&lt;/strong>. After all, by virtue of serving the container JavaScript &lt;em>from your own domain&lt;/em>, you escape many of the heuristic devices today&amp;rsquo;s blocker technologies employ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve gone on record over and over again to say how this is &lt;strong>poor justification&lt;/strong> for using server-side GTM. By circumventing the user&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>wish&lt;/em> to block scripts, you are disrespecting them and forcing their browser to download scripts that they wanted to avoid downloading in the first place.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Google Ads Remarketing In GTM Server Containers</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/google-ads-remarketing-gtm-server-containers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 07:22:22 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/google-ads-remarketing-gtm-server-containers/</guid><description>&lt;p>Google has released the &lt;strong>Google Ads Remarketing&lt;/strong> tag for &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">server-side tagging in Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Functionally, it&amp;rsquo;s remarkably similar to the &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-ads-server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">Conversion Tracking tag&lt;/a> they released previously. In fact, you should go ahead and read that article first, so that you have an understanding of how Google Ads tracking works through Server containers!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Follow &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/tag-manager/serverside/ads-remarketing-setup">this link&lt;/a> to read the official documentation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through how to set things up, and I&amp;rsquo;ll also provide an overview of &lt;strong>how it works&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Cross-domain Tracking With Server-side FPID Cookie</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/cross-domain-tracking-server-side-fpid-cookie/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/cross-domain-tracking-server-side-fpid-cookie/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;strong>FPID cookie&lt;/strong> in &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">server-side tagging&lt;/a> for &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> is an &lt;code>HttpOnly&lt;/code>, &lt;strong>server-managed&lt;/strong> ID cookie that&amp;rsquo;s designed to replace the &lt;em>JavaScript-managed&lt;/em> &lt;code>_ga&lt;/code> cookie used by Google Analytics 4 and Universal Analytics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more details about the cookie itself, check out my &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/fpid-cookie-google-analytics-server-side-tagging/">previous article on FPID&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In that article, I mentioned one caveat for adopting FPID being the fact that &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/10071811?hl=en">cross-domain tracking&lt;/a> will not work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I mean, how could it? FPID is an &lt;code>HttpOnly&lt;/code> cookie, which means it&amp;rsquo;s not available to JavaScript in the browser. Cross-domain tracking, on the other hand, decorates links dynamically as users click them, which means it needs the cookie to be available via JavaScript so that it could be decorated into the target page URL.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Ads Conversion Tracking With Server-side Tagging In Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-ads-server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-ads-server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the biggest blockers for &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">server-side tagging&lt;/a> to slip out of &lt;em>beta&lt;/em> is &lt;strong>Google Ads&lt;/strong>. Until server-side tagging supports a solution for both &lt;strong>conversions&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>remarketing&lt;/strong> capabilities to be reproduced server-side, it&amp;rsquo;s unlikely that Server containers will lose their beta label.&lt;/p>



&lt;div style="aspect-ratio: 1104 / 678;" class="figure nocaption">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2021/07/google-ads-server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager.jpg" title="google-ads-server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager.jpg">
 
 &lt;img class="fig-img" height="678" width="1104" loading="lazy" src="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2021/07/google-ads-server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager.jpg#ZgotmplZ" alt="google-ads-server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager.jpg">
 
 &lt;/a>
 
 
&lt;/div>


&lt;p>While I can&amp;rsquo;t say what will happen to the beta label now, the fact is that Google Tag Manager &lt;strong>has now released support for Conversion tracking&lt;/strong> using server-side tagging.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploy Server-side Google Tag Manager In AWS</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/deploy-server-side-google-tag-manager-aws/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/deploy-server-side-google-tag-manager-aws/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since Google Tag Manager released the &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/tag-manager/serverside/manual-setup-guide">manual setup guide&lt;/a> for &lt;a href="server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager">server-side tagging&lt;/a>, my mind has been spinning with the idea of walking through the deployment into Amazon&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/">AWS&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I personally prefer &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/">Google Cloud Platform&lt;/a> over AWS, because I think it&amp;rsquo;s so much more user-friendly. Even though in this guide we&amp;rsquo;ll be utilizing one of the simplest AWS services, &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/elasticbeanstalk/">Elastic Beanstalk&lt;/a>, the deployment is still &lt;em>much&lt;/em> more complex than if you were to use GCP&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/appengine">App Engine&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Custom GTM Loader For Server-side Tagging</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/custom-gtm-loader-server-side-tagging/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 07:11:32 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/custom-gtm-loader-server-side-tagging/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Important!&lt;/strong> I really do &lt;em>not&lt;/em> recommend using this in production. The only proper way of loading Google scripts from server-side Google Tag Manager containers is to use the official &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/gtmtips/new-way-load-google-scripts-server-container/">Web Container Client&lt;/a>. This template was introduced at a time when the script loading mechanism in server-side Google Tag Manager wasn&amp;rsquo;t as complex as it was today, and I also noticed that most people use templates like these to avoid ad blockers, which is &lt;strong>not something I condone&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>reCAPTCHA v3 With Google Tag Manager Server-side Tagging</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/recaptcha-v3-server-side-tagging/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 07:00:58 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/recaptcha-v3-server-side-tagging/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve written about Google&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/improve-google-analytics-bot-detection-with-recaptcha/">reCAPTCHA v3&lt;/a> before. It&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;em>verification API&lt;/em>, which analyzes the signals fed into it and returns a &lt;strong>bot score&lt;/strong>, based on how &amp;ldquo;bot-like&amp;rdquo; the hits are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a great way to validate whether or not to collect data from certain sources that exhibit bot-like behavior. You&amp;rsquo;ll want to ignore those in your analytics tools, for example, as they tend to add a lot of (unrealistic) noise to the data set.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Provision Server-side Tagging Application Manually</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/provision-server-side-tagging-application-manually/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 07:48:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/provision-server-side-tagging-application-manually/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/tag-manager/serverside#create_a_google_cloud_platform_gcp_server">automatic provisioning process&lt;/a> of the &lt;strong>Google Tag Manager server-side tagging service&lt;/strong> is extremely useful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With just a few clicks of the button, you can have a fully functional (albeit limited to testing use) server-side tagging endpoint on the Google Cloud Platform (GCP).&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>For a video overview of the automatic deployment, see &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6OGbOh216mU">this video&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>However, the automatic provisioning process creates &lt;strong>a new Google Cloud Platform project&lt;/strong> and, at the time of writing, always deploys the App Engine application (on which the tagging server runs) in the &lt;code>us-central-1&lt;/code> GCP region.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: The URL Parser Variable Template For Server Containers</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/url-parser-variable-template-server-containers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 07:25:12 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/url-parser-variable-template-server-containers/</guid><description>&lt;p>With &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">server-side tagging&lt;/a>, you can send any types of HTTP requests to the Server container. The Server container parses these, fires up container instances, and sends the data onwards to first-party data stores and third-party vendors alike.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Often these requests contain URL strings encoded in query parameters. A prime example is the &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/protocol/v1/parameters#dl">document location&lt;/a> parameter in Universal Analytics requests.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Server-side &lt;strong>Clients&lt;/strong> would parse these URL strings and convert them into the format required by the &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/tag-manager/serverside/common-event-data">event data object&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Facebook Conversions API Using GA4 Web Tags And A GTM Server</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/facebook-conversions-api-gtm-server-side-tagging/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 07:42:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/facebook-conversions-api-gtm-server-side-tagging/</guid><description>&lt;p>Facebook has now &lt;strong>officially&lt;/strong> released their &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/business/help/702509907046774">&lt;strong>Conversions API tag template&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> for &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">server-side tagging in Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this tag template, you can create a server-side tag that fires with any &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/#clients-and-tags">Client&lt;/a> designed to parse requests into a &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/#event-model">unified event model&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>



&lt;div style="aspect-ratio: 1802 / 1192;" class="figure nocaption">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2021/03/facebook-conversions-api-tag.jpg" title="Facebook Conversions API Tag">
 
 &lt;img class="fig-img" height="1192" width="1802" loading="lazy" src="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2021/03/facebook-conversions-api-tag.jpg#ZgotmplZ" alt="Facebook Conversions API Tag">
 
 &lt;/a>
 
 
&lt;/div>


&lt;p>One such Client already exists, and every single Server container has it built-in: the &lt;strong>GA4 Client&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet deployed a Server container, check out &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/6OGbOh216mU">this video walkthrough&lt;/a> for more details on how to do it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Map Multiple Domains To A Server-side Tagging Endpoint</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/map-multiple-domains-server-side-tagging-endpoint/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 14:38:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/map-multiple-domains-server-side-tagging-endpoint/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the biggest perks of working with &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">server-side tagging&lt;/a> is that you can establish a &lt;strong>first-party context&lt;/strong> between the site sending the data and the server-side tagging endpoint itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This leads to &lt;em>many&lt;/em> benefits, including improved control of the &lt;strong>data streams&lt;/strong>, the possibility to &lt;strong>set cookies&lt;/strong> that extend beyond &lt;a href="https://www.cookiestatus.com/safari/#first-party-cookies">ITP&amp;rsquo;s restrictions&lt;/a>, and reduced stress on an already very likely overloaded &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/CSP">&lt;strong>Content Security Policy&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to map multiple custom domains to your Google Cloud Project application. I&amp;rsquo;ll also show you how to configure the container to support previewing all these different domains.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Write To Google BigQuery From A GTM Server Container</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/write-to-google-bigquery-from-gtm-server-container/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 09:57:51 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/write-to-google-bigquery-from-gtm-server-container/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ever since it was released that &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">server-side tagging in Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> would run on the &lt;strong>Google Cloud Platform&lt;/strong> stack, my imagination has been running wild.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By running on GCP, the potential for integrations with &lt;em>other&lt;/em> GCP components is limitless. The output to &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/tips-for-logging-server-side-tagging/">Cloud Logging&lt;/a> already introduces interesting pipeline opportunities, but now it gets even better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It&amp;rsquo;s finally possible to write directly to Google BigQuery from a &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/tag-manager/serverside/api">Client or tag template&lt;/a>!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>



&lt;div style="aspect-ratio: 1202 / 452;" class="figure nocaption">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2021/03/bigquery-in-template.jpg" title="BigQuery in a custom template">
 
 &lt;img class="fig-img" height="452" width="1202" loading="lazy" src="https://www.simoahava.com/images/2021/03/bigquery-in-template.jpg#ZgotmplZ" alt="BigQuery in a custom template">
 
 &lt;/a>
 
 
&lt;/div>


&lt;p>This means that instead of treating server-side tagging as a &amp;ldquo;simple&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong>proxy&lt;/strong>, whose purpose is mainly to replace data streams that would otherwise connect a client directly with an endpoint, it&amp;rsquo;s now possible to use a Server container as a data collection machine itself.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Tips For Logging In Server-side Tagging</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/tips-for-logging-server-side-tagging/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/tips-for-logging-server-side-tagging/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the &lt;strong>largest&lt;/strong> costs in a &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">server-side tagging&lt;/a> can be &lt;strong>logging&lt;/strong>. Google warns about this in their &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/tag-manager/serverside/script-user-guide#disable_app_engine_request_logging_optional">official documentation&lt;/a>, and it&amp;rsquo;s definitely something to keep a keen eye on if your server-side endpoint processes enough data per month.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How much should it process for logging to become an issue? It depends, but you could start seeing some impact once the endpoint processes &amp;gt;1 million incoming requests per month. The best way to find out if logging is a problem is to visit the &lt;strong>Billing&lt;/strong> dashboard in your server-side tagging Google Cloud project and check what the portion of &lt;strong>Log Volume&lt;/strong> is in your monthly costs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New Google Tag Manager Web Container Client For Server Side Tagging</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-web-container-client-server-side-tagging/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 07:22:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-web-container-client-server-side-tagging/</guid><description>&lt;p>With the introduction of &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">server-side tagging&lt;/a> in &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>, the variety of things you can do with your own server-side &lt;strong>proxy&lt;/strong> is mind-boggling:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Reduce &lt;strong>client-side bloat&lt;/strong> by consolidating data streams and distributing them to vendor endpoints server-side.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Improve &lt;strong>data security&lt;/strong> by adding safeguards and validations to prevent harmful data from being sent to vendor endpoints.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enrich&lt;/strong> data server-side, by combining the incoming data stream with data from APIs and data stores that you own and control.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove &lt;strong>third-party&lt;/strong> downloads from the browser by proxying them via the server-side container.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This last point is what this article expands on. If you check out &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/_c4JEfSkP6U?t=1515">this video (jumps straight to the relevant part)&lt;/a>, you can see how it&amp;rsquo;s possible to already proxy popular libraries like &lt;strong>analytics.js&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>gtag.js&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Utilize App Engine Headers In Server-side Tagging</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/utilize-app-engine-headers-server-side-tagging/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 09:00:17 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/utilize-app-engine-headers-server-side-tagging/</guid><description>&lt;p>When you create a &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">Server container&lt;/a> in &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>, GTM creates an &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/appengine">App Engine&lt;/a> deployment in the Google Cloud Platform for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>App Engine is a &lt;strong>managed serverless platform&lt;/strong>, which basically means it&amp;rsquo;s a (set of) virtual machine(s) running in the cloud, with some extra bells and whistles added to make managing it easier.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A potentially useful thing that App Engine does is decorate all incoming HTTP requests with some HTTP headers that can be used in the app. These headers include &lt;strong>geolocation&lt;/strong> headers, based on the IP address of the machine that sent the hits.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Get True IP Anonymization With Server-side Tagging</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/get-true-ip-anonymization-server-side-tagging/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 09:52:51 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/get-true-ip-anonymization-server-side-tagging/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since the &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">release of Server-side tagging&lt;/a> in &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>, I&amp;rsquo;ve jumped at every opportunity to celebrate the tools it provides for improving end-user privacy and data security.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the biggest benefits is obfuscation-by-default. Since all hits are passed through the server-side proxy, the default view for any third-party tool (such as Google Analytics) is that of the server in the Google Cloud rather than the browser and device with which the user was browsing the site.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The FPID Cookie For Google Analytics In Server-side Tagging</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/fpid-cookie-google-analytics-server-side-tagging/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 07:04:01 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/fpid-cookie-google-analytics-server-side-tagging/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Last updated 27 April 2023 with details about preventing FPID access in cookieless scenarios.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>With &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">Server-side tagging&lt;/a>, the developer community has a chance to vastly improve the data collection capabilities of Google&amp;rsquo;s analytics platforms (&lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2790010">Universal Analytics&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/9306384">App+Web&lt;/a>). The ability to build &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/build-custom-universal-analytics-client-server-side-tagging/">our own templates&lt;/a> is particularly potent with a Server container.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, it&amp;rsquo;s not as if Google themselves are just sitting idly by and seeing what the community can come up with.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Build A Custom Universal Analytics Client For Server-side Tagging</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/build-custom-universal-analytics-client-server-side-tagging/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 07:03:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/build-custom-universal-analytics-client-server-side-tagging/</guid><description>&lt;p>You can utilize &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/">&lt;em>Server-side tagging&lt;/em>&lt;/a> in &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> to build your own custom Universal Analytics proxy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This proxy comes in the shape of a new &lt;strong>Client&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/custom-templates-guide-for-google-tag-manager/">custom template&lt;/a>, which takes the incoming &lt;code>/collect&lt;/code> requests and sends them to Google Analytics. While doing so, it also returns the &lt;code>_ga&lt;/code> cookie in a &lt;code>Set-Cookie&lt;/code> header, thus preventing Safari&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://www.cookiestatus.com/safari/">Intelligent Tracking Prevention&lt;/a> from capping its expiration to just 7 days.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>You might also be interested in reading what &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/fpid-cookie-google-analytics-server-side-tagging/">Google&amp;rsquo;s own solution&lt;/a> is for migrating from JavaScript cookies to those set in HTTP headers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Send Google Analytics Requests To Custom Endpoint</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/send-google-analytics-requests-custom-endpoint/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 07:01:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/send-google-analytics-requests-custom-endpoint/</guid><description>&lt;p>When you use &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com/">Google Analytics&lt;/a> on the web, you are most likely implementing one of &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs">analytics.js&lt;/a>, the &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/gtagjs">global site tag (gtag.js)&lt;/a>, or Universal Analytics tags via &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These libraries all end up doing the same thing: compiling a payload-rich HTTP request to an endpoint at &lt;code>https://www.google-analytics.com&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What if you want to have the JavaScript libraries do their job, but instead of sending the data to Google&amp;rsquo;s servers, you send them to a new, custom endpoint?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Server-side Tagging In Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ever since &lt;strong>Server-side tagging&lt;/strong> was &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SimoAhava/status/1222459714614841346?s=20">publicly announced&lt;/a> at &lt;a href="https://superweek.hu/">SUPERWEEK 2020&lt;/a>, Google and the trusted tester community have been hard at work, building something that just might change the landscape of digital analytics for good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> has now released Server-side tagging into &lt;strong>public beta&lt;/strong>. In this lengthy article, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a look at what Server-side tagging is, how it should (and should not) be used, and what its implications are on the broader digital analytics community.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>