<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>server-side tagging on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/server-side-tagging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in server-side tagging on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 07:04:01 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/server-side-tagging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The FPID Cookie For Google Analytics In Server-side Tagging</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/fpid-cookie-google-analytics-server-side-tagging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 07:04:01 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/fpid-cookie-google-analytics-server-side-tagging/</guid>
      <description>With Server-side tagging, the developer community has a chance to vastly improve the data collection capabilities of Google&amp;rsquo;s analytics platforms (Universal Analytics and App+Web). The ability to build our own templates is particularly potent with a Server container.
However, it&amp;rsquo;s not as if Google themselves are just sitting idly by and seeing what the community can come up with.
In the built-in Universal Analytics Client template in a Server container, there&amp;rsquo;s an option to migrate to a Server Managed Client ID.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Build A Custom Universal Analytics Client For Server-side Tagging</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/build-custom-universal-analytics-client-server-side-tagging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 07:03:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/build-custom-universal-analytics-client-server-side-tagging/</guid>
      <description>You can utilize Server-side tagging in Google Tag Manager to build your own custom Universal Analytics proxy.
This proxy comes in the shape of a new Client custom template, which takes the incoming /collect requests and sends them to Google Analytics. While doing so, it also returns the _ga cookie in a Set-Cookie header, thus preventing Safari&amp;rsquo;s Intelligent Tracking Prevention from capping its expiration to just 7 days.
 You might also be interested in reading what Google&amp;rsquo;s own solution is for migrating from JavaScript cookies to those set in HTTP headers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Send Google Analytics Requests To Custom Endpoint</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/send-google-analytics-requests-custom-endpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 07:01:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/send-google-analytics-requests-custom-endpoint/</guid>
      <description>When you use Google Analytics on the web, you are most likely implementing one of analytics.js, the global site tag (gtag.js), or Universal Analytics tags via Google Tag Manager.
These libraries all end up doing the same thing: compiling a payload-rich HTTP request to an endpoint at https://www.google-analytics.com.
What if you want to have the JavaScript libraries do their job, but instead of sending the data to Google&amp;rsquo;s servers, you send them to a new, custom endpoint?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server-side Tagging In Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/server-side-tagging-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>Ever since Server-side tagging was publicly announced at SUPERWEEK 2020, Google and the trusted tester community have been hard at work, building something that just might change the landscape of digital analytics for good.
Google Tag Manager has now released Server-side tagging into public beta. In this lengthy article, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a look at what Server-side tagging is, how it should (and should not) be used, and what its implications are on the broader digital analytics community.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>