<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tools on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 16:15:24 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Introducing The customTask Builder</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/introducing-customtask-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 16:15:24 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/introducing-customtask-builder/</guid>
      <description>One of the coolest features about Google Analytics and, as a consequence, Google Tag Manager is customTask. It&amp;rsquo;s a method you can use to add and execute code as the hit to Google Analytics is being generated.
I&amp;rsquo;ve written A LOT about customTask, and much of the feedback I&amp;rsquo;ve received has been around the question of how to combine all these different tricks into one customTask script. The problem is, you see, that a tag or hit can only have one customTask script attached to it, so the code within must combine all the different tricks I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing about over the past months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RELEASE: GTM Tools V2.0</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/release-gtm-tools-v2-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 17:50:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/release-gtm-tools-v2-0/</guid>
      <description>(UPDATE 3 Apr 2017: There is a newer version of GTM Tools out, so please ignore this article and read this one instead.)
So, the time has come to update my GTM Tools. I released the first toolset in October 2014, and it performed its duties just well enough. Sure, the UI was ugly as hell, and there were bugs along the way, but for cloning containers, macros, and rules, and for visualizing containers, it was just good enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Container Visualizer for Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/container-visualizer-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 14:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/container-visualizer-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>[UPDATE:] Quite a lot of people had trouble accessing the tool after I published this post. This should now be fixed.
So, AWESOME stuff. The new Google Tag Manager UI and API have just rolled out, and I can finally start revealing the stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on :)
I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go into the new UI in this post. I just want to give a huge thanks to the GTM team for working on the UX with such dedication.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>