<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scroll Depth on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/scroll-depth/</link><description>Recent content in Scroll Depth on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 09:16:15 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/scroll-depth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fire GTM Tag Upon Scroll Depth And Time Spent</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/fire-tag-upon-scroll-depth-and-time-spent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 09:16:15 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/fire-tag-upon-scroll-depth-and-time-spent/</guid><description>&lt;p>Over 5 years ago, I wrote an article titled &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-adjusted-bounce-rate-universal-analytics/">Track Adjusted Bounce Rate In Universal Analytics&lt;/a>. It basically explored a number of different methods to tweak the Bounce Rate metric so that it becomes more meaningful in your &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com/">Google Analytics&lt;/a> reports.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, writing that article wasn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily my proudest moment. It&amp;rsquo;s not because the solution was poor, but rather because I was suggesting it makes sense to &lt;strong>tweak a metric&lt;/strong>. The concept of &amp;ldquo;adjusted Bounce Rate&amp;rdquo; sounds like the analyst is fixing a metric to be more beneficial to their cause, rather than fixing the business problem that caused the metric to be poor in the first place.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Customize The Scroll Depth Trigger In Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/customize-scroll-depth-trigger/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 09:44:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/customize-scroll-depth-trigger/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Last updated 9 March 2018 with some new tips.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/scroll-depth-trigger-google-tag-manager/">Scroll Depth trigger&lt;/a> in &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> has a lot going for it. Tracking how far users scroll down a given page has &lt;a href="http://cutroni.com/blog/2014/02/12/advanced-content-tracking-with-universal-analytics/">long since&lt;/a> been recognized as an important cog in the &lt;em>engagement tracking&lt;/em> machine, and there have been &lt;a href="http://scrolldepth.parsnip.io/">really&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://www.bounteous.com/labs/recipes/scroll-tracking/">great&lt;/a> solutions for implementing scroll depth tracking for web analytics over the years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With Google Tag Manager&amp;rsquo;s native Scroll Depth trigger, it&amp;rsquo;s tempting to think we now have a be-all end-all solution that covers all the bases. However, as with everything else in analytics, the native scroll depth trigger does require customization to provide you with relevant information about your content and the visitors interacting with it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Scroll Depth Trigger In Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/scroll-depth-trigger-google-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 19:11:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/scroll-depth-trigger-google-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>Scroll depth tracking in web analytics is one of those things you simply &lt;strong>must&lt;/strong> do, especially if you have a content-heavy site. Tracking scroll depth not only gives you an indication of how much users are digesting your content, but it also lets you turn meaningless metrics such as Bounce Rate into something far more useful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;ve already been tracking scroll depth in &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably been using either Rob Flaherty&amp;rsquo;s brilliant &lt;a href="http://scrolldepth.parsnip.io/">Scroll Depth&lt;/a> jQuery plugin, or Bounteous&amp;rsquo; equally ingenious &lt;a href="https://www.bounteous.com/labs/recipes/scroll-tracking/">Scroll Tracking recipe&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;m sure you&amp;rsquo;ll be very pleased to know that Google Tag Manager just released a &lt;strong>native Scroll Depth trigger&lt;/strong>, with which setting up scroll depth tracking will be a doozy!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>