<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Privacy on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/categories/privacy/</link><description>Recent content in Privacy on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 07:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/categories/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Expiration Cap Removed From JavaScript Cookies In WebKit Browsers</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/privacy/first-party-cookies-webkit-revisited/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/privacy/first-party-cookies-webkit-revisited/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you recall, in February 2019, Apple published a post on the &lt;a href="https://webkit.org/blog/8613/intelligent-tracking-prevention-2-1/">WebKit blog&lt;/a>, which introduced version &lt;strong>2.1&lt;/strong> of their &lt;strong>Intelligent Tracking Prevention&lt;/strong> browser mechanism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this version, Safari (and soon &lt;strong>all&lt;/strong> WebKit browsers, including browser apps on iOS and iPadOS) placed an &lt;strong>expiration limit&lt;/strong> on browser cookies set with JavaScript. It was no longer possible to set the expiration date further than &lt;strong>7 days in the future&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a recent 2022 release (I don&amp;rsquo;t have the exact date or version number), WebKit has now modified this mechanism to &lt;strong>no longer set an expiration cap on JavaScript cookies&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intelligent Tracking Prevention In iOS 14, iPadOS 14, And Safari 14</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/privacy/intelligent-tracking-prevention-ios-14-ipados-14-safari-14/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 07:00:10 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/privacy/intelligent-tracking-prevention-ios-14-ipados-14-safari-14/</guid><description>&lt;p>Apple&amp;rsquo;s annual Worldwide Developer Conference in late June this year included a couple of big announcements around Apple&amp;rsquo;s approach to privacy in their software.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new &lt;strong>Privacy Report&lt;/strong> in Safari 14 (on all platforms) uses &lt;a href="https://github.com/duckduckgo/tracker-radar">DuckDuckGo&amp;rsquo;s tracker radar list&lt;/a> to detail which of the most prominent tracking-capable domains have been flagged by &lt;a href="https://webkit.org/blog/7675/intelligent-tracking-prevention/">Intelligent Tracking Prevention (ITP)&lt;/a> in the user&amp;rsquo;s browser.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apple also announced that the &lt;code>WKWebView&lt;/code> class, which all iOS and iPadOS (the operating systems for iPhones and iPads, respectively) must use, will include WebKit&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>ITP mechanisms on by default&lt;/strong>. The list of major browsers running on these operating systems includes Brave, Chrome, Edge, Firefox, and Safari.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>