<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fpid on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/fpid/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fpid on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 07:47:46 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/fpid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Prevent SGTM From Setting The FPID Cookie</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/prevent-sgtm-from-setting-fpid-cookie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 07:47:46 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/prevent-sgtm-from-setting-fpid-cookie/</guid>
      <description>The FPID cookie is what server-side Google Tag Manager would prefer to use for your Google Analytics 4 tracking.
It&amp;rsquo;s a cookie set in the HTTP response from the server, and it&amp;rsquo;s flagged as HttpOnly, which means it&amp;rsquo;s only accessible by a web server running on the domain on which it was set.
There&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with the technology, and I do recommend that server-side setups toggle it on by default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Cross-domain Tracking With Server-side FPID Cookie</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/cross-domain-tracking-server-side-fpid-cookie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/cross-domain-tracking-server-side-fpid-cookie/</guid>
      <description>The FPID cookie in server-side tagging for Google Tag Manager is an HttpOnly, server-managed ID cookie that&amp;rsquo;s designed to replace the JavaScript-managed _ga cookie used by Google Analytics 4 and Universal Analytics.
For more details about the cookie itself, check out my previous article on FPID.
In that article, I mentioned one caveat for adopting FPID being the fact that cross-domain tracking will not work.
I mean, how could it? FPID is an HttpOnly cookie, which means it&amp;rsquo;s not available to JavaScript in the browser.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>