<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>google tag on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/google-tag/</link>
    <description>Recent content in google tag on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 07:01:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/google-tag/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Google Tag Template In Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-template-in-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 07:01:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-template-in-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>Google is going all-in with Google Tag. We&amp;rsquo;ve already seen the consolidation effort through products like Google Analytics 4, and now Google is extending the merging of the tagging stack into Google Tag Manager, too.
I&amp;rsquo;m referring to the new Google Tag that has replaced Google Analytics 4 configuration tags in your Google Tag Manager containers.
With this release, all your old GA4 configuration tags have been auto-migrated to the new Google Tag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settings Variables For GA4 In Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/settings-variables-for-ga4-in-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/settings-variables-for-ga4-in-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>One of the big pain points in configuring Google Analytics 4 through Google Tag Manager has been the difficulty of setting up event parameters, user properties, and settings across a range of tags.
Well, we can finally get rid of our clumsy Config tag sequencing hacks because Google has released two new settings variables that mimic how the Google Analytics Settings Variable used to work in Universal Analytics.
The new variables are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Tag To Rule Them All: Introducing The New Google Tag</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/one-tag-rule-them-all-introducing-google-tag/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 01:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/one-tag-rule-them-all-introducing-google-tag/</guid>
      <description>For the longest time, Google has been working towards consolidation of their products to build a unified tagging platform.
Products that are instrumented (or associated) with &amp;ldquo;tags&amp;rdquo; would fall under this umbrella. These comprise tools like Google Tag Manager, Google Ads, Google Optimize, and, of course, Google Analytics.
If you&amp;rsquo;ve been peeking under the hood, you might have noticed how all the tools listed above already run through the gtag.js library.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>