<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Google Cloud Platform on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/google-cloud-platform/</link><description>Recent content in Google Cloud Platform on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 07:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/google-cloud-platform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Join Google Ads And GA4 Data In Google BigQuery</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/join-ga4-google-ads-data-in-google-bigquery/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/join-ga4-google-ads-data-in-google-bigquery/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am fortunate to share another &lt;strong>guest post&lt;/strong> by &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/arben-kqiku-301457117/">Arben Kqiku&lt;/a>, Digital Analyst at &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/assura-ch/">Assura&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last time, Arben graced this blog with a &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/content-analysis-using-ga4-bigquery-r-google-sheets-data-studio/">comprehensive love letter to R&lt;/a> as an example of the power of this programming language.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time, he&amp;rsquo;ll add even more fancy tools to the toolkit to help you build a &lt;strong>data pipeline&lt;/strong> in the Google Cloud Platform to join your Google Ads and Google Analytics 4 data together.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- toc -->
&lt;h2 id="goal-of-this-article">Goal of this article&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My goal for this article is twofold; first, I want to show my fellow R users that it is possible and fun to use R in a production environment! R is sometimes seen as a second-class citizen compared to Python, but in my experience, R has consistently proven effective in addressing all my data challenges at work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Setup IAM For Manual Installation Of Server-side GTM</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtmtips/setup-iam-manual-installation-server-side-gtm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 07:00:01 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtmtips/setup-iam-manual-installation-server-side-gtm/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you want to &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/provision-server-side-tagging-application-manually/">manually install server-side Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> on App Engine in the Google Cloud Platform, you are of course welcome to do so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main benefits of doing this are that you get to &lt;strong>choose the region where App Engine is deployed&lt;/strong> and that you can use &lt;strong>existing project resources&lt;/strong> instead of having a new project automatically created for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, to run the script without errors, there are a number of things you need to enable first. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through the required permissions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Provision Server-side Tagging Application Manually</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/provision-server-side-tagging-application-manually/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 07:48:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/provision-server-side-tagging-application-manually/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/tag-manager/serverside#create_a_google_cloud_platform_gcp_server">automatic provisioning process&lt;/a> of the &lt;strong>Google Tag Manager server-side tagging service&lt;/strong> is extremely useful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With just a few clicks of the button, you can have a fully functional (albeit limited to testing use) server-side tagging endpoint on the Google Cloud Platform (GCP).&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>For a video overview of the automatic deployment, see &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6OGbOh216mU">this video&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>However, the automatic provisioning process creates &lt;strong>a new Google Cloud Platform project&lt;/strong> and, at the time of writing, always deploys the App Engine application (on which the tagging server runs) in the &lt;code>us-central-1&lt;/code> GCP region.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How To Build A Google Tag Manager Monitor</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-monitor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 11:49:15 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-monitor/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> is strictly a &lt;em>tag delivery system&lt;/em>, and it&amp;rsquo;s very careful &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/tagmanager/answer/9323295#data">not to collect any analytics data&lt;/a> on its own. This is most likely a deliberate choice, because if GTM was to start collecting data, it would introduce additional barriers to adoption.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nevertheless, being a tool that consolidates the design, development, deployment, and testing of all the marketing and analytics pixels, code snippets, and utilities running on a website or a mobile app, lacking the necessary features for auditing and monitoring has always seemed like an oversight.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>