<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>google cloud platform on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/google-cloud-platform/</link>
    <description>Recent content in google cloud platform on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 07:48:42 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/google-cloud-platform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Provision Server-side Tagging Application Manually</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/provision-server-side-tagging-application-manually/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 07:48:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/provision-server-side-tagging-application-manually/</guid>
      <description>The automatic provisioning process of the Google Tag Manager server-side tagging service is extremely useful.
With just a few clicks of the button, you can have a fully functional (albeit limited to testing use) server-side tagging endpoint on the Google Cloud Platform (GCP).
 For a video overview of the automatic deployment, see this video.
 However, the automatic provisioning process creates a new Google Cloud Platform project and, at the time of writing, always deploys the App Engine application (on which the tagging server runs) in the us-central-1 GCP region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Build A Google Tag Manager Monitor</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-monitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 11:49:15 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-monitor/</guid>
      <description>Google Tag Manager is strictly a tag delivery system, and it&amp;rsquo;s very careful not to collect any analytics data on its own. This is most likely a deliberate choice, because if GTM was to start collecting data, it would introduce additional barriers to adoption.
Nevertheless, being a tool that consolidates the design, development, deployment, and testing of all the marketing and analytics pixels, code snippets, and utilities running on a website or a mobile app, lacking the necessary features for auditing and monitoring has always seemed like an oversight.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>