<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Custom Html on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/custom-html/</link><description>Recent content in Custom Html on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 09:00:14 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/custom-html/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Custom HTML Tag Guide For Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/custom-html-tag-guide-google-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 09:00:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/custom-html-tag-guide-google-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the most prominent features of &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> since the dawn of time (actually, late 2012) is the &lt;strong>Custom HTML tag&lt;/strong>. This little piece of magic lets Google Tag Manager &lt;em>inject&lt;/em> an HTML element to the page. Since time immemorial (still late 2012), it&amp;rsquo;s allowed us to turn Google Tag Manager from a sandboxed prisoner of the native tag templates to a no-holds-barred client-side content management solution.&lt;/p>


 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/images/2020/01/custom-html-tag-guide.jpg" title="Custom HTML tag guide">
 
 &lt;amp-img src="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/images/2020/01/custom-html-tag-guide.jpg" layout="responsive" alt="Custom HTML tag guide" height="894" width="2132">&lt;/amp-img>
 
 &lt;/a>
 

&lt;p>In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how the Custom HTML tag &lt;strong>works&lt;/strong>, and what you might be tempted to use it for.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Get Latest Exchange Rates For Client-side Conversions</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/get-latest-exchange-rates-client-side-conversions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 13:00:43 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/get-latest-exchange-rates-client-side-conversions/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve last written a bona fide &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> &lt;strong>trick&lt;/strong>, so here comes. This was inspired by Bart Gibby&amp;rsquo;s question in &lt;a href="https://www.measure.chat/">Measure Slack&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose is to fetch the latest currency exchange rates from the &lt;a href="https://exchangeratesapi.io">exchangeratesapi.io&lt;/a> service, cache them using &lt;code>sessionStorage&lt;/code>, and push the results into &lt;code>dataLayer&lt;/code>. From &lt;code>dataLayer&lt;/code>, they can then be utilized in Custom JavaScript variables and custom variable templates to perform client-side conversions. I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Tag Sequencing With Custom HTML Tags</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/tag-sequencing-custom-html-tags/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 10:14:32 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/tag-sequencing-custom-html-tags/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/understanding-tag-sequencing-in-google-tag-manager/">Tag sequencing&lt;/a> was introdced to &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> in late 2015. Its main purpose was to facilitate the &lt;em>sequential&lt;/em> firing of tags that have dependencies with each other. Due to the &lt;a href="https://www.pluralsight.com/guides/introduction-to-asynchronous-javascript">asynchronous&lt;/a> nature of third-party libraries like Google Tag Manager, it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to establish an order of completion with tags that compete for their chance to fire.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tag sequencing changed this, as it allows you to establish &lt;strong>setup&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>cleanup&lt;/strong> tags - the former firing &lt;em>before&lt;/em> the main tag, and the latter &lt;em>after&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Restrict Custom HTML Tag Scope</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/restrict-custom-html-tag-scope/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 15:06:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/restrict-custom-html-tag-scope/</guid><description>&lt;p>What better way to celebrate the &lt;strong>50th&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/categories/gtm-tips/">#GTMTips&lt;/a> article than, well, a &lt;em>really useful &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> tip&lt;/em>?! This tip is so useful and simple; it encapsulates everything that I had in mind when starting this series. The tip is about &lt;em>restricting scope&lt;/em> of Custom HTML Tags. This is an important concept, because it&amp;rsquo;s possible that you&amp;rsquo;re stuffing your page&amp;rsquo;s global JavaScript namespace with all sorts of junk, and thus inadvertently causing conflicts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#GTMTips: Using document.write Safely In GTM Tags</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/using-document-write-safely-gtm-tags/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 07:25:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/using-document-write-safely-gtm-tags/</guid><description>&lt;p>This article is a guest article by someone from the analytics community I really look up to. &lt;a href="https://www.bounteous.com/insights/author/danwilkerson/">Dan Wilkerson&lt;/a> is an analytics developer at &lt;a href="https://www.bounteous.com/">Bounteous&lt;/a>, a company I hold in high esteem. Dan is one of the smartest technical analytics experts out there, and a large bulk of the awesome scripts and hacks that Bounteous produces (almost on a daily basis) have been orchestrated by him. So I&amp;rsquo;m very pleased to give the floor to Dan, so that he can tell you all about using the pesky &lt;code>document.write()&lt;/code> method in your &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> Custom HTML Tags!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Track Form Abandonment With Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/track-form-abandonment-with-google-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 08:12:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/track-form-abandonment-with-google-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Form abandonment&lt;/strong> isn&amp;rsquo;t always easy to define. Most often, it refers to when someone starts to fill in an HTML form, but leaves the page without submitting it. As a definition, this works nicely. However, with multi-page forms it naturally refers only to the &lt;em>last&lt;/em> page of the form. Also, especially with government institutions, forms can be saved to be submitted later. Here, again, &lt;em>form abandonment&lt;/em> must be reconsidered.&lt;/p>


 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/images/2015/07/form-abandonment.jpg" title="Form abandonment in Google Tag Manager">
 
 &lt;amp-img src="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/images/2015/07/form-abandonment.jpg" layout="responsive" alt="Form abandonment in Google Tag Manager" height="524" width="1740">&lt;/amp-img>
 
 &lt;/a>
 

&lt;p>In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll go over &lt;strong>four&lt;/strong> different ways to track form abandonment in &lt;a href="https://analytics.google.com">Google Analytics&lt;/a>, using &lt;a href="https://tagmanager.google.com">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a> to setup the tracking. The definition I&amp;rsquo;ll use is the first one: abandonment occurs when someone enters a form page, but leaves it without submitting the form. Do note that GA might not be the right tool to actually track issues with your form. There are dedicated resources for that, such as &lt;a href="http://www.clicktale.com">ClickTale&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="http://www.hotjar.com">Hotjar&lt;/a>. But if you want to measure form engagement as part of a more coherent visitor journey, then it might make sense to track this engagement (or lack thereof) in Google Analytics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Access The Tracker Object In Your Page View Tag</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/access-the-tracker-object-in-your-page-view-tag/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 10:29:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/access-the-tracker-object-in-your-page-view-tag/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you read my &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/improve-data-collection-with-four-custom-dimensions/">previous post&lt;/a> on fetching the &lt;em>Client ID&lt;/em> from the Universal Analytics tracker object with &lt;a href="http://tagmanager.google.com">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>, you might have agreed with me that it sucks you can&amp;rsquo;t access the tracker object interface in real time using Google Tag Manager. This is because all of the &lt;code>set&lt;/code> commands you add to a Universal Analytics tag template take place before the &lt;strong>analytics.js&lt;/strong> is loaded and the tracker object is properly created.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Simple Split Test With Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/simple-split-test-google-tag-manager/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 11:36:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/simple-split-test-google-tag-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>Over the last couple of posts I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/send-mail-upon-google-tag-manager-event/">mainly&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-tag-manager-dom-listener/">been&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/form-tracking-google-tag-manager/">doing&lt;/a> proof-of-concept (POC) tests with &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/tagmanager">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>. The great thing about a POC is that you don&amp;rsquo;t really need to have any viable results or insight-driving technological innovations. The point is to showcase some feature of the platform on which the experiment was conducted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll take a care-free step into the world of POCs again. My goal is to do a simple split test in order to identify which variant of a landing page (or key element thereof) produces the most conversions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Block Internal Traffic With Google Tag Manager</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/block-internal-traffic-gtm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 11:30:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/block-internal-traffic-gtm/</guid><description>&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ve probably come across a &lt;a href="http://www.seerinteractive.com/blog/best-ways-to-exclude-internal-traffic-in-google-analytics">number&lt;/a> of &lt;a href="http://andygibson.us/2013/09/filter-internal-traffic-using-custom-variables/">guides&lt;/a> or posts talking about why it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to block so-called &lt;em>internal traffic&lt;/em> from your web analytics reports. The reasons are pretty solid: internal traffic does not emulate normal visitor behavior, it rarely contributes to conversions (skewing up your conversion rate), it inflates page views, and it wreaks havoc on your granular, page-by-page data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Internal traffic is vaguely described as &amp;ldquo;your employees&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;people really close to your brand&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;your marketing department&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;your web editors&amp;rdquo;, and so on. Basically, it should be a term which covers &lt;em>traffic that does not adequately represent trending visitor behavior on your site&lt;/em>. Most often, this is &amp;ldquo;internal&amp;rdquo;, in that it is traffic by people who generate the content. It can also be your proof-readers (wives, husbands, best friends), beta testers (wives, husbands, best friends), outreach marketers (wives, husb&amp;hellip; you get my drift).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Tag Manager: Content Grouping</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-tag-manager-content-grouping/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 16:45:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-tag-manager-content-grouping/</guid><description>&lt;p>Content Grouping is a nice new feature from the good folks at &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2853423?hl=en">Google Analytics&lt;/a>. Basically, it allows you to group your content according to a logical structure. You can create up to &lt;strong>five&lt;/strong> Content Groupings, and you can have as many Content Groups within these groupings as you like. The difference between a &lt;strong>Content Grouping&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Content Group&lt;/strong> is hierarchy. The second is a member of the first. Read Justin Cutroni&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://cutroni.com/blog/2014/01/09/set-google-analytics-content-grouping/">post on Content Groupings&lt;/a> to get you started.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Tag Manager: Track Social Interactions</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-tag-manager-track-social-interactions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 15:02:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-tag-manager-track-social-interactions/</guid><description>&lt;p>(Last updated June 2014) &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/analytics">Google Analytics&lt;/a> provides us with a nifty way of &lt;a href="http://www.seotakeaways.com/social-interactions-tracking-through-google-analytics/">tracking social interactions&lt;/a>. With a simple plugin, you can track how many +1s and Likes your pages accumulate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This guide shows you how to activate social interaction tagging with Google Tag Manager and Universal Analytics. The instructions are for Facebook Likes, Google+ +1s (now deprecated since &lt;strong>Google Analytics tracks +1s automatically&lt;/strong>), Twitter Tweets and Pinterest Pins.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that if you use a third-party API (e.g. &lt;a href="http://www.addthis.com">AddThis&lt;/a>) these tricks probably won&amp;rsquo;t work. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to use the API functions themselves to enable tracking.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Track Adjusted Bounce Rate In Universal Analytics</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/track-adjusted-bounce-rate-universal-analytics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2013 09:09:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/track-adjusted-bounce-rate-universal-analytics/</guid><description>&lt;p>So here we are again. &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2790010?hl=en">Universal Analytics&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/tagmanager">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>, the dynamic duo, ready to strike again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, remember to check my previous two tips for UA and GTM use in custom scenarios:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/web-development/universal-analytics-weather-custom-dimension/">Weather as a custom dimension&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/page-load-time-universal-analytics/">Tracking page load time&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>In this post, I visit the idea of &lt;a href="http://analytics.blogspot.fi/2012/07/tracking-adjusted-bounce-rate-in-google.html">adjusted bounce rate&lt;/a>, which I came across a year ago in the &lt;a href="http://analytics.google.com">Google Analytics&lt;/a> blog.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adjusted bounce rate basically refers to tweaking the traditional bounce rate collection method (single engagement hits / total visits) so that visits which only included a single page view would not count towards a bounce, as long as they met some qualitative requirements.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Page Load Time In Universal Analytics</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/page-load-time-universal-analytics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2013 14:49:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/page-load-time-universal-analytics/</guid><description>&lt;p>In Google Analytics, you can monitor your &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/1205784?hl=en">site speed&lt;/a> and get a decent overview of what pages are contributing positively and negatively to site speed. The problem with page load time metric is that it&amp;rsquo;s an average based on a sample. You can modify the sample rate with &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/gajs/methods/gaJSApiBasicConfiguration?csw=1#_gat.GA_Tracker_._setSiteSpeedSampleRate">setSiteSpeedSampleRate()&lt;/a>, but for me &lt;em>that&amp;rsquo;s not bloody well good enough&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(&lt;strong>UPDATE 28.3.2014&lt;/strong>: This post is still valid, but an implementation with &lt;em>User Timings&lt;/em> is a much smarter way to measure actual page load time. I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing a short update at some point in the near future.)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Universal Analytics: Weather As A Custom Dimension</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/web-development/universal-analytics-weather-custom-dimension/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 16:51:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/web-development/universal-analytics-weather-custom-dimension/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>There is a new version of this post for GTM V2 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/send-weather-data-to-google-analytics-in-gtm-v2/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[Last updated June 2014] I&amp;rsquo;ve fallen in love with &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2790010?hl=en">Universal Analytics&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/tagmanager/">Google Tag Manager&lt;/a>. Together they form an incredibly powerful tool for marketing professionals. In most cases, I no longer need to post recommendations to my client for yet another page template revision, since with the tag manager in place, I can just add custom code via the admin panel. Add to that the power of Universal Analytics with its ultra-sensitive Measurement Protocol, and the ability to craft custom dimensions and metrics, and voila! I&amp;rsquo;m in a happy place.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>