<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 07:26:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>customTask Builder</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tools/customtask-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 07:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/tools/customtask-builder/</guid>
      <description>You can use the customTask Builder tool to create a customTask script. customTask is a method of the Google Analytics library, which lets you run JavaScript code when the hit request to Google Analytics is being built.
 Click here to jump directly to the tool.
 This is very useful for a number of reasons, and I recommend you read customTask - The Guide before doing anything with the tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test page</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/test-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/test-page/</guid>
      <description>Hello  #wrapper { height: 100%; width: 100%; display: table; } #top { height: 50%; background-color: #5B9BD5; width: 100%; display: table-row; } #bottom { height: 50%; background-color: #fff; width: 100%; display: table-row; } #greeting { color: #fff; font-family: Lobster,sans-serif; font-size: 2em; vertical-align: bottom; text-align: center; display: table-cell; padding: 10px; } #subscribe { vertical-align: top; text-align: center; display: table-cell; padding-top: 20px; } #email-field { width: 700px; height: 50px; color: #838383; font-size: 3em; padding: 5px; border: 2px dotted #ddd; font-family: sans-serif; } #subscribe-button { background-color: #f08406; border: 1px solid #ad5d15; -webkit-box-shadow: inset 0px 1px 0px rgba(255,255,255,0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Talks</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/upcoming-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 15:02:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/upcoming-talks/</guid>
      <description>8 June 2019: MeasureCamp Copenhagen 27 September 2019: People That Count, Warsaw 30 September 2019: SMX Advanced, Berlin 10 October 2019: SearchStars, Malmö 16 October 2019: Marketing Analytics Summit, London 6 November 2019: Analytics Summit, Hamburg    I enjoy presenting at conferences and meetups, and I have a track record of hundreds of talks since 2013, comprising keynotes, conference presentations, workshops, seminars, and public trainings. Audience sizes have varied between 3 and 2,000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GTM Tools Add-on For Google Sheets</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tools/gtm-tools-by-simo-ahava/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/tools/gtm-tools-by-simo-ahava/</guid>
      <description>The GTM Tools by Simo Ahava is a Google Sheets add-on. It lets you manage and update your Google Tag Manager containers, tags, triggers, and variables.
  In this first iteration, the tools feature a Documentation builder, which lets you automatically generate documentation for the latest version of your Google Tag Manager container, tags, triggers, and variables. In addition to this, the toolset features a Push changes to Notes functionality, which lets you automatically mass update the Notes field across your tags, triggers, and variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference Biography</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/conference-bio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 15:12:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/conference-bio/</guid>
      <description>Simo Ahava is a recognized expert on customizing web analytics and tag management solutions to improve the entire &amp;ldquo;life cycle&amp;rdquo; of data collection, processing, and reporting. His main areas of expertise lie with Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager, and Google has appointed him as a Google Developer Expert in these fields. He is especially interested in the interface between marketing and development, and his main focus is on increasing awareness, skills, and critical thinking around data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Simo Ahava</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/about-simo-ahava/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 15:10:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/about-simo-ahava/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Simo Ahava. I&amp;rsquo;m partner and co-founder at 8-bit-sheep.
I have also been a Google Developer Expert for Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager since 2014.
I hail from Espoo, neighboring Helsinki, the capital of Finland. I have a background in academics (English language and linguistics), in IT, in digital marketing, and in web development. I&amp;rsquo;ve been programming actively since 1997, and I built my first website the same year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Dimension Manager For Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tools/google-analytics-custom-dimension-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 07:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/tools/google-analytics-custom-dimension-manager/</guid>
      <description>The Custom Dimension Manager For Google Analytics is a Google Sheets add-on. It lets you update Custom Dimensions in any given Google Analytics property en masse.   When updating, new dimensions are created automatically with values from a source data sheet (or using a default value if no value is specified), and for existing dimensions you have the choice to update or skip.   The add-on is completely free to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Analytics Validator</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tools/google-analytics-validator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 07:51:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/tools/google-analytics-validator/</guid>
      <description>The Google Analytics Validator is a Google Sheets add-on. It lets you build a spreadsheet of all the accounts, properties, and views you have access to in Google Analytics. Then, you can select any number of these properties to populate a second sheet, where each Custom Dimension configured in the property is displayed with its name, scope, and active status.   Finally, you can poll for the last 7 days data for any selected property/view to see if the Custom Dimension has collected any hits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chrome Extensions</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tools/chrome-extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 07:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/tools/chrome-extensions/</guid>
      <description>Here are the two Chrome Extensions I&amp;rsquo;ve written.
 GTM Sonar - Debug your on-site JavaScript to see if it&amp;rsquo;s compatible with the event listeners Google Tag Manager leverages
 Internalize for Google Analytics - Send a Custom Dimension hit at the click of a button. This tool is intended to annotate traffic in a certain way, letting you filter it out or process it in any way you choose</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GTM Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tools/gtm-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 07:25:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/tools/gtm-tools/</guid>
      <description>GTM Tools are utilities created for managing Google Tag Manager containers. The main features are:
 Clone containers from one account to another (or within the same account)
 Visualize containers
 Inspect containers, and add individual assets (Tags, Triggers, Variables) to a &amp;ldquo;Shopping cart&amp;rdquo;
 Clone Shopping cart contents as a new container in a GTM account
 Save Shopping cart contents into an asset library for future use</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spam Filter Insertion Tool</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/spam-filter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 06:13:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/spam-filter/</guid>
      <description>I took my Spam Filter Insertion Tool down since it&amp;rsquo;s very ineffective for tackling referral spam in Google Analytics. There are far better ways to combat spam.
You can still download the source in the GitHub repository if you want to build the tool yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Statistics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/blog-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 15:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/blog-statistics/</guid>
      <description>I started writing articles in May, 2013. The first couple of articles written during the first months of this blog&amp;rsquo;s life were not very good. Things picked up when I started focusing only on Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager articles.
The following statistics are powered by Google Data Studio.
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2014 17:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/tools/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written a bunch of tools to help you use and debug Google Tag Manager and Google Analytics. I&amp;rsquo;m neither a professional product developer nor am I a visual designer, and both correlate with how the tools look like and what their user experience is :)
Nevertheless, I only create tools that I want to use myself, and being a sort of power-user especially in the development side of things, I do think that these little utilities provide added value to your tag management needs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>