<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>consent mode on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/consent-mode/</link>
    <description>Recent content in consent mode on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 07:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/consent-mode/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Consent Mode: The Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/basic-consent-mode-the-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/basic-consent-mode-the-guide/</guid>
      <description>Google&amp;rsquo;s Consent Mode is a way to control how tags react to the user&amp;rsquo;s consent for different tracking purposes. It is specifically designed to work with Google&amp;rsquo;s tags, but especially through Google Tag Manager, you can use Consent Mode&amp;rsquo;s features and APIs to control other tags, too.
Consent Mode comes in two &amp;ldquo;flavors&amp;rdquo;:
  Advanced Consent Mode is specifically designed for Google&amp;rsquo;s products. Tags for GA4, Ads, and Floodlight are sensitive to the user&amp;rsquo;s consent choices and change their behavior accordingly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Automatic Page View Hits In SGTM After Consent Granted</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtmtips/automatic-page-view-hits-to-sgtm-after-consent-granted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 07:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtmtips/automatic-page-view-hits-to-sgtm-after-consent-granted/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re using server-side Google Tag Manager, Google (Advanced) Consent Mode and you&amp;rsquo;re collecting hits to Google Analytics 4, you might have noticed something odd happening when switching consent to granted state.
It looks as if your page_view hits as well as any other hits marked as &amp;ldquo;Conversions&amp;rdquo; (or key events now, I guess) are automatically redispatched to the server-side Google Tag Manager endpoint when consent is granted!
This sounds incredibly useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Consent Granted Reprocesses Previously Denied Hits</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtmtips/consent-granted-reprocesses-previously-denied-hits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtmtips/consent-granted-reprocesses-previously-denied-hits/</guid>
      <description>This will be a quick tip, but it&amp;rsquo;s here to correct my previous statements in the comments section of different articles on this blog.
When using Advanced Consent Mode, Google Analytics 4 collects hits when consent is in &amp;quot;denied&amp;quot; state. These hits have a lot of parameters stripped off them, including identifiers like the Client ID and the Session ID.
The hits will not surface in reports directly, but they will instead go through a modeling process to enrich the reports once modeled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consent Mode V2 For Google Tags</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/consent-mode-v2-google-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/consent-mode-v2-google-tags/</guid>
      <description>**Last updated March 7, 2024. Clarified that you do NOT need to resend hits when consent is granted, if those hits were collected on the same page when consent was denied.
 Google&amp;rsquo;s Consent Mode continues to be a hot topic, especially since in 2024 it will be required to implement Consent Mode in case a website or app is collecting data for audience building or remarketing with Google&amp;rsquo;s advertising services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consent Mode For Google Tags</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/consent-mode-google-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 12:08:47 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/consent-mode-google-tags/</guid>
      <description>Note! This is about the original version of Consent Mode. While the content is still very valid and you should read through it to understand how it works, Google has since released a &amp;ldquo;V2&amp;rdquo; update with additional consent signals. You can read about Consent Mode V2 here. . Not too long ago, Google announced a new consent mode for Google tags. It allows you to build a mechanism where Google&amp;rsquo;s tags parse, react, and respond to the consent status of your site visitors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>