<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guide on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/tags/guide/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guide on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 18:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/tags/guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Templates Guide For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/custom-templates-guide-for-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 18:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/custom-templates-guide-for-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>As I have finally managed to pick up my jaw from the floor, it&#39;s now time to tell you what&#39;s got me so excited. Google Tag Manager recently released a new feature called Custom Templates. Actually, it&#39;s not fair to call it a feature. It&#39;s a full-blown paradigm shift in how we use Google Tag Manager. It&#39;s a suite of features designed to help brands, companies, and users create and share their own custom JavaScript and HTML setups with ease, while taking care that the code is optimized for delivery in the web browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Selector Guide For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/css-selector-guide-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 09:55:23 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/css-selector-guide-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>Some four years ago, Google Tag Manager released a new trigger predicate named matches CSS selector. Slowly but surely, it has evolved into one of the most useful little features in GTM.
  Even though I&#39;ve written about CSS selectors many times before, I wanted to compile all the relevant information into a single guide. For an external resource, I recommend bookmarking the w3schools.com CSS Selector Reference. But for your day-to-day use of CSS selectors in GTM, this guide will hopefully prove useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Ecommerce Guide For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-guide-for-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 08:35:17 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-guide-for-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>Enhanced Ecommerce is certainly one of the finest reporting user interface features that Google Analytics has to offer. Enhanced Ecommerce, as the name implies, is a set of dimensions, metrics, and reports, which combine to provide you with a fairly complete view into how users are interacting with your products in your webstore. The main downside of Enhanced Ecommerce is, as with all good things, that it&#39;s complicated to implement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide To Zones In Google Tag Manager 360</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/guide-zones-google-tag-manager-360/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 23:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/guide-zones-google-tag-manager-360/</guid>
      <description>Google Tag Manager supports loading multiple containers on the same page. It&#39;s useful if you have multiple companies or organizations working on the same site, but for one reason or another (e.g. governance) you want to restrict access to your main container. In these situations, having the other party create their own container and adding it to the site is the best of bad options.
Well, in Google Tag Manager 360, we now have Zones that make managing multiple partners&amp;rsquo; containers quite a bit easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Scroll Depth Trigger In Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/scroll-depth-trigger-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 19:11:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/scroll-depth-trigger-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>Scroll depth tracking in web analytics is one of those things you simply must do, especially if you have a content-heavy site. Tracking scroll depth not only gives you an indication of how much users are digesting your content, but it also lets you turn meaningless metrics such as Bounce Rate into something far more useful.
If you&#39;ve already been tracking scroll depth in Google Tag Manager, you&#39;ve probably been using either Rob Flaherty&#39;s brilliant Scroll Depth jQuery plugin, or Bounteous&amp;rsquo; equally ingenious Scroll Tracking recipe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The RegEx Table Variable In Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/the-regex-table-variable-in-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 21:29:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/the-regex-table-variable-in-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>Ever since the Lookup Table variable was introduced in Google Tag Manager, users have been craving for more. The Lookup Table does exactly what it promises: lookups. These are exact match operations, which are extremely inexpensive to perform, because they can only have a binary result: either the match exists in the data store being queried or it doesn&#39;t. This performance stays constant even if the data store being queried increases in size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: The Timer Trigger</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/timer-trigger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 10:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/timer-trigger/</guid>
      <description>Google Tag Manager has a Trigger type which fires after a certain duration of time has passed on the web page: the Timer Trigger. The most common uses for the Timer Trigger seem to be either to send an event to Google Analytics after X seconds of dwell time (to kill the Bounce), or to defer a Tag from firing until some asynchronous request has completed with certainty.
In the previous version of Google Tag Manager, the Timer was a separate listener Tag, which meant that you could start a timer based on a user interaction such as a click.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: 10 Blogs, 10 Articles, 10 People To Follow</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/gtmtips-10-blogs-10-articles-10-people-follow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 15:11:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/gtmtips-10-blogs-10-articles-10-people-follow/</guid>
      <description>Quite a while ago, I wrote an article on what I considered (then) to be my favorite Google Tag Manager resources. Many of them are still very valid, but I still wanted to write a follow-up. Times have changed, and GTM is very different from what it was two years ago when I wrote the post.
So in this article, I want to divert your attention to 10 blogs, 10 articles, and 10 people - all which are and/or share excellent Google Tag Manager content on a periodic basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: URL Source In The URL Variable</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/url-source-in-the-url-variable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 07:53:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/url-source-in-the-url-variable/</guid>
      <description>One of the less-known features of Google Tag Manager, a hidden gem if you will, is the URL Source setting in the URL Variable type. It lets you parse any URL String for its components.
Tip 38: Parse URL strings with the URL Source setting   The setting itself is easy to find. Just edit an existing URL Variable, or create a new one. Then, scroll down to the More Settings divider, expand it, and you&#39;ll see the URL Source drop-down list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firing A Single Tag Multiple Times In GTM</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/firing-a-single-tag-multiple-times-in-gtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 07:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/firing-a-single-tag-multiple-times-in-gtm/</guid>
      <description>There might be many reasons you&#39;d want to fire a single Tag multiple times in Google Tag Manager. The most common one is when you want to deploy multiples of a single tracking point on the web. Perhaps you have a roll-up account you want to send the hits to, in addition to the site-specific tracking property.
Quite a while ago, I gave a solution for this with a specific focus on Google Analytics Tags.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Referral Exclusion On Receipt Page</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/referral-exclusion-on-receipt-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 07:27:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/referral-exclusion-on-receipt-page/</guid>
      <description>You might have noticed that the Referral Exclusion List in Google Analytics is difficult to maintain. You can&#39;t copy a list from one property to another, the list is a wildcard match for domain names (so all subdomains are automatically excluded), and it&#39;s just about the clunkiest user interface we&#39;ve seen since ERP tools from the 1990s. A while ago, I wrote of a solution which lets you manage referral exclusions using Google Tag Manager, and it&#39;s still a neat trick, as it&#39;s way more flexible than said clunky UI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better QA With Google Tag Manager Environments</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/better-qa-with-google-tag-manager-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 05:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/better-qa-with-google-tag-manager-environments/</guid>
      <description>Google Tag Manager, our favorite free tag management solution, has always struggled with its enterprise-worthiness. There are many features still lacking, most of which have to do with working in multi-user environments. Now, grab the last word of that sentence (see what I did there), and hug it tightly, for GTM just introduced a new, enterprise-friendly feature: Environments.
  These Environments are actually browser cookies, which you use to link a Google Tag Manager container state with the browser of the user who needs to or wants to view that particular state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iframe Cross-Domain Tracking In Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/iframe-cross-domain-tracking-in-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 10:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/iframe-cross-domain-tracking-in-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>NOTE! This solution has been upgraded, and the new approach can be found here.
 If you&#39;re unfamiliar with the lingo, cross-domain tracking is a hack used by Google Analytics to circumvent the web browser&#39;s same-origin policy. Essentially, the policy dictates that browser cookies can only be shared with a parent domain and all its sub-domains. In other words, domainA.com and domainB.com do not share cookies.
Since Google Analytics calculates sessions and users by using a cookie, this is problematic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup Google Tag Manager iOS With Swift</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/setup-google-tag-manager-ios-with-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 12:16:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/setup-google-tag-manager-ios-with-swift/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been meaning to write about Google Tag Manager for mobile apps for such a long time. Finally, I have some great use cases to share, as well as some useful examples for implementing GTM for iOS. That&#39;s right, this is an iOS guide, and, to be more specific, geared towards a successful Swift implementation.
  If you didn&#39;t know, Swift is a relatively new programming language, developed by Apple for iOS and OS X programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measure Ad And Content Blocker Impact</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/measure-ad-content-blocker-impact-on-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 08:52:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/measure-ad-content-blocker-impact-on-traffic/</guid>
      <description>So, looks like iOS 9 has built-in support for integrating &amp;ldquo;content blocking&amp;rdquo; extensions on your iPhone. Now, blocking ads and other intrusive content is nothing new, nor do I want to get into a debate about whether it&#39;s a good thing or not. But as a data geek I&#39;m very interested in knowing just what share of my site tracking has some content blocker enabled. In this post, I&#39;ll show two tricks (easy and advanced) to expose these content blockers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measure SERP Bounce Time With GTM</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/measure-serp-bounce-time-with-gtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 12:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/measure-serp-bounce-time-with-gtm/</guid>
      <description>Here&#39;s an interesting and hacky use case for you. It&#39;s all about uncovering bounce metrics for visits which originate from organic Google search results. In particular, the metric we&#39;re interested in is how long user dwelled on the landing page after arriving from organic Google search AND returned to the search engine results page (SERP) using the browser&#39;s back button.
  The inspiration for this post came from an audience question at the Best Internet Conference in Lithuania, which I recently attended as a speaker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Check For New User</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/check-for-new-user/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 11:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/check-for-new-user/</guid>
      <description>Every now and then we want to create a bridge between the stateful machines we send data to (e.g. Google Analytics), and the stateless environment where we collect the data itself (e.g. Google Tag Manager). This is not easy. There is no synergy between Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager which would let the latter understand anything about things like sessions or landing pages or Bounce Rates.
One thing we can reliably measure, however, is whether or not the visitor is a New User in Google Analytics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Ecommerce Tips And Learnings</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-tips-and-learnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 07:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-tips-and-learnings/</guid>
      <description>Enhanced Ecommerce is undoubtedly an excellent feature of Google Analytics. It provides us with a set of reports that truly extend the capabilities of funnel-based website analysis. As I&#39;ve shown before, it&#39;s also very useful for tracking other transactional events on your site, such as content engagement.
  However, here&#39;s the thing. It&#39;s not very easy to implement. Even if you get everything right according to the documentation, there are still quite a number of pitfalls, and many of the learnings emerge only through experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track Form Engagement With Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-form-engagement-with-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 07:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-form-engagement-with-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>(Updated 13 August 2017)
A little over a year ago, in April 2014, I wrote the post &amp;ldquo;Advanced Form Tracking In Google Tag Manager&amp;quot;, and it&#39;s been at the top of my best seller list ever since. Turns out that many people are rightfully passionate about making the web forms on their websites as fluid and intuitive as possible, since a web form is often the only thing that stands between a prospect and their transformation into clienthood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Tag Sequencing In Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/understanding-tag-sequencing-in-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 06:18:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/understanding-tag-sequencing-in-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>A recent update to Google Tag Manager introduced a feature which has been on the wishlist of many users for a long time. It&#39;s called Tag sequencing, and its purpose is to facilitate the sequential firing of Tags. The idea is that you can specify a setup and a cleanup for each Tag in your container.
  This article is intended to function as a quick tour of the feature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Ways To Persist Data Via Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/two-ways-to-persist-data-via-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 15:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/two-ways-to-persist-data-via-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>The web is stateless. It&#39;s basically blind to your past, and it does a poor job of predicting what you might do in the future. When you browse to a website, the browser requests the page from the web server, and then proceeds to render it for you. This is a detached, clinical process, and any personalized or stateful data transfer is left to the sophistication of your web server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Block Your Tags With Trigger Exceptions</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/block-your-tags-with-trigger-exceptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 09:54:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/block-your-tags-with-trigger-exceptions/</guid>
      <description>To prevent a Tag from firing in Google Tag Manager, you can:
  Delete the Tag
  Remove all Triggers from the Tag
  Add an Exception Trigger to the Tag
  The third option is usually the best if the blocking is just temporary. Exceptions are what used to be called blocking rules in the first version of GTM. To add them is easy enough. In the Fire On step of Tag creation, you can click Create Exceptions, and choose the Trigger that will block this Tag from firing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Form Field Timing With Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/form-field-timing-with-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 09:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/form-field-timing-with-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>The inimitable Craig Sullivan gave me an idea for a continuation to my latest post on form abandonment tracking. In this short tutorial, I&#39;ll show you how to track the time users spend on your form fields. We&#39;re going to use the User Timings hit type, and we&#39;ll send the data for just one form. With small modifications, you can expand the script to cover multiple forms on a page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track Form Abandonment With Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-form-abandonment-with-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 08:12:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-form-abandonment-with-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>Form abandonment isn&#39;t always easy to define. Most often, it refers to when someone starts to fill in an HTML form, but leaves the page without submitting it. As a definition, this works nicely. However, with multi-page forms it naturally refers only to the last page of the form. Also, especially with government institutions, forms can be saved to be submitted later. Here, again, form abandonment must be reconsidered.
  In this article, I&#39;ll go over four different ways to track form abandonment in Google Analytics, using Google Tag Manager to setup the tracking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Ecommerce With A Custom JavaScript Variable</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-with-a-custom-javascript-variable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 08:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-with-a-custom-javascript-variable/</guid>
      <description>Enhanced Ecommerce is a very nice improvement to the pretty lame, transaction-based Ecommerce tracking in Universal Analytics. Instead of staring blindly at what happens on a receipt page, Enhanced Ecommerce expands your entire webstore into one large funnel labelled &amp;ldquo;Shopping Behavior&amp;rdquo;, and you&#39;re able to zoom in on the Checkout funnel as well. Also, the addition of product-scoped tracking is incredibly useful, and it&#39;s enabled us to think of any asset (our content, for example) on our site as something we could track through the Enhanced Ecommerce reports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Tag Manager: SoundCloud Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-soundcloud-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 12:28:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-soundcloud-integration/</guid>
      <description>According to their website, SoundCloud is &amp;ldquo;the world’s leading social sound platform where anyone can create sounds and share them everywhere&amp;rdquo;. For artists, it&#39;s a channel for distributing previews of their tracks, and for people like me it&#39;s a nice way to do some API tinkering. To each their own, I guess!
  I saw a number of requests in the Google+ Google Tag Manager community about a SoundCloud integration, so I decided to look into it to see if I could just build one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Take The Google Tag Manager Fundamentals Course</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/take-the-google-tag-manager-fundamentals-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 12:50:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/take-the-google-tag-manager-fundamentals-course/</guid>
      <description>Are you (even marginally) interested in one of the most powerful tag management systems out there? Do you want to refresh your memory on how JavaScript works in the web? Do you want to get the most out of Google Tag Manager as the go-to system for all marketing and measurement tagging on your websites?
Take the Google Tag Manager Fundamentals Course at the Analytics Academy, then! And take it even if you have no idea what the tool is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Add Google Tag Manager To Your Blogger Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/add-google-tag-manager-to-your-blogger-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 16:17:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/add-google-tag-manager-to-your-blogger-blog/</guid>
      <description>This is a very simple tip, but judging by the number of queries on the Product Forums, it should prove helpful.
Blogger is a free blogging service by Google. Like WordPress, they allow you to run hosted blogs on the blogger.com domain, and they also allow you to modify the HTML source. This, of course, means that you can add the Google Tag Manager code to the HTML template, if you wish (and why wouldn&#39;t you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve Data Collection With Four Custom Dimensions</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/improve-data-collection-with-four-custom-dimensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 16:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/improve-data-collection-with-four-custom-dimensions/</guid>
      <description>Since writing my rant about the schema conspiracy of web analytics platforms, I&#39;ve been giving the whole idea of hit-level data collection a lot of thought. Sessionization is very heavily implemented in Google Analytics, which is understandable, but the regular Google Analytics API just doesn&#39;t give you the kind of information you&#39;d need, if you wanted to stitch hits together differently in your own backend. In fact, there are four distinct levels of aggregation that are not exposed via the API, even though I think they should:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Send Weather Data To Google Analytics In GTM V2</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/send-weather-data-to-google-analytics-in-gtm-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 09:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/send-weather-data-to-google-analytics-in-gtm-v2/</guid>
      <description>In 2013, I wrote a guide for Universal Analytics and Google Tag Manager on how to poll for weather conditions, and send this information to Google Analytics as a custom dimension of the session. The guide was intended as a technical introduction to Google Tag Manager, and I think it succeeded in that.
However, GTM has changed a lot over the last 1.5 years, and I&#39;ve made some improvements to the method along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMtips: Add The &#34;event&#34; Key To dataLayer Pushes</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/add-the-event-key-to-datalayer-pushes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 09:10:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/add-the-event-key-to-datalayer-pushes/</guid>
      <description>In Google Tag Manager, every single Tag requires a Trigger to fire. Every single Trigger requires an Event condition to activate. Sometimes, these Event conditions are obfuscated under template semantics, but you can also create a Custom Event Trigger, where you specify the value of the &amp;lsquo;event&amp;rsquo; key in dataLayer that fires your tag. You can read more about the relationship between GTM events and Tags in these two posts:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Matches CSS Selector&#34; Operator In GTM Triggers</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/matches-css-selector-operator-in-gtm-triggers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 11:21:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/matches-css-selector-operator-in-gtm-triggers/</guid>
      <description>Be honest, can you think of anything that&#39;s more unfair than this:
  A new Google Tag Manager feature, published at 02:07 AM my time, and with an easter egg hunt involved?! Of course it was the infuriating Charles Farina who found the new feature and claimed the prize. Curses! (Just kidding Charles, you&#39;re still awesome.)
  Anyway, there&#39;s a new GTM feature in town, and oh boy, this time it&#39;s a big&#39;un!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leverage useBeacon And beforeunload In Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/leverage-usebeacon-beforeunload-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 08:25:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/leverage-usebeacon-beforeunload-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>This nifty little solution will let you calculate the time spent on pages that are not tracked in Google Analytics by default. These include both bounced landing pages and exit pages. Bounced pages and exit pages lack the necessary subsequent pageview, which Google Analytics uses to calculate time-based metrics.
Before you go on, read this excellent article by Yehoshua Coren:
REAL Time On Page in Google Analytics
Yehoshua gives a very nice use case for the technical solution I&#39;m about to explore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMtips: Track File Downloads In GTM V2</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/track-file-downloads-in-gtm-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 08:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/track-file-downloads-in-gtm-v2/</guid>
      <description>In this #GTMtips post, we&#39;ll go over a simple method for tracking file downloads in Google Tag Manager, specifically the new, V2 interface. Also, &amp;ldquo;tracking file downloads&amp;rdquo; means sending Events to Google Analytics, so this is a GA for GTM guide as well.
Tip 15: Set up file download tracking in GTM   Since we&#39;re using Google Analytics as the tracking platform, we&#39;ll need the following ingredients to make this setup work:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMtips: Track Outbound Links In GTM V2</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/track-outbound-links-in-gtm-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 10:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/track-outbound-links-in-gtm-v2/</guid>
      <description>NOTE 30 Oct 2019: I&#39;ve published a new article on outbound link tracking in Google Tag Manager, which makes the whole process much, MUCH simpler. I strongly recommend you read that article instead.
 Tracking outbound links is important for many. Identifying the exit paths is almost as important as tracking entrances. In this simple #GTMtips post, I&#39;ll show you how to track outbound links with a simple Trigger + Auto-Event Variable combination in the new Google Tag Manager interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RELEASE: GTM Tools V2.0</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/release-gtm-tools-v2-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 17:50:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/release-gtm-tools-v2-0/</guid>
      <description>(UPDATE 3 Apr 2017: There is a newer version of GTM Tools out, so please ignore this article and read this one instead.)
So, the time has come to update my GTM Tools. I released the first toolset in October 2014, and it performed its duties just well enough. Sure, the UI was ugly as hell, and there were bugs along the way, but for cloning containers, macros, and rules, and for visualizing containers, it was just good enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enrich SERP Results Using GTM</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enrich-serp-results-using-gtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 09:21:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/enrich-serp-results-using-gtm/</guid>
      <description>Google has a myriad of ways to make the search engine results page (SERP) livelier. When you input a search query, the engine&#39;s mission is to provide you with the most relevant information with as few clicks as possible. Often, this means that you&#39;ll see the answer to your query directly in the SERP:
  See also Dr. Pete&#39;s excellent description of variation in the SERP (note that this post is from 2013, and not all the data types are relevant today).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMtips: Create A Generic Event Tag</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/create-a-generic-event-tag/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 08:28:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/create-a-generic-event-tag/</guid>
      <description>With Google Tag Manager, there are a million different ways to make your tagging setup leaner and more flexible. The reason this should be a priority is because the UI isn&#39;t perfect. The more tags you have, the more difficult it becomes to manage your assets.
In this #GTMtips post, I show you one of my favorite ways to put your container on a diet.
Tip 13: How to create a Generic Event Tag   I&#39;ve seen a lot of containers that suffer from the same problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variable Guide For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/variable-guide-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 08:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/variable-guide-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>(Updated 21 February 2019)
The current version of Google Tag Manager was released in October 2014. With the release, we saw a brand-spanking new UI, a lot of new functionalities (revamped auto-event tracking, for example), plus a new terminology to cope with. We moved away from the programming-centric concepts of Macros and Rules to the more tactile variables and triggers.
It&#39;s difficult to rank the changes. The new Auto-Event Tracking is perhaps most impactful, but the improvements done to triggers and variables, when compared to the previous version of GTM, require attention as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track Content With Enhanced Ecommerce</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-content-enhanced-ecommerce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 12:18:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/track-content-enhanced-ecommerce/</guid>
      <description>My fingers have been tingling to write this article. Ever since I implemented Enhanced Ecommerce on my blog a couple of weeks ago, I&#39;ve been getting such an impressive amount of useful data that it&#39;s mind-boggling.
In this article, I&#39;ll walk you through the steps I went to implement the solution, along with examples of the data I can now access through Google Analytics&amp;rsquo; reporting interface. As you might have guessed, if you&#39;ve read my articles before, I implemented Enhanced Ecommerce with Google Tag Manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trigger Guide For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/trigger-guide-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 20:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/trigger-guide-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>Updated 27 March 2019
 In the new version of Google Tag Manager, one of the most visible and profound changes to the previous version is how tags are fired (and blocked). First of all, there&#39;s the obvious terminological distinction: we talk about triggers now, not rules. Second, triggers have become an integral part of the tag creation workflow, and as such have far more significance in the user interface than before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check If Google Analytics Is In The Page Template</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/check-if-google-analytics-is-in-page-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 08:33:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/check-if-google-analytics-is-in-page-template/</guid>
      <description>One of the recurring problems in migrating to Google Tag Manager is how to make the transition as smooth as possible. Usually it requires that we agree with the developers on a time when the old code is removed, and at that moment we need to make sure the GTM tags point to the right UA code. This is, of course, only one use case for migrations, as some people do the entire migration in a staging environment, and some just don&#39;t care if they lose a little bit of data along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple RegEx Table For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/simple-regex-lookup-table-for-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2014 11:57:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/simple-regex-lookup-table-for-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>When our good friends in the Google Tag Manager developer team first introduced the Lookup Table Macro, we were excited. For many of us, it soon became the weapon of choice especially when used as a management and optimization tool for the container itself.
  However, the macro wasn&#39;t considered perfect. In fact, the most frequently heard request had to do with the core functionality of the feature itself: the macro should support operations, that is, predicate logic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMtips: Fix Problems With GTM Listeners</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/fix-problems-with-gtm-listeners/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 17:06:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/fix-problems-with-gtm-listeners/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve written about this before here and here, but this issue remains probably the biggest problem users have when implementing Google Tag Manager.
Tip 10: Resolve conflicts with GTM&#39;s listeners   The tip title is actually wrong. You&#39;re not fixing Google Tag Manager listeners. Rather, you&#39;re resolving conflicts that other scripts on your page might introduce.
GTM&#39;s event listening is based on something called event delegation. Event delegation makes use of the document object model (DOM) and its tree-like hierarchy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Analytics And The Page Load</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-analytics-page-load/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 16:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-analytics-page-load/</guid>
      <description>If you use Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager, or any JavaScript-based data collection or analytics platform, have you ever stopped to wonder how they actually work? I mean, you obviously care about getting the data in, but are you taking the machinations of these tools for granted?
This is something I&#39;ve been thinking about for a long while, because I&#39;m not so sure that many who work with these platforms actually understand how the browser and the web page interact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto-Event Tracking In GTM 2.0</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/auto-event-tracking-gtm-2-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 15:04:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/auto-event-tracking-gtm-2-0/</guid>
      <description>In the new version of Google Tag Manager, auto-event tracking has received a considerable usability upgrade. It might seem quirky at first, especially if you&#39;re used to the old auto-event tracking method, but the logic behind the new setup is brilliant.
  The most important distinction is that auto-event tracking isn&#39;t something you control with separate tags anymore. Rather, it&#39;s now entirely trigger-driven, meaning you activate and specify the auto-event tracking of your choice using tag triggers (triggers are what ye olde folk used to call rules).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eCommerce Tips For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/ecommerce-tips-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 07:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/ecommerce-tips-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve noticed that setting up eCommerce in Google Tag Manager (and now the new Enhanced ecommerce) is very difficult for many. I&#39;m sure part of the problem is that eCommerce is for many users the moment that GTM forces you to take steps in to the developer&#39;s domain, since it&#39;s obvious that you&#39;ll need to add some code to the web page.
This isn&#39;t a tutorial on how to do eCommerce in Google Tag Manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMtips: hitCallback And eventCallback</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/hitcallback-eventcallback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 07:03:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/hitcallback-eventcallback/</guid>
      <description>This time we&#39;ll take a look at two different, JavaScript-y features of Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager. Callback as a concept should be familiar to anyone who&#39;s ever used a programming language. It&#39;s basically a piece of code that is passed as an argument to some function, so that when this second function has completed, the callback is executed.
For web analytics, callbacks are hugely important, since they allow you to impose a firing order for your asynchronous tags.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Tag Manager&#39;s Data Model</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-data-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 10:40:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-data-model/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s time for MeasureCamp again! As before, I want to write an accompanying post for my session, since there&#39;s always so much more to say than the time slot allows for. So, the topic of this article is the data model used by Google Tag Manager to process digital data in your data layer.
This post also picks up where I left in my previous foray into the data layer. However, where the first article aimed to be generic (since the data layer should be generic), this post will look at how GTM uses the information in the generic data layer, and how it processes this information to work with the proprietary features of the tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Page Visibility API With GTM</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/use-page-visibility-api-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 08:52:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/use-page-visibility-api-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>The Page Visibility API for web browsers is pretty sweet. It lets you poll, using some new properties of the document object, whether or not the current page is visible to the user. Visibility is hidden if the page is not open in the current browser tab instance, or if the browser window has been minimized.
  In this post, I&#39;ll give an example of how features of the Page Visibility API could be used with Google Tag Manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMtips: Rules In A Nutshell</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/gtmtips-rules-nutshell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 08:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/gtmtips-rules-nutshell/</guid>
      <description>Rules are the cornerstone of Google Tag Manager. As with any critical element in a system, they are easy to get wrong. This tip is just a refresher on how GTM firing and blocking rules work.
Tip 3: Google Tag Manager rules in a nutshell   So, let&#39;s go through these points one-by-one.
Every tag requires a firing rule to work - this is a given. Without a firing rule, your tag will not be written in the document object, and it will never be executed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMtips: Check {{referrer}} For Previous Page URL</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/check-referrer-for-previous-page-url/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 06:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/check-referrer-for-previous-page-url/</guid>
      <description>Here&#39;s a simple way to check what was the source of the visitor&#39;s arrival to the current page. It&#39;s done by utilizing the {{referrer}} macro, which comes out-of-the-box in any GTM setup.
Tip 2: Use {{referrer}} to see where the visitor came from   You might want to also explore the Component Types and create new macros for {{referrer path}} and {{referrer host name}} for example:
  By default, you see, the {{referrer}} macro returns the entire URL of the previous page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMtips: Save GATC In A Constant String Macro</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/save-gatc-constant-string-macro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 11:59:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/gtm-tips/save-gatc-constant-string-macro/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to try something new (and, naturally, I&#39;m running out of content ideas), so let me introduce the hashtag #gtmtips. I hope others contribute as well, but I will be adding a new tip as often as possible. I&#39;ve got maybe 20 tips in store right now, and I&#39;m writing new ones all the time. So without further ado, here&#39;s&amp;hellip;
Tip 1: Save GATC In A Constant String Macro   This is an easy one, and everyone should already be doing this in one way or another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persist dataLayer In Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/persist-datalayer-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 06:57:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/persist-datalayer-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>(Update 19 November 2018: See this article for a more elegant solution.)
If you know your JavaScript, you know that all variables, functions, objects, resources, and data in the document get rewritten with every page load. In other words, every single page refresh builds the page from scratch, and the state of the document before the page refresh is left drifting in the ocean of oblivion.
Google Tag Manager&amp;lsquo;s dataLayer is also one such entity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node Relationships And GTM</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/node-relationships-gtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 13:25:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/node-relationships-gtm/</guid>
      <description>There&#39;s a much easier, native-to-GTM way to do this now: the Matches CSS Selector.
Behind this tragically boring title is a simple solution to many problems with Google Tag Manager&#39;s auto-event tracking. The common denominator to these problems is poor website markup. Selectors are used sparingly, and element hierarchy is messy. This disregard for proper node relationships means you have to resort to Data Layer Variable Macros which look like</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Event Listeners For GTM</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/custom-event-listeners-gtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 17:36:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/custom-event-listeners-gtm/</guid>
      <description>(UPDATE 1 Oct 2014 Due to a change in how macros work in Debug Mode, the {{generic event handler}} macro no longer works when testing in Debug Mode. That means that you&#39;ll have to test your custom listener in a live container (I know, ouch!). If you want to test in Debug Mode, you&#39;ll have to skip using the {{generic event handler}} as a macro, and instead copy the inner function into the Custom HTML Tag, give the function a name, and use that as the callback in addEventListener or attachEvent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript 101 For GTM: Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/javascript-101-gtm-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 06:50:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/javascript-101-gtm-part-2/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s been an awesome summer, with temperatures soaring in the global warming range throughout our northern country. The heat has given me ample reason to not be near a computer, but now it&#39;s time to mine some JavaScript wisdom again. Here&#39;s the second part of my JavaScript for Google Tag Manager series. The first part focused on GTM specific tips and tricks, and I hope that while reading it, you were treated to another grand example of the flexibility of this wonderful tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix GA Site Search With Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/fix-ga-site-search-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 06:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/fix-ga-site-search-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>Analyzing what people write in your site search field is pretty much one of the smartest things you can do for your website tracking. If certain terms pop up over and over again in internal search reports, it means that your site is not providing the answers people are looking for, meaning you have an excellent opportunity to provide supply for the demand!
  However, not all site search applications are trackable out-of-the-box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript 101 For GTM: Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/javascript-101-gtm-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2014 13:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/javascript-101-gtm-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Here&#39;s the link to part 2 of this JavaScript guide.
The thing about Google Tag Manager, or any JavaScript tag manager for that matter, is that there&#39;s JavaScript involved. In fact, the tool itself is just a JavaScript library with some additional bells and whistles (such as a management UI). This means that to make the best of it, some knowledge of JavaScript is warranted, and that&#39;s the point of this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun With Google Tag Manager: Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/fun-google-tag-manager-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 06:52:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/fun-google-tag-manager-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Apologies for leaving you hanging. It&#39;s now almost three weeks since I published the first part of this post, and I&#39;m sure you&#39;ve been holding your breath ever since.
There&#39;s been a lot going on since the last post. First, my favorite sports team in the world, San Antonio Spurs, won their fifth NBA championship from the defending champs, Miami Heat. Next, my wife and I moved to our new house, and we&#39;ve been remodeling ever since.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun With Google Tag Manager: Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/fun-with-google-tag-manager-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 13:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/fun-with-google-tag-manager-part-1/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s time to dig into my tip library for some pretty cool things you can do with Google Tag Manager to enhance your site tagging. Some of these are macro magic through and through, some of these are best practices, and some of these are things that will make your life easier while managing a tag management solution.
  I&#39;ve split this post into two parts to make it more Hobbit and less Lord Of the Rings length-wise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Split Test With Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/simple-split-test-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 11:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/simple-split-test-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>Over the last couple of posts I&#39;ve mainly been doing proof-of-concept (POC) tests with Google Tag Manager. The great thing about a POC is that you don&#39;t really need to have any viable results or insight-driving technological innovations. The point is to showcase some feature of the platform on which the experiment was conducted.
In this post, I&#39;ll take a care-free step into the world of POCs again. My goal is to do a simple split test in order to identify which variant of a landing page (or key element thereof) produces the most conversions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Send Mail Upon Google Tag Manager Event</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/send-mail-upon-google-tag-manager-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 04:49:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/send-mail-upon-google-tag-manager-event/</guid>
      <description>Let&#39;s say you want to set up a rudimentary email alert system in your Google Tag Manager implementation. Say, for example, you want to receive an email every time an uncaught error occurs on your website. It&#39;s not a very good use case, since a large website can spawn hundreds of uncaught exceptions in a short period of time, but let&#39;s just pretend for now.
If you know your JavaScript, you&#39;ll know that you can&#39;t send mail using client-side code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Tag Manager: DOM Listener</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-dom-listener/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 05:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-dom-listener/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&#39;ll walk you through a tutorial on how to create a Google Tag Manager extension. This extension will be a new listener, whose sole job is to listen for changes in the HTML and CSS markup on the page.
The reason I&#39;m teaching you how to create a DOM listener is simple. Ever so often I come across people asking for help, but they are unable to touch on-page code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Form Tracking In Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/form-tracking-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 07:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/form-tracking-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>There is a new, updated version of this article for the new version of Google Tag Manager. I strongly suggest you read that as well!
I really enjoy the ad hoc Q&amp;amp;A sessions my blog posts have inspired. I haven&#39;t said this enough, but I am really, REALLY grateful to people who take their time to comment on my posts, even if it&#39;s just say a quick &amp;ldquo;Hi!&amp;quot;. The main reason I enjoy getting blog comments is because they often turn into blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Tag Manager: Playing By The Rules</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-playing-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 19:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/google-tag-manager-playing-rules/</guid>
      <description>There is a new version of this guide for GTM V2 here.
(Last updated April 2014) I see Google Tag Manager&#39;s operational model as an analogy of Montesquieu&#39;s three-branched government theory (don&#39;t leave just yet, I&#39;m getting somewhere with this). We have the legislative power of tags (what should be done), the judiciary power of macros (explore the context and circumstance of each tag), and the executive power of rules (make the tag happen).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Awesome Google Tag Manager Resources</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/awesome-google-tag-manager-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 15:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/awesome-google-tag-manager-resources/</guid>
      <description>When push comes to shove, I&#39;m a pretty lazy guy. I enjoy nothing more than just to stretch my legs on a couch, pick up my iPad, and read what&#39;s going on in the world. I skip the news, since they&#39;re just full of depressing stories. Instead, I head over to my favorite Google+ communities to see what&#39;s new in the blogosphere.
  This approach has led me to some pretty amazing individuals, whom I follow like a suckerfish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macro Guide For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/macro-guide-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 16:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/macro-guide-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve written a new Variable Guide for Google Tag Manager, which covers the new GTM UI. This guide is for the old UI.
You might be vaguely familiar with macros if you&#39;ve ever used a computer. Basically, whenever you perform a complicated task with a simple gesture, or reuse complex code with a simple input mechanism, you&#39;re using macros. Think keyboard shortcuts.
In Google Tag Manager, this is the essence of macros.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot Google Analytics: 9-Step Program</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/troubleshoot-google-analytics-9-step-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 16:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/analytics/troubleshoot-google-analytics-9-step-program/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve had such a blast in the Google+ Google Analytics community. Not only are the people super-duper-nice, but I have the wonderful opportunity of helping people with their Google Analytics problems without feeling obligated to invoice them or ask for compensation for my troubles. I do it because I love to help, because I feel like I have a lot to share with the community, and because I&#39;ve always believed that the more knowledge you share the more you accumulate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Not About Marketing</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/digital-marketing/its-not-about-marketing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 17:46:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/digital-marketing/its-not-about-marketing/</guid>
      <description>In a recent post, I took a short foray into the world of clumsy analogies by comparing the team work qualities (and necessities) of basketball and digital marketing. In an even earlier post, I made the claim that the single most important facet of content strategy is audience design. Well, now is the time to pull these two threads together all trilogy-like. After this, you can hail me as the Stieg Larsson of marketing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>