<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Debug on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/debug/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Debug on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 13:27:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/debug/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Log Failed Google Analytics Requests In Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/log-failed-google-analytics-requests-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 13:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/log-failed-google-analytics-requests-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE 20 December 2016: I made some fixes to the solution - be sure to grab the latest code snippet from below!
Having worked in all sorts of Google Analytics projects over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself more and more interested in the technical underpinnings of digital analytics rather than the actual analytical work. We all play to our respective strengths, I guess. For example, there are still many purely technical / technological mysteries surrounding Google Analytics, because much of the data processing is done server-side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Debug Change History In GTM</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/debug-change-history-gtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 07:44:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/debug-change-history-gtm/</guid>
      <description>Google Tag Manager can be quite the hierarchical mess. You have accounts which comprise containers. Containers are split into container versions, and you use workspaces to create new versions. Phew! Trying to keep tabs on all the activity within these layers can be quite the chore.
In this #GTMTips article, I&amp;rsquo;ll do a quick walkthrough of (almost) all the places where you can review changes made in your Google Tag Manager account and container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Analytics Endpoint Debugger</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-analytics-endpoint-debugger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 09:59:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-analytics-endpoint-debugger/</guid>
      <description>This is a really cool feature for Google Analytics data collection, of which I&amp;rsquo;ve heard very, very little buzz. It&amp;rsquo;s a way to debug any and all hits sent to the Google Analytics endpoint at https://www.google-analytics.com/collect.
  In all simplicity, you just need to copy the entire URL of the HTTP request to your clipboard, paste it into a web browser, and add /debug between the hostname and /collect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMtips: Debugging Tag Execution Properly</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/debugging-tag-execution-properly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 13:32:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/debugging-tag-execution-properly/</guid>
      <description>One of the unfortunate misunderstandings regarding the wonderful Google Tag Manager Preview mode is what it actually means when GTM reports &amp;ldquo;Tags Fired On This Event&amp;rdquo;. For many, this seems to indicate that whatever code the Tag was meant to execute also completed successfully. However, this is not the case.
Tip 19: Debugging Tag execution vs. actual requests   Let&amp;rsquo;s get the distinction straight right away:
Google Tag Manager debug panel tells you when a Trigger has been invoked by certain conditions, and the Tag which uses this Trigger has its JavaScript injected into the Document Object Model.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>