<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>debug on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/debug/</link>
    <description>Recent content in debug on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 09:20:24 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/debug/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Still Running&#39; Google Tag Manager Tags – What To Do?</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/still-running-google-tag-manager-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 09:20:24 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/still-running-google-tag-manager-tags/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, in Google Tag Manager&#39;s Debug mode, you&#39;ll see tags appear with the status Still Running, and you&#39;ll (eventually) notice that these tags are not doing what they are supposed to be doing.
  When you see this message on a tag, it technically means this:
The tag failed to signal Google Tag Manager that it is &amp;ldquo;done&amp;rdquo;.
The technical explanation is, naturally, too simple to be useful. In this article, I&#39;ll explore what &amp;ldquo;done&amp;rdquo; means, and how especially Google Analytics tags manifest this behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Log Failed Google Analytics Requests In Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/log-failed-google-analytics-requests-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 13:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/log-failed-google-analytics-requests-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>READ THIS (26 Aug 2019)!! Unfortunately, the update I made in 2016 contained code that was incomplete and broken. I nevert noticed this until it was pointed out to me almost three years later. At this point, I don&#39;t have a working backup of the solution, so unless some internet archive / cache service manages to surface the code, this article is basically lost.
 UPDATE 20 December 2016: I made some fixes to the solution - be sure to grab the latest code snippet from below!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMTips: Debug Change History In GTM</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/debug-change-history-gtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 07:44:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/debug-change-history-gtm/</guid>
      <description>Google Tag Manager can be quite the hierarchical mess. You have accounts which comprise containers. Containers are split into container versions, and you use workspaces to create new versions. Phew! Trying to keep tabs on all the activity within these layers can be quite the chore.
In this #GTMTips article, I&#39;ll do a quick walkthrough of (almost) all the places where you can review changes made in your Google Tag Manager account and container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Analytics Endpoint Debugger</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-analytics-endpoint-debugger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 09:59:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/google-analytics-endpoint-debugger/</guid>
      <description>This is a really cool feature for Google Analytics data collection, of which I&#39;ve heard very, very little buzz. It&#39;s a way to debug any and all hits sent to the Google Analytics endpoint at https://www.google-analytics.com/collect.
  In all simplicity, you just need to copy the entire URL of the HTTP request to your clipboard, paste it into a web browser, and add /debug between the hostname and /collect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GTMtips: Debugging Tag Execution Properly</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/debugging-tag-execution-properly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 13:32:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/gtm-tips/debugging-tag-execution-properly/</guid>
      <description>One of the unfortunate misunderstandings regarding the wonderful Google Tag Manager Preview mode is what it actually means when GTM reports &amp;ldquo;Tags Fired On This Event&amp;rdquo;. For many, this seems to indicate that whatever code the Tag was meant to execute also completed successfully. However, this is not the case.
Tip 19: Debugging Tag execution vs. actual requests   Let&#39;s get the distinction straight right away:
Google Tag Manager debug panel tells you when a Trigger has been invoked by certain conditions, and the Tag which uses this Trigger has its JavaScript injected into the Document Object Model.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>