<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>variable templates on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/variable-templates/</link>
    <description>Recent content in variable templates on Simo Ahava&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 14:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/variable-templates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Tests For Custom Templates In Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/writing-tests-for-custom-templates-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/writing-tests-for-custom-templates-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>Google Tag Manager introduced the capability to add tests to your Custom Templates. Tests, in this context, refer specifically to unit tests that you write in order to make sure your template code works in a predictable way. Unit tests are also used to drive development, ensuring that you have added contingencies for all the different scenarios that the template, when coupled with user input, might introduce.
  In this guide, I&amp;rsquo;ll introduce how the Tests feature works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Ecommerce Object Builder Template For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-builder-custom-variable-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 11:48:29 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/enhanced-ecommerce-builder-custom-variable-template/</guid>
      <description>One of the cool things about Enhanced Ecommerce deployments in Google Tag Manager is that you can use a Custom JavaScript variable to generate the necessary data.
There are many reasons to do so, with the biggest one being the flexibility it offers for manipulating the dataLayer object in case quick changes are required on the site, and it would take too long to wait for a new release of the site JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Templates Guide For Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/custom-templates-guide-for-google-tag-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 18:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/custom-templates-guide-for-google-tag-manager/</guid>
      <description>As I have finally managed to pick up my jaw from the floor, it&amp;rsquo;s now time to tell you what&amp;rsquo;s got me so excited. Google Tag Manager recently released a new feature called Custom Templates. Actually, it&amp;rsquo;s not fair to call it a feature. It&amp;rsquo;s a full-blown paradigm shift in how we use Google Tag Manager. It&amp;rsquo;s a suite of features designed to help brands, companies, and users create and share their own custom JavaScript and HTML setups with ease, while taking care that the code is optimized for delivery in the web browser.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>