<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Timings on Simo Ahava's blog</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/timings/</link><description>Recent content in Timings on Simo Ahava's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 12:28:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/tags/timings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Measure SERP Bounce Time With GTM</title><link>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/measure-serp-bounce-time-with-gtm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 12:28:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.simoahava.com/amp/analytics/measure-serp-bounce-time-with-gtm/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s an interesting and hacky use case for you. It&amp;rsquo;s all about uncovering &lt;strong>bounce&lt;/strong> metrics for visits which originate from organic Google search results. In particular, the metric we&amp;rsquo;re interested in is how long user &lt;em>dwelled&lt;/em> on the landing page after arriving from organic Google search &lt;strong>AND&lt;/strong> returned to the search engine results page (SERP) using the browser&amp;rsquo;s back button.&lt;/p>


 &lt;a href="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/images/2015/09/dwell-time-landing-page.jpg" title="Dwell time landing page">
 
 &lt;amp-img src="https://www.simoahava.com/amp/images/2015/09/dwell-time-landing-page.jpg" layout="responsive" alt="Dwell time landing page" height="726" width="1614">&lt;/amp-img>
 
 &lt;/a>
 

&lt;p>The inspiration for this post came from an audience question at the Best Internet Conference in Lithuania, which I recently attended as a speaker. They were concerned that Google is using Bounce Rate as a search ranking signal, and I was fairly strongly opinionated that it&amp;rsquo;s simply not possible, as all the &amp;ldquo;native&amp;rdquo; GA metrics are really easy to manipulate. However, Dr. Pete from Moz wrote about &lt;a href="https://moz.com/blog/the-2-user-metrics-that-matter-for-seo">&lt;em>dwell time&lt;/em>&lt;/a> in 2012, and it makes a lot of sense. Google should be &lt;strong>very&lt;/strong> interested how long the visitor stays out of the SERP when following a link. If users tend to immediately return to the SERP, it&amp;rsquo;s very likely the result was not relevant for them.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>